[Thunder Rumbling]
[Rain Pattering]
[Birds Chirping]
[Woman]
Our world was much larger then.
The forest went on forever.
We tree spirits nurtured the harmony
of all living things,
but our closest friends were humans.
Then, as sometimes happens,
the balance of nature shifted,
[1812 Reset / MudFlood]
and Hexxus...
the very spirit of destruction...
rose up from the bowels
of the earth...
and rained down his poison.
The forest was nearly destroyed.
Many lives were lost,
and the humans fled in fear,
never to return.
Most think they didn't survive.
It was only by calling up
the magical powers of nature...
that I was able to trap Hexxus
inside an enchanted tree...
and save FernGully.
Which is why it is so important
for you to learn to use these powers.
I won't be around forever,
and you'll have to...
Crysta?
Yes.
That is why it is so important
for you to learn the secrets of...
♪[Rhythmic]
- Crysta!
- Magi, yes. The secrets.
I know. But, I mean,
it's all right now.
That was so long ago, and you trapped
him in that tree and everything, so...
I really have to go now,
but I'll see you later, okay? Bye!
♪[Continues]
- Hey!
- Pips.
You know, you're spending more time
with Magi than you do with me.
Well, what can I learn from you?
- Hey!
- ♪ When the sleepy planet comes alive ♪
♪And I wake up
in the warm sunlight ♪
♪ There's a simple harmony
to life ♪
♪A magic thing ♪
♪ Then I walk among
the flowers and trees ♪
Hi, Ock. Hi, Rock.
[Giggles]
- [Both Squawking]
- ♪And I feel the earth beneath my feet ♪
♪And I remember that
the air we breathe ♪
♪Is a magic thing ♪
♪Everybody, now
Life is a magic thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
[Slurping, Grunting]
- ♪Life is a magic thing ♪
- [Protesting, Yelling]
- Comin' through! Watch out! Here I come!
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪Life is a magic thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
There she goes.
Come on. Don't lose her.
Whoa!
- Okay.
- Crysta, stop!
[All] Whoa!
Never, never go above the canopy.
Never go above the canopy.
Crysta!
[Gasps]
- [Screeching]
- [Screaming]
- I got ya.
- [Gasping, Panting]
Are you crazy, going above the canopy?
Yeah, we was almost falcon fodder.
- I've got to tell Magi.
- Tell Magi what?
Hey, wait!
Wh-What'd you see...
up there?
- Halt! Who goes there?
- Hi, Crysta!
- Okay, what's the password?
- Oh, come on, you guys.
- Is that the password?
- It sounds good.
- Bye.
- "Bye." That's it! That's the password!
Well, I don't know if that's the
password or not. I'm so confused, you...
Magi? Magi.
Oh, Magi, I just saw the most
incredible thing above the canopy.
A whole other world.
The sky went on forever.
And way over in the distance
as far as I could see,
there was this enormous rock like a...
Mountain.
That was Mount Warning.
And next to it was a... a...
I don't know.
It looked like a strange black cloud
rising out of the earth.
- Smoke, I should think.
- What's smoke?
Oh, there are many things in our world
you don't yet know about, Crysta.
There are worlds
within worlds, Crysta.
Everything in our world is connected by
the delicate strands of the web of life,
which is balanced
between forces of destruction...
and the magic forces of creation.
Help it grow.
Why can't I do it?
Everyone can call on
the magic powers of the web of life.
You have to find it in yourself.
I want to, Magi.
You know I do.
But I was thinking about that smoke.
Do you think
it could be... Hexxus?
No, there isn't a force in
nature that could release him,
and there are no poisons here
on which he can feed.
Hexxus is trapped for all time.
Now that's enough for today.
- But what could have caused the smoke?
- Now, now, now, off with you.
But, Magi...
Hexxus.
[Chittering, Squawking]
♪[Pan Pipes]
So what did the Mag have to say, huh?
- She said I should get serious.
- 'Bout time.
Oh, and stop hanging around
with bug-brained layabouts like you.
Oh, no! Oh!
Red light.
Red light again.
Immediate clearance requested!
Immediate clearance!
- Oh, no!
- Where you goin'? Crysta!
Hello?
[Muffled Yelling]
[Continues Yelling]
Bless your heart with magic light.
I give the gift of fairy sight.
[Sighs] Oh, what a strange little bug.
I did it! I did it!
Oh! Gravity works.
[Thump]
Oh. Poor guy.
Oh!
Primary testing laboratory.
No! Pass the probe.
Graduate students,
all gather forward. No!
- Love the haircut.
- [Screams]
It's all right.
We won't hurt you.
- He's still a little confused.
- Clearly.
Hello, I'm a nocturnal
placental flying mammal,
a member of the family of pteropodidae,
or Ptero-didn't I. [Laughing]
If you can't tell, I'm a bat!
Yes, I am. And they used to
call me "Batty," Batty Koda.
- Pleased to meet you. Bonjour.
- [Giggles]
And where are you from?
I just blew in from a biology lab.
I'm back, and I'm flappin' free.
Let me tell you a story,
and it's all about...
♪[Techno Horror]
♪ Yo, the name is Batty
The logic is erratic ♪
♪ Potato in a jacket
Toys in the attic ♪
♪ I rock and I ramble
My brain is scrambled ♪
♪ Wrapped like an animal
But I'm a mammal ♪
All of our cosmetics
are non carcinogenic.
♪ I've been brain-fried, electrified
infected and injectified ♪
♪ Vivisectified
and fed pesticide ♪
♪ My face is all cut up 'cause
my radar's all shut up ♪
♪ Nurse, I need a checkup
from the neck up I'm Batty ♪
Seems to have no effect, Doctor. Get me
another one. Get me another animal!
♪ They used and abused me
Battered and bruised me ♪
♪ Red wires, green wires
Stuck 'em right through me ♪
♪ So hear my batty word and
exercise a little prudence ♪
♪ When dealing with... humans ♪
- Humans?
- [Screaming] Where?
N-N-N-No!
[Imitating Ricky] Lucy!
No, no, there are no humans.
- They're long gone.
- Vanished.
Definitely extinct.
- They only exist in stories.
- [Sniffing]
[Slurps, Belches] Excuse me.
- Oh, charming.
- It's been lovely, but I gotta "hoon".
Adios, amigos!
Ding! Check, please.
[Grunting, Groaning] Whoa!
Oh, Father,
do you think it's possible?
Could humans still exist?
Now, Crysta. Ooh!
Don't you think you're a little old
to believe in human tales?
Human tails?
Humans don't have tails.
They have big, big bottoms
that they wear with bad shorts.
They walk around going,
"Hi, Helen!"
[Sniffs, Slurps]
Did you really see humans?
- Were they at Mount Warning?
- Oh, masses of Homo sapiens. [Chuckling]
Hey!
Where are you going?
Yeah, this territory
looks kinda familiar.
Fabulous day in the canopy, isn't it?
- Where do you think you're goin'?
- Mount Warning.
[Groggy] I know where I am.
I know where I am.
Hey! You scared me there. For a minute I thought
you said you were going to Mount Warning.
Well, I did.
- But there are humans on Mount Warning!
- Exactly.
Fractured fig, fairy bug!
Come on!
Mount Warning is the last place in the
world a little bug like you wants to go.
Look at these!
You think nature did this?
Do you think I put this in
to get better reception?
No! Humans did this.
We should stay here.
It's nice here.
Come on! You got a great set of wings.
Let's just flutter for a while.
- [Whimpering]
- Batty?
Batty.
Well, come on!
- My heart! Oh, my heart!
- [Gasps]
I can't go on. Help me!
My little wings can't make it.
Maybe you should wait here for me.
This is a fabulous idea.
I really think we should fly with that.
Only, why don't you stay here with me?
It's okay, really.
I'll be right back.
Why do I not believe you?
[Giggles]
[Moaning]
[Gasps]
Take anything you want.
I won't tell the cops. Huh?
- Are you all right?
- [Yells] I'm fine.
- What is going on here?
- The monster... it tried to eat you.
- Monster?
- My friend and I saved you.
Oh, Batty. Batty?
Huh?
Oh, sonic interference.
What a nightmare.
I thought I saw a human.
[Yells] Human!
[Gasps] That's a human?
Yes! Kill it! Restrain it!
Medicate it! Something!
[Inhaling]
Puff up. They hate that.
- [Yelling]
- [Screaming]
Back! Back!
Get back!
- Don't worry! I've got it scared.
- No! Stop!
- I have but one claw, but beware.
- Will you both just calm down?
[In Unison] He tried to kill you!
I did not! You did!
Hold on! The only thing
that tried to kill anybody...
was that horrible monster
in the forest.
"Monster"? What monster?
The one that ate the tree.
It was terrible.
Tree?
The leveler.
- Hey, am-am I dead?
- No.
We could fix that for ya.
- Then I must be dreaming.
- Nope.
Aw, sure. And what are you
supposed to be... some kind of fairy?
Of course I am. What about you?
Are you really a human?
Last time I checked.
Listen, fairy, it's been weird,
but I'm outta here,
this dream is history.
[Yelling]
[Sighs, Grunts]
[Continues Yelling]
[Yelling Becomes Laughing]
[Whooping]
[Laughing, Whooping Continue]
[Yelling]
[Laughs]
- Check this out.
- [Yells]
♪ I've a basic inclination ♪
- [Whimpering] No. No.
- ♪ A very primal need ♪
[Yelling]
♪ To inspect the vegetation ♪
♪ For an egg or centipede ♪
♪ I just can't control
this hunger ♪
♪I just can't seem
to cut it back ♪
♪ On my ravenous consumption ♪
[Grunts]
♪ You're a welcome little snack ♪
♪ If I'm gonna eat somebody ♪
- ♪ It might as well be you ♪
- Uh-oh.
♪ Can you dig it ♪
♪ I can see you as a sandwich ♪
♪ Or a strange exotic stew ♪
[Chorus]
♪Floating down the river ♪
- ♪ Like an oyster in a stew ♪
- ♪ Get funky one time ♪
♪ He's gonna eat somebody ♪
- ♪It might as well be you ♪
- [Yelling]
♪ You know it
Kick it one time ♪
- [Yelling]
- ♪ Mmm ♪
♪ Welcome to the food chain ♪
No! You can't eat him.
He's a human.
- Uh, what's a human?
- [Yelling]
Delicious and nutritious.
Tastes just like chicken.
Wait!
- He's my friend.
- [Sighs]
Well, any friend of a fairy...
- [Yelling]
- Is a friend of mine.
Thanks a lot.
Oh, man. You owe me
a free dinner after this one.
- Are you okay?
- [Screams] What happened to me?
- I-I-I'm three inches tall!
- Oh.
- I shrank you.
- You what?
Well, it was the most amazing thing.
Of course, it's not what the spell
is really supposed to do.
But Magi Lune will fix you.
You shrank me?
- Yeah.
- Catches on quick, doesn't he?
- We better buzz off. It's getting late.
- "Buzz off'?
I'm not buzzing anywhere.
Now, unshrink me, and I mean now!
- Well, I guess I could take a bash at it.
- "Take a bash"?
Actually, I'm just sort of learning.
Great! I've been shrunk
by an amateur.
I don't believe this.
Okay, come on. Bash away.
Okay!
What was done, now undo.
Return you to the form that's true.
[Grunts, Moans]
Oh, oh, oh, big ears.
Elephant! No, no, no.
Anteater! Orangutan!
Okay, okay, let me guess. A duck!
A duck! Oh, it's Darwin's grab bag!
- [Zak Panting]
- Uh, let me try again.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
- No, no, no!
Thank you, but I think maybe
we better go see this Magi.
I'm Zak.
- I'm Crysta.
- Nice to meet you.
You're going to love FernGully.
It's the most beautiful,
wonderful place in the forest.
Well, come on.
Batty can carry you.
Moi? Uh-uh.
Not this little mammal.
Fly a human?
I'd rather suck wax fruit.
Crysta!
- Crysta!
- Whoa! Hey!
Any sign of her?
Let's go back.
She's probably back home havin' dinner.
Yeah, or she's somebody else's dinner.
[Laughing]
She's fine.
Now, keep looking.
- We're lookin', we're lookin'.
- Okay, yeah, we're lookin'.
- We're lookin'. What are we lookin' for?
- Look at us look. We're lookin'.
Oh, look!
Oh, is that what we're lookin' for?
This is so incredible!
[Crysta]
What are the trees like where you live?
Not like this.
I live in a city.
"City"?
Yeah... buildings,
traffic, roads,
lights... a city.
Most humans live in cities.
- There's not many trees there.
- But how can you live without trees?
- Easy.
- But trees give life.
They make the clouds,
the rain, the air.
We've got air.
Yeah, if you don't mind getting
all your minerals in one breath.
[Coughing]
Don't you miss talking to the forest?
Can't say I've actually
talked with a forest before.
I do all the time.
[Chuckles] What does it say?
Well, listen.
♪It's raining like magic ♪
♪It's falling like starlight ♪
♪It's raining life ♪
♪ The forest is breathing ♪
♪And ferns are rejoicing ♪
♪ The trees are all singing ♪
♪Hey, it's raining life ♪
[Chorus]
♪Raining like magic ♪
♪La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la
It's raining life ♪
So what about you, Crysta?
I mean, what do fairies do anyway?
- "Do"?
- Yeah, I mean, do you have jobs or anything?
What-What's a job?
Guess that answers that question.
Look, um, what do you do all day?
- Mm, help things grow.
- Yeah? That sounds cool.
No, usually it's warm.
- No, no. Cool means hot.
- What?
Yeah. You know...
bodacious, bad, tubular.
Awesome use of the language, dude.
As in,
"You are
one bodacious babe."
And that's good.
I mean cool.
- [Zak] Yeah. We're communicating now.
- [Snoring]
[Crysta] Tubular.
[Chopping]
[Chopping Continues]
Morning!
- [Gasps]
- What are you doing?
Carving your name.
See? C-R-Y-S...
No, no, you mustn't do that.
Here.
- Can't you feel its pain?
- "Its pain"?
[Crysta]
Yes.
Humans can't feel anything...
they're numb from the brain down.
Oh, Zak.
He doesn't understand.
[Sighs]
Did I say something wrong?
So, uh, which way to FernGully?
- [Grunting]
- Oh!
[Laughing]
[Zak Laughing]
Isn't this great?
Wow!
- What is this place?
- This is FernGully.
[Yelling]
- Hey, Crysta, what's this?
- [Yells]
Careful, Stump.
He's a human.
- Hey!
- Hey, how does it taste?
- A "hoo-man"?
- Is this what we're lookin' for?
- Let go of me!
- [Yells, Indistinct]
- Crysta!
- Hey, that's my human!
Hey!
Oh, no!
I'm blind! Oh, no!
I can see!
It's a miracle!
Another perfect landing.
No worries. I'm okay.
- Thank you for caring. It's just a few bruises.
- [Chattering]
- Nobody cares about me.
- I do, bat man.
- You sure?
- I'm positive.
- Only fools are positive.
- Are you sure?
- I'm positive. I fell for it!
- [Chuckling]
- I should have known!
- Come on, Zak.
Crysta, we were so worried about...
- What's that?
- Father, I'd like you to meet Zak.
- Hi.
- He's a bodacious babe.
- A what?
- He's a human!
[All Gasp]
[All Chattering]
Somehow I thought they'd be...
bigger.
Well, I had a little accident,
and he sort of shrank.
But just think...
humans back in the forest.
Yep, there goes the neighborhood.
- Be nice, Batty.
- First thing, all these trees go.
Then come your highways, then come your
shopping malls and your parking lots...
and your convenience stores,
and then come...
Price check on prune juice, Bob.
Price check on prune juice.
Crysta! Where you been?
I've been looking all over for ya.
Pips, you won't believe what I found.
Isn't he amazing?
Shouldn't we be charging
admission for this?
That's all you've got to say?
I been out all night,
and you want to show me
this weird creature here?
This "weird creature" is a human.
Hmm. He's kinda small,
ain't he?
- [Whistles]
- [All Shouting] Look out!
[All Gasp]
Uh, Pips, why don't you tell us
about your strange treasure?
Oh. Well,
it's simple, really.
It's hard like stone,
yet, uh... yet it's hollow.
And, uh, yeah, it has this, uh...
it has this little vine
coming out of it and... and...
It's my stereo.
Look, I found it,
so I'll explain it, all right?
Okay.
Then what is it?
- Well, it's obviously, um...
- [Fairies] Yeah?
Obviously, it's, uh...
- [Music] [Rock]
- [Zak] Where are you going?
- It's alive!
- And it's noisy!
It's a recording of music.
Well, I don't know
what a recording is,
but I know what music is,
and that is not music.
- ♪ Come on, everybody, gather 'round ♪
- Come on!
♪Na, na-na-na-na na-na-na-na,
na-na-na na-na-na ♪
- ♪Na-na-na-na ♪
- ♪I need somebody to help me Come on ♪
♪Na, na-na-na-na
na-na-na-na ♪
Rock out, fairies!
Come on! Move, move, move!
Get the beat!
♪ You gotta know how to pony
like bony maroni ♪
- Audio pollution! Oh! Oh!
- ♪Hot potato ♪
♪Do the alligator ♪
♪Put your hands
on your hips, yeah ♪
♪Let the backbone slip ♪
♪Do the Watusi ♪
♪ With my little Lucy ♪
- ♪ Come on ♪
- Whoo-hoo!
♪ Na, na-na-na-na na-na-na-na,
na-na-na na-na-na ♪
♪Na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Na, na-na-na-na na-na-na-na,
na-na-na na-na-na ♪
♪Na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ It sure feels good, yeah
Like I knew it would ♪
♪Feel all right, yeah ♪
♪ You know
way down in the alley ♪
- ♪ Long, tall Sally ♪
- Whoo!
♪ Twistin' with the new thing ♪
♪ Doin' the Watusi ♪
♪ Roll over on your back, yeah ♪
♪I like it like that ♪
♪ Push it through the jerk ♪
- ♪ And then watch me watch me work ♪
- Hey!
Come with me and the boys.
We'll give you a taste of real FernGully wildlife.
Unless, of course,
you're not up to it, "Zap."
- I'm up to anything you can dish out, bud.
- [Growling]
[Laughing]
- Not now, Pips.
- Nuts!
- Come on, Zak.
- Hey! Hey, where they goin'?
See you around, "Zag."
[Zak Sighs]
[Giggling]
♪Anytime you want ♪
♪ To be right here ♪
♪Just imagine me ♪
[Giggling]
♪And all this will appear ♪
♪ You can keep this moment ♪
♪All your life
forever near ♪
Come on, Zak.
♪A dream worth keeping ♪
♪ When you're feelin' lost ♪
♪I'll be your star ♪
♪Just reach out and touch me ♪
- ♪No matter where you are ♪
- [Giggling]
♪In a world
where precious things ♪
♪Are disappearing overnight ♪
♪Just keep my star in sight ♪
♪I believe ♪
♪ We've found the dream ♪
♪ That we're keeping ♪
♪For more than just a day ♪
♪And even though ♪
♪ The winds of change ♪
♪May come sweeping ♪
♪It's still a dream
worth keeping ♪
♪So don't let it ♪
♪Fade away ♪
♪Someday you might
be thinking ♪
♪ That life has passed you by ♪
♪ Your spirits
might be sinking ♪
♪ With hope in short supply ♪
♪And that's the reason why ♪
♪ That's the reason why ♪
- ♪I know your dream's worth keeping ♪
- [Giggling]
♪As long as it will stay ♪
♪Even when you see ♪
♪ The darkness come creeping ♪
♪A dream worth keeping ♪
♪ Will never fade away ♪
Well, I guess I better go find
Magi and get you unshrunk.
- There's no hurry.
- No, I promised.
Let it wait till tomorrow.
Come here.
No, I've got to tell her
about you anyway.
Wait here. I'll be back
as soon as I can find her.
- Hey, what's goin' on, Zak?
- What are you talkin' about?
You know exactly what I'm
talkin' about... the forest.
- You know what's happening, don't you?
- What?
Good idea. Ask the human.
He may know.
- Uh, Crysta...
- You lied to me!
[Stammering]
I-I... Crysta...
I wish... I wish
the human tales were true.
They're not here
to protect the forest.
They're cutting down trees.
They're destroying the forest.
[All Gasp]
And I was helping them do it.
Batty was right.
- I was?
- They're coming this way.
You can't stop them.
You'll have to leave.
The humans have released Hexxus.
Gather everyone in the circle.
You know, Zak, truth doesn't
always win friends,
but it certainly influences people.
You're not half bad for a hominid.
[Sobbing]
Father?
- [Magi] Since the beginning of time,
- Oh, Father.
We have been the guardians
and the healers of the forest.
We have too long forgotten
the magic powers of nature.
The time has come
to call on them again.
Remember:
All the magic of creation...
exists within a single tiny seed.
[Thunder Rumbling]
♪[Vocalizing]
♪[Vocalizing Continues]
We must go to Magi.
Look for the hero
inside yourself, Crysta.
Look to the good and loving heart
in you and all others.
For just as every seed holds
the power and magic of creation,
so, too, do you...
and every other creature
in this world.
♪[Vocalizing Continues]
Magi, don't leave me.
I love you.
I'll always be with you.
[Echoing]
We all have a power,
and it grows when it is shared.
Remember what you've learned, Crysta.
Oh, Crysta's gone.
Oh, look!
We did it, Zak.
Now Hexxus can never harm
FernGully again.
But humans still could.
That's why I have to go back.
There's a part of me
that really wants to stay.
There's a part of you
that will always stay.
Remember, Zak.
Remember everything.
Keep the stereo, dude.
- Thanks, dude.
- Hey, he's not going already?
He was a nice guy.
- He just needed wings.
- What was done, now undo.
Return you to the form...
that's true.
Good-bye, Zak.
Oh.
Batty.
[Gasps] I've shrunk!
- Zak!
- What happened here?
I will remember.
Guys, things have gotta change.
[Magi's Voice] Crysta, help it grow.
Hey! Where are you going?
♪ You fell through a tunnel ♪
♪Solid walls
should be broken down ♪
♪And you can't see
the field of grain ♪
♪Has been turned into
a raging battleground ♪
♪And you live
with the consequence ♪
♪ Tell me
Why don't you understand ♪
♪ You'll destroy all the love
that's been created ♪
♪Feeding mouths
with an empty hand ♪
♪And it's all such a simple thing
Changin' everything ♪
♪Listening to the one who
brings all this love to you ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Don't you care Stop and think
about us and what you feel ♪
♪I'll be there Don't you cut
yourself off from what is real ♪
♪Don't live in
some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ You don't live in
some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ There's a boat
down from paradise ♪
♪If you hurry
you can ride it back ♪
♪As my bait hits the water ♪
♪It don't take long
till the sharks attack ♪
♪But it's all just a simple thing
Changes everything ♪
♪Let me be the one who brings
all this love to you ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Don't you care Stop and think
about us and what you feel ♪
♪I'll be there Don't you cut
yourself off from what is real ♪
♪Don't live in
some other world ♪
♪In some other world ♪
♪ You don't live in
some other world ♪
♪In some other world ♪
♪ Gotta stop livin'
in some other world ♪
♪Livin' here
will change your mind ♪
♪And it's all such a simple thing
Changin' everything ♪
♪Listen to the one who brings
all this love to you ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Some other world
Some other world ♪
♪ That's where you live ♪
♪Don't you care Stop and think
about us and what you feel ♪
♪I'll be there Don't you cut
yourself off from what is real ♪
♪Don't live in
some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ You don't live in
some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
- ♪Some other world ♪
- ♪ This is our world ♪
♪Not some other world ♪
♪ You don't live in
some other world ♪
♪Live in our world ♪
♪Not some other world ♪
♪ You don't live in
some other world ♪
♪ This is our world
not some other world ♪
♪Some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh Some other world ♪
♪Some other world ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪