Don't know how many times.
I've been crossed off the
list and left for dead.
Guess when it first happens
the day you were born,
you're gonna lose count.
So this,
this ain't nothing new.
There are bad days,
and then there are
legendary bad days.
Whole damn planet
wanted a piece of me.
Can't stay in the open.
Can't risk another attack.
It's always the punch you don't
see coming that puts you down.
But why didn't I see it?
Of course they were
gonna try to kill me.
Death is what they
do for a living.
So the question ain't
"What happened?".
The question is.
"What happened to me?"
You are the Lord Marshal now.
How did they get so close?
How did I let them
blindside me like that?
Threshold!
Take us to the threshold!
Necromongers.
Some wanted to put a
crown on my head.
noose around my neck.
Okay, more nooses than crowns.
I needed a way out.
Some new place.
Or maybe just an old one.
But how do you find something
you've never seen?
Making more friends, I see.
But who put her up to it?
Which commander?
It could be any of many.
Don't doubt it for a second,
Commander Vaako.
Lord Marshal.
They say you lost
your nerve, Vaako,
after that big
swing and a miss.
Is that what they say?
Now what are you gonna do
to get that cred back?
What's the big play?
Something splashy.
Actually,
I had in mind
something different.
I've been thinking about
an early campaign.
My very first.
I was but a boy.
We dropped from the sky and
did what Necromongers do.
Destruction was breathtaking.
But then we met resistance.
Ferocious like a
storm of lions.
Each one of them killed
over a hundred Necro
before their weapons failed.
And then they killed
another 30 more.
Barehanded.
Our firepower and
strength in numbers
eventually won us the day.
I can still see him, the last
of those magnificent warriors,
standing on a pile of his own.
And he looked at me.
And I will never
forget those eyes.
His eyes were just like yours.
The planet was Furya.
I know what it's called.
You just don't
know where it is.
I need charts. I need maps.
- Impossible.
- I need a direction.
Purged from all records,
as you well know.
But you remember where.
So many worlds...
The only map left in existence
is the one that's in
my head, Riddick.
So what do you want?
The crown?
Transcendence.
Krone.
Break off a ship.
Riddick's going home.
Transcendence.
I guess that was Necro speak for "Get the
fuck off our ship and make it forever."
Fine by me.
You can't blame him
for dangling Furya.
Home has a certain equity.
But I do blame him
for what came next.
It's along way to come.
For this.
This guy with the
fucked-up face, Krone,
he was supposed to
be our ride home.
But instead of Furya, we
wind up someplace called...
Not Furya.
Yet again, someone was
trying to play me.
So yet again,
we play for blood.
You keep what you
kill, Riddick!
You keep what you kill!
Somewhere along
the way, I lost a step.
I got sloppy.
Dulled my own edge.
Maybe I went and did the
worst crime of all...
I got civilized.
So now we zero the clock.
Just me and this
no-name world.
Gotta find that
animal side again.
Before long, I realized there was
a whole other world over there,
of water, grass and life.
Just had one thing in my way.
Hey.
Come on, show me some teeth.
Escape artist, huh?
What you got over there?
Thought we shared everything.
Drop it.
Stay.
Bounty hunters.
Wait.
Wait...
Steady...
Okay, now.
Sounds good.
Mmm...
Mmm!
All yours.
It says "dog food" on it.
If you could read.
Come on.
All right. Bring
me my reserve.
Where's yours?
Rain.
It's a good thing.
Just because you've never seen it
before doesn't mean it's a bad thing.
Hey, easy.
Looks like our
time is up here.
Nothing.
Look again, Diaz.
Somebody should teach this
Riddick asshole how to count.
"Leave one ship"? Like we've got
a fucking spare laying around.
Let's crank it up.
Good morning, Cyclops.
Shit. Here comes
the neighborhood.
Small world.
Unidentified vessel, this is
Clan Vagos out of Ursa Five.
Be advised that we are
on the ground now
and have responded to
an emergency signal.
No distress found,
no need to land.
I repeat, there is no reason for you
to land at this location at this time.
Is that clear?
No reason for you to land at
this location at this time.
What the fuck did I just say?
It was a long haul. We
could take on some water.
Wouldn't mind a little
true-gravity time either.
Like I was saying,
I've got this.
You knew who that was, right?
On the emergency beacon?
Wouldn't be here if I didn't.
The concept of back-up still
has no appeal to you?
My besties here can
ball with anyone.
No disrespect for
your crew, of course,
who look strong, too, in
those matchy-matchy outfits.
Shit. Didn't know there
was a dress code.
Yeah, right?
Well, it's not my intention
to jump another man's claim.
If you don't mind, maybe
we'll just pull up a chair
and spectate for a while.
What if I do?
Well, this is a co-op station,
pal. It's open to all Mercs.
- By the way, my name is...
- "Too late."
That's your name. "Too Late."
And I don't need you stepping all
over my dick here, my friend.
Well, I'll tell you what.
I won't lift a finger to help until
you come ask me for it. How's that?
I was scoping
this out earlier.
It's a cave system.
Five clicks South.
Might be worth a look.
Hey, Too Late.
Need to pull a node
from your ship
and store it right here
next to mine. Okay?
Really? Why is that?
Riddick triggered the beacon
to get off-world, right?
Basically, he was
calling a taxi.
And...
And a ship would make
a sweet trap, right?
Confined space, metal
walls, jail cell.
Is cool, huh?
Is it true half the
people you meet
are below average
intelligence?
Got to make sure the ship stays
grounded when he comes for them, okay?
Come on.
Dahl, pull a node
from the ship.
I'll do it...
Ooh!
Ooh...
Any time now, Riddick.
I'm telling you, this
is total overkill.
What? Eleven of
us out here now?
Should have been a
four-man op, tops.
You are jinxing our janx, man.
And that ain't cool.
Hey, I don't give a shit
what they say. He's one guy.
Whatever you say, man.
He's one guy.
Man...
So I guess that's what passes for
a fucking moon on this planet.
It's gonna be a dark night.
Advantage, him.
Maybe he's gonna wear you down first.
Force you to go without sleep.
Can't you see I'm busy?
I'm just sharing my thoughts.
Well, now that you have,
can I politely invite you to
step off my fucking porch?
I'll start rotating down.
You let me know, huh?
As soon as I have his head in
a box, I will let you know.
Grid 29D. Stand by, stand by.
What you got, cuz?
Aha, some dingo-dongo thing.
Yeah. I see it now.
You want me to pop it?
Knock it down. One
shot suppressed.
Nice work, Diaz. Encouraging.
Had something in my eye.
It's called a scope.
Try next time.
You got this, right?
Will you get off my
freaking frequency!
What the fuck is
going on here?
Thank fucking God!
Fuck off!
Rubio, coming your way now.
Gotta swap out a bad sensor.
What was here versus
what was found.
How does it square?
Pretty good. I mean,
the morphine's gone,
but that's always the
first thing to go.
That was a bit weird, though.
"A predator restraint with
42-inch offset jaws."
Six listed, zero found.
That is an odd thing
to go for a walk.
Yeah, but, Boss, you know how shit
goes missing from these stations.
One bad year and guys are
ripping shit off for salvage.
Hey, Santana?
You did sweep the area
before I got here, right?
Sweep for what?
I just want to make sure
no one has set any traps for us.
5Q.
Understand what I'm saying?
Traps? What kind of traps?
The kind with jaws.
Don't touch that
fucking thing!
What?
Up-armor.
Shit!
Ready. Ready.
Stay put,
stay put, stay put, stay put!
Oopah!
Who the hell was
that screaming and why?
Nunez, break out
the sweep gear.
And figure out how many
of these big-ass traps
we got out here, okay?
I'm thinking maybe the
whole upper left quad
is some kind of
fucking mine field.
You got to do that
now, okay, Nunez?
Copy that, Nunez?
Nunez?
This is bad. This is very bad.
Nunez? Nunez?
Shut the fuck up, puto!
His radio just crapped out.
Someone get eyes on him.
Make sure he's right where he
should be, 13-H. Go, go, go!
Right here.
13-H. He's supposed to
be right fucking...
Don't mess with me now.
Hey. Hey, what is it?
What is it?
- Get back!
- It's me, it's me.
He's got Falco!
Jock up, but you're
staying home.
No one's going out
there until I say so.
Man down,
he's got Falco.
Compromise, compromise.
How the fuck
did he do that?
Never ever saw him, man.
He was right here and I never...
What about the ship?
Is he on it?
He's not coming for the
ships, he's coming for fucking us!
Just fucking shoot! Shoot!
One night, three dead.
Not sure I'm
loving this trend.
Two dead, one missing.
Exactly. Three dead.
Well, look at it
this way, boys.
We might all fit
on one ship now.
Diaz!
Get those other
traps back there.
Luna, say something
Bible-like over these bodies.
Okay, maybe,
we zero this out.
What is your tag anyway?
So now you wanna know my name.
Well, I'm not sure
I'm gonna say.
Because everyone you know by
name, Santana, winds up dead.
You gonna clean this shit up?
- Excuse me.
- Wow.
Watch out for
surprise attacks.
Maybe...
Maybe it's time to start
merging assets, right?
So this is you
asking for my help?
This is me saying that I may
need some of your gear.
If some of your guys happen to
come attached to that gear,
I will understand that's
the way it's gotta be.
So you're asking for
my gear's help?
More like that.
Moss...
The gear's saying,
"Nah." Bitch.
There's your answer.
What the fuck do
you want, man?
You know what? I'm gonna
fold you in, Santana.
But I give orders to Dahl. And
Delhi's gonna give orders to you.
And that's the chain of command
from this point forward.
Why am I not loving
this plan so far?
Oh, I know, I know.
You know why?
Because it sucks
ass and swallows!
I'm not taking orders
from your pet whore
who thinks I won't smack
her right back...
I don't fuck guys.
Occasionally I fuck 'em
up if they need it.
Here's what's gonna happen, Santana.
You're gonna take a back seat.
We'll track Riddick
down, I promise.
But I want him alive.
You give me a day, and after
that he's yours to kill.
You're giving me the bounty?
You pay my crew, fuel costs, the
rest is yours. That's the deal.
What is Riddick for you?
Not just some convict.
What do you want?
Why are you here?
Who are you?
My name is Johns.
Lock down those ships,
get those hogs on deck.
I will ride with
Moss and Lockspur.
I want a non-lethal load-out, L.O.D.'s
and phosphor frags to start with.
This is a man that hunts by night.
We'll take it to him by day.
Diaz! Vargas! Show me the
spot of the last kill.
Some kind of canine.
Hey, Diaz, I got a dog here.
Is it the same dingo-dongo
thing from last night?
Nah, I'm pretty sure
we killed that one.
Could be the same one.
The same.
Dahl, get your sniper rifle
and barium rounds now.
1,500 meters.
Could be just the first hole it found.
A stressed animal is gonna
run to ground it knows.
Besides, I'm getting
human pheromones.
Riddick!
Dial down, dial
down, dial down!
Santana's guy.
Falco.
Shit. Did we
just kill a hostage?
I've been hunting
Riddick for 10 years.
The concept of a hostage
has no appeal to him.
Falco was already dead.
This is just some fucking
sideshow to buy more time.
Whoa! Fuck...
Shit.
Just dropped some
mud right there.
So if Riddick isn't here...
Remember, he could
be anywhere.
This is Johns to
any-goddamn-body at the station.
I want you to keep an eye on that
locker. Keep an eye on the node.
Riddick may have
made an end run.
My ETA is seven minutes.
But watch your back.
You need to see this.
He wrote that?
He took out our deep space
communications. All of it.
And whose blood is that?
There... Here...
Over there...
I had to kick his ass again.
Sorry.
Not really.
Fuck it.
Let's take a look at this.
Six.
Huh.
You are a shit storm trooper,
Santana. I'll give you that.
You beat the devil this time.
Didn't actually
think he was gonna do it.
This is a sign.
Ah, sweet.
I believe this is a sign.
It may be that the good Lord
wants us to take these nodes
and flee this planet
just as soon as we can.
That's my good luck charm.
Wrong business, kid.
You know, I was kind of
hoping the bomb would go off.
So we sealed up his cave with some
phosphor frags here, so he can't go back.
And just like an animal, he's
gonna head to known ground.
But we're gonna find he's got
three or four lairs out there.
So we'll radius out
from this point, here.
Now radio comms... I saw three
repeaters listed in inventory.
Find them. Set them up
at regular intervals.
I never want to be out of
touch like that again.
Are you scared of me?
Yeah.
Are they scared of me?
Yes, they're scared of you.
Maybe you're all scared
of the wrong thing.
Lockspur, I want you to lock
down those hogs, all right?
I don't want this guy any more
mobile than he already is.
Now, Dahl, I spotted a
nice little nest for you.
Right here and in
these low hills.
Moss?
I just saw him.
Say again?
Dahl, I want you to
sit on this ship!
Diaz, make sure your
ship is locked down!
The rest of you get on
the fucking perimeter
and keep your eyes
on each other!
Santana! He got the
fucking nodes!
I know. It's coming.
So then we just combine nodes.
Pull one from that ship, put
it in this ship, you know?
Amps is amps, right?
It's not about amps. It's about
What each ship is rated to handle.
You miss by even a few milli-joules,
you fry every chip you've got.
Okay, so figure out the
difference, and just do it.
Jailbreak the fucking thing.
I could give you
a crash course
on thermodynamic equilibrium
and energy exchange right now,
or maybe you just want to take
my goddamn word for it...
I get it. I get it.
The ships are incompatible. We're not
gonna fly without the nodes back.
Why do I feel like we just
cut off our own nuts here?
Probably because we did.
How about I take one of those jet
hogs, two days' worth of food
and go out and hunt this
fucker down myself?
Bad idea, Diaz.
One-on-one with Riddick?
I might be able to get the
emergency beacon working again.
That's like an ambulance calling
for an ambulance, isn't it?
It's back-up for the
fucking back-up. We can't.
I thought he was
the one stranded here.
Yeah, well, looks
like you thought wrong.
Long wait for back-up.
In case you were
thinking about
fixing the beacon and
calling for help.
Falco's radio.
Riddick, I don't give a
fuck about the back-up.
Because I've still got
all kinds of gear
that can ruin your
day in a hurry.
So you go find another
fucking cave.
You keep running,
you keep hiding.
Doesn't matter me none.
Because in the end,
I will find you!
Look South.
I don't believe it.
The balls on this fucking guy.
Dahl, keep an eye
on things here.
What should I do?
Stay low.
Come on. Come on.
Both of you drop.
So what's the bounty at?
I don't know. I don't care.
It's not why I'm here.
I bet the big jamoke knows.
Yeah. I know exactly
what it is.
What I do know is that it's double
if you're brought back dead.
That's new.
Will it be enough to
pay for your funerals?
What I'm interested in
is a little backwater place
with a system code M-344/G.
I want to know what happened
there 10 years ago.
The father.
Big Daddy Johns.
Yeah, that's right.
And you traveled all
this way just to see me.
I'm flattered.
It's kind of strange
not knowing
what to put down in
the family Bible.
It's kind of strange three guys have
to die just so that you can hear...
No, no, no. You don't get
to put that shit on me.
Those kills are on you.
I have a feeling that's not the
only thing on me right now.
Okay, got barium shells,
stab-shock, explosive tip.
What do you want,
barium or stab-shock?
Horse tranq.
Okay.
I'll give you till that
rain hits that station.
That's your clock.
Dahl! Do it now! Now!
Again!
He's not going down.
Do it again, Dahl!
Just go down.
I got this, Dahl.
Riddick.
Riddick?
Johns?
We beating men in chains now?
Okay, from the beginning.
For the historical record...
The Hunter Gratzner.
That's the commercial
vessel my son uses
to transport you
back to the slammer.
But that ship sends a distress
call somewhere near M-344/G.
It's a backwater system, with
two suns, one habitable planet.
Does he survive the crash?
Big drama the next few hours.
But whatever happens, no
matter what they tell you,
don't let 'em take
these chains off me.
Them? Who's "them"? Who
are you talking...
Do you know who you're
talking to here?
That was for me?
For the historical record,
he made it.
So it's just you and him?
Was, uh,
about the same number you
see here in this room.
So how many made it off?
Three.
But not him?
No.
So between the time of the crash and
the time you leave that planet,
my son dies.
And I can safely assume it's
at your hands. Is that right?
Tell me what you see
outside that window, Dahl.
Cyclops unit, two ships,
couple dead guys in plastic.
And you don't see anything else?
Nothing else.
Time's up.
Time is up.
He's all yours.
Hold him down.
More dingo-dongos maybe.
Lucky.
I know what's coming.
Called to find you.
The serpents...
spotlight!
Like I said,
it ain't me you
gotta worry about.
What is it? What's out there?
I don't know.
Fucked up or
something out there.
It ain't right.
It's coming our way.
Whatever they are, they
ain't so hard to kill.
What the fuck?
Fuck!
No more holes, please.
What the fuck is happening?
How fucked are we?
Who knows how long
it will rain?
Or just how many of them
are buried out there?
He saw it. He saw it with those eyes
of his and he didn't tell us what.
One ship for you, one for me.
I need to know that these
nodes are retrievable.
And I need to know
we have a deal.
We got a deal.
The chains stay on.
Why don't we sit this one out?
Okay. Okay.
Up, up, up...
Good doggie.
Oh!
Holy shit.
Where the hell did that... Jesus Christ!
No, no, no!
What the fuck is wrong with
you, you crazy bastard?
You could have killed me!
Got it, didn't I?
Vargas, get up.
Come on, let's go.
Vargas, come on, man.
Walk it off.
Let's go. It's
just a little one.
Small ones are the worst.
They save the most venom.
I forgot to mention,
there's no weapons for you.
You think you can ride
one of these things?
I'll ride it like I stole it.
I'll take flank.
If Riddick comes back
here without us,
you go ahead, you kill him
on general principle.
Is that before or after
I'm supposed to fuck him?
How bad you want
those nodes, Johns?
I don't suppose you took the
time to do this for him, huh?
This may come as a
shock to you, Johns,
but I didn't ghost your son.
He seemed set on
killing himself.
What the fuck does that mean?
Morphine.
Your son liked his morphine.
Liked it twice a day.
Didn't know your
son was a junkie?
Johns was like most Mercs.
They look all
stand-up and do-right
until you out them open and
you find something missing.
In his case, a spine.
I don't have to listen to this
shit! That's not the man I knew.
Then you didn't know your son.
He wanted to kill a kid.
To save his own skin.
I had a problem with that.
You expect me to believe
my son was gonna kill a
child to save his own life?
Morphine makes the
brain soft. Heart weak.
I don't fucking buy it!
I just can't believe that
my son's the bad guy
in this fucking demented
fairy tale of yours.
No reason to lie now.
Johns.
Either one of us.
Thanks for starting the killing
spree for me, Riddick.
But I'll take it from here.
Jamoke.
So that blade you buried
was meant for me?
Anyone who deserved
it, really.
We've got a problem, Riddick,
because I've got
two nodes here.
We've got one hog.
And I sure as shit am not
riding bitch with you again.
One hog?
You sure about that, Johns?
He pulled the goddamn
turbine pin!
You just figured that out?
Diaz was gonna take the nodes
for himself and ghost me.
He was gonna leave
you out here alone.
So what now?
Now we switch to
our ground game.
Let's see if that lack of
spine runs in the family.
Reload!
Watch your head.
Go!
I got inbound.
Take this!
Is it just you?
Just slam this thing in.
See if it's still good.
Boss...
Just see if the fucking thing
works! We need to get outta here.
Extraction, 30 seconds or less.
Let's go, let's go!
Lot of good
men died here, Riddick.
Not sure how I'm supposed to
overlook that. Next time.
Yeah. Things would
have been different
if they weren't trying
to put my head in a box.
So where to now, Riddick?
You know what? Fuck that.
Don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
I'll tell you this, Johns.
Sooner or later, we all
have to head home.
Tell Dahl to keep
it warm for me.
And, Johns,
you keep a strong spine.
Vaako.
- You are still alive.
- Tell me where.
He's no longer among us.
Tell me, and I'll
kill him first.
You misunderstand.
Vaako is a decent man who
meant to honor his word.
Even with you, strangely.
I don't care about Furya.
I don't care what the pact
was between you and him.
This faith cannot
have a misbeliever
or a kind heart leading it,
and I have done what I have
done to ensure...
Too many words.
Never lie to me,
I'll never hurt you.
One word answer.
Is Vaako alive or dead?
Both.
Transcendence.