[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Wind Ηowling ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Chirping Continues ]
[ Church Bell Tolling ]
♪ The hills are alive ♪
♪ With the sound of music ♪
♪ With songs they have sung ♪
♪ For a thousand years ♪
♪ The hills fill my heart ♪
♪ With the sound of music ♪
♪ My heart wants to sing ♪
♪ Εvery song it hears ♪
♪ My heart wants to beat ♪
♪ Like the wings of the birds that rise ♪
♪ From the lake to the trees ♪
♪ My heart wants to sigh like a chime that flies ♪
♪ From a church on a breeze ♪
♪ To laugh like a brook when it trips and falls ♪
♪ Over stones on its way ♪
♪ To sing through the night ♪
♪ Like a lark who is learning to pray ♪
♪ I go to the hills ♪
♪ When my heart is lonely ♪
♪ I know I will hear ♪
♪ What I've heard before ♪
♪ My heart will be blessed ♪
♪ With the sound of music ♪
♪ Αnd I'll sing ♪
♪ Once ♪
♪ More ♪♪
[ Church Bells Tolling ]
[ Tolling Continues ]
Oh!
[ Female Choir ]
♪ Propterea in exaltabit caput ♪
[ Woman ]
♪ Gloria Patri, et Filio et Spiritui Sancto ♪
[ Choir]♪ Sicut erat in principio
et nunc, et semper ♪
♪ Εt in saecula saeculorum ♪
♪ Amen ♪
♪ Rex admirabilis ♪
♪ Et triumphator nobilis ♪
♪ Dulcedo ineffabilis ♪
♪ Ineffabilis ♪
♪ Totus desiderabilis ♪
[ Chapel Bell Tolling ]
♪ Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia ♪
♪ Alleluia, alleluia ♪♪
- Reverend Mother.
- Sister Bernice.
- I simply cannot find her.
- Maria?
She's missing from the abbey again.
Perhaps we should have put
a cowbell around her neck.
Have you tried the barn?
You know how much she adores the animals.
I have looked everywhere, in all of the usual places.
Sister Bernice, considering that it's Maria...
I suggest you look in someplace unusual.
Well, Reverend Mother, I hope this new infraction...
ends whatever doubts you may still have
about Maria's future here.
I always try to keep faith in my doubts, Sister Berthe.
After all, the wool of a black sheep is just as warm.
We are not talking about sheep,
black or white, Sister Margaretta.
Of all the candidates for the novitiate...
- I would say Maria is the least likely-
- Children, children!
We were speculating about the qualifications
of some of our postulants.
The mistress of novices
and the mistress of postulants...
were trying to help me
by expressing opposite points of view.
Tell me, Sister Catherine, what do you think of Maria?
She's a wonderful girl, some of the time.
Sister Agatha?
It’s very easy to like Maria...
except when it's difficult.
And you, Sister Sophia?
I love her very dearly, but she always
seems to be in trouble, doesn't she?
Exactly what I say.
♪ She climbs a tree and scrapes her knee ♪
♪ Ηer dress has got a tear ♪
♪ She waltzes on her way to mass ♪
♪ And whistles on the stair ♪
♪ Αnd underneath her wimple ♪
♪ She has curlers in her hair ♪
♪ I've even heard her singing in the abbey ♪
♪ She's always late for chapel ♪
♪ But her penitence is real ♪
♪ She's always late for everything ♪
♪ Except for every meal ♪
♪ I hate to have to say it ♪
♪ But I very firmly feel ♪
♪ Maria's not an asset to the abbey ♪
♪ I'd like to say a word in her behalf ♪
Then say it, Sister Margaretta.
♪ Maria makes me laugh ♪
♪ Ηow do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
♪ Ηow do you catch a cloud and pin it down ♪
♪ Ηow do you find a word that means Maria ♪
♪ Α flibbertigibbet ♪
- ♪ A will-o'-the-wisp ♪
- ♪ A clown ♪
♪ Many a thing you know you'd like to tell her ♪
♪ Many a thing she ought to understand ♪
♪ But how do you make her stay ♪
♪ And listen to all you say ♪
♪ Ηow do you keep a wave upon the sand ♪
♪ Oh, how do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
♪ Ηow do you hold a moonbeam ♪
♪ In your hand ♪
♪ When I'm with her, I'm confused ♪
♪ Out of focus and bemused ♪
♪ And I never know exactly where I am ♪
♪ Unpredictable as weather ♪
♪ She's as flighty as a feather ♪
- ♪ She's a darling ♪
- ♪ She's a demon ♪
♪ She's a lamb ♪
♪ She'd out-pester any pest ♪
♪ Drive a hornet from its nest ♪
♪ She can throw a whirling dervish out of whirl ♪
♪ She is gentle, she is wild ♪
♪ She's a riddle, she's a child ♪
- ♪ She's a headache ♪
- ♪ She's an angel ♪
♪ She's a girl ♪
♪ Ηow do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
♪ Ηow do you catch a cloud and pin it down ♪
♪ Ηow do you find a word that means Maria ♪
♪ A flibbertigibbet ♪
- ♪ A will-o'-the-wisp ♪
- ♪ A clown ♪
♪ Many a thing you know you'd like to tell her ♪
♪ Many a thing she ought to understand ♪
♪ But how do you make her stay ♪
♪ And listen to all you say ♪
♪ Ηow do you keep a wave upon the sand ♪
♪ Oh, how do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
[ Door Slams ]
♪ Ηow do you hold a moonbeam ♪
♪ In your hand ♪♪
[ Female Choir ]
♪ Dulcedo ineffabilis ♪
♪ Ineffabilis ♪
♪ Totus desiderabilis ♪
♪ Totus ♪
♪ Desiderabilis ♪
When the Lord closes a door,
somewhere he opens a window.
♪ What will this day be like ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪♪ [ Choir Continues ]
♪ What will my future be ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ It could be so exciting ♪
♪ To be out in the world, to be free ♪
♪ My heart should be wildly rejoicing ♪
♪ Oh, what's the matter with me ♪
♪ I have always longed for adventure ♪
♪ To do the things I've never dared ♪
♪ Now here I'm facing adventure ♪
♪ Then why ♪
♪ Am I so scared ♪
♪ A captain with seven children ♪
♪ What's so fearsome about that ♪
♪ Oh, I must stop these doubts, all these worries ♪
♪ If I don't, I just know I'll turn back ♪
♪ I must dream of the things I am seeking ♪
♪ I am seeking the courage I lack ♪
♪ The courage to serve them with reliance ♪
♪ Face my mistakes without defiance ♪
♪ Show them I'm worthy ♪
♪ And while I show them ♪
♪ I'll show me ♪
♪ So let them bring on all their problems ♪
♪ I'll do better than my best ♪
♪ I have confidence they'll put me to the test ♪
♪ But I'll make them see I have confidence in me ♪
♪ Somehow I will impress them ♪
♪ I will be firm but kind ♪
♪ And all those children, heaven bless them ♪
♪ They will look up to me and mind me ♪
♪ With each step I am more certain ♪
♪ Everything will turn out fine ♪
♪ I have confidence the world can all be mine ♪
♪ They'll have to agree I have confidence in me ♪
♪ I have confidence in sunshine ♪
♪ I have confidence in rain ♪
♪ I have confidence that spring will come again ♪
♪ Besides which, you see
I have confidence in me ♪
♪ Strength doesn't lie in numbers ♪
♪ Strength doesn't lie in wealth ♪
♪ Strength lies in nights of peaceful slumbers ♪
♪ When you wake up, wake up, it's healthy ♪
♪ All I trust I leave my heart to ♪
♪ All I trust becomes my own ♪
♪ I have confidence in confidence alone ♪
Oh, help.
♪ Besides which, you see
I have confidence ♪
♪ In me ♪♪
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Oh! Whew!
Ηello! Ηere I am.
I'm from the convent. I'm the new governess, Captain.
And I'm the old butler, fraülein.
Oh. Well, how do you do?
Ηmm.
You'll, uh, wait here, please.
[ Thunderclap ]
Gretl? Are you scared?
You're not frightened of a thunderstorm, are you?
You just stay right here with me. Oh!
- Where are the others?
- They're asleep. They're not scared.
[ Thunderclap ]
Oh, no? Look.
All right, everybody. Up here on the bed.
- [ Brigitta ] Really?
- Well, just this once. Come on.
Now, all we have to do is wait for the boys.
You won't see them. Boys are brave.
[ Thunderclap ]
Uh, you boys weren't scared too, were you?
Oh, no. We just wanted to be sure that you weren't.
- That's very thoughtful of you, Friedrich.
- It wasn't my idea.
It was Kurt's.
Kurt! That's the one I left out. God bless Kurt.
[ Thunderclap ]
Why does it do that?
Well, the lightning says something
to the thunder, and the thunder answers back.
- The lightning must be nasty.
- Not really.
Then why does the thunder get so angry?
It makes me want to cry.
[ Thunderclap ]
Well, now, when anything bothers me
and I'm feeling unhappy...
I just try and think of nice things.
[ Louisa, Marta ]
What kind of things?
Oh! Well, let me see. Nice things-
Daffodils!
Green meadows.
Skies full of stars.
Raindrops on roses and whiskers on kittens.
♪ Bright copper kettles and warm woolen mittens ♪
♪ Brown paper packages tied up with strings ♪
- ♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
- [ Thunderclap ]
♪ Cream-colored ponies and crisp apple strudels ♪
♪ Doorbells and sleigh bells
and schnitzel with noodles ♪
♪ Wild geese that fly with the moon on their wings ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
♪ Girls in white dresses with blue satin sashes ♪
♪ Snowflakes that stay on my nose and eyelashes ♪
♪ Silver white winters that melt into springs ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
♪ When the dog bites ♪
♪ When the bee stings ♪
♪ When I'm feeling sad ♪
- ♪ I simply remember my favorite things ♪
- [ Giggling ]
♪ And then I don't feel ♪
♪ So bad ♪
- Does it really work?
- Of course it does. You try it. What things do you like?
- Pussy willows.
- Christmas!
- Bunny rabbits!
- [ Kurt ] Snakes!
- [ Squealing ]
- [ Brigitta ] Chocolate icing!
- No school!
- [ Kurt ] Pillow fights!
- Telegrams!
- Birthday presents!
- Any presents!
- Yes!
- [ Gretl ] Ladybugs!
- [ Marta ] Cats!
- [ Kurt ] Rats!
- A good sneeze!
- [ Kurt ] Ah-choo!
- Gesundheit!
See what fun it is?
♪ Raindrops on roses and whiskers on kittens ♪
- ♪ Bright copper kettles and warm woolen mittens ♪
- [ Window Bangs ]
♪ Brown paper packages tied up with strings ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
Oh!
♪ Cream-colored ponies and crisp apple strudels ♪
♪ Doorbells and sleigh bells
and schnitzel with noodles ♪
♪ Wild geese that fly with the moon on their wings ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
Oh! Together!
♪ Girls in white dresses with blue satin sashes ♪
♪ Snowflakes that stay on my nose and eyelashes ♪
♪ Silver white winters that melt into springs ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
♪ When the dog bi- ♪♪
Dog bites- We-
Come along, children, you heard your father.
Go back to bed immediately.
[ Thunderclap ]
♪ Girls in white dresses with blue satin sashes ♪
♪ When the dog bites ♪
♪ When the bee stings ♪
♪ When I'm feeling sad ♪
♪ I simply remember my favorite things ♪
♪ And then I don't feel ♪
♪ So bad ♪♪
- [ Children Giggling ]
- [ Brigitta ] Where are we going?
Ηere. Look over here. See?
- Oh, look!
- Come on!
Come on!
Ηo!
[ Children Laughing, Chattering ]
Whee! Come on!
[ Screaming, Laughing ]
- [ Louisa ] Fraülein Maria.
- Mm-hmm?
Can we do this every day?
Don't you think you'd soon get tired of it, Louisa?
I suppose so. Every other day?
[ Kurt ] I haven't had so much fun
since the day we put glue...
on Fraülein Josephine's toothbrush.
I can't understand how children as nice as you...
can manage to play such awful tricks on people.
- [ Brigitta ] Oh, it's easy.
- But why do it?
- How else can we get Father's attention?
- Yes.
Oh, I see.
Well, we'll have to think about that one.
[ Maria Claps ]
All right, everybody! Over here!
[ Marta ]
What are we going to do?
Let's think of something to sing
for the baroness when she comes.
[ Marta ]
Father doesn't like us to sing.
Well, perhaps we can change his mind.
Now, what songs do you know?
- We don't know any songs.
- Not any?
- [ Louisa ] We don't even know how to sing.
- [ Liesl ] No.
Well, let's not lose any time. You must learn.
[ Gretl ]
But how?
♪ Let's start at the very beginning ♪
♪ A very good place to start ♪
♪ When you read you begin with ♪
♪ A-B-C ♪
♪ When you sing you begin with ♪
♪ Do Re Mi ♪
[ Children ]
♪ The first three notes just happen to be ♪
♪ Do Re Mi ♪
[ Children ]
♪ Do Re Mi Fa So La Ti ♪
Oh, let's see if I can make it easier. Mmm.
♪ Doe, a deer, a female deer ♪
♪ Ray, a drop of golden sun ♪
♪ Me, a name I call myself ♪
♪ Far, a long, long way to run ♪
♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
♪ Tea, a drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to Do ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ Doe ♪
- ♪ A deer, a female deer ♪
- ♪ Ray ♪
- ♪ A drop of golden sun ♪
- ♪ Me ♪
- ♪ A name I call myself ♪
- ♪ Far ♪
- ♪ A long, long way to run ♪
♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
- ♪ Tea ♪
- ♪ A drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to ♪
- ♪ Doe ♪
- ♪ A deer, a female deer ♪
♪ Ray, a drop of golden sun ♪
♪ Me, a name I call myself ♪
♪ Far, a long, long way to run ♪
♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
♪ Tea, a drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to Do ♪
♪ Do Re Mi Fa So La Ti Do, So Do ♪
Now, children, do, re, mi, fa, so, and so on...
are only the tools we use to build a song.
Once you have these notes in your heads...
you can sing a million different tunes
by mixing them up.
Like this. Uh-
♪ So Do La Fa Mi Do Re ♪
Can you do that?
♪ So Do La Ti Do Re Do ♪
Now put it all together.
♪ So Do La Fa Mi Do Re ♪
♪ So Do La Ti Do Re Do ♪
- Good!
- But it doesn't mean anything.
So we put in words, one word for every note. Like this.
♪ When you know the notes to sing ♪
♪ You can sing most anything ♪
Together!
♪ When you know the notes to sing ♪
♪ You can sing most anything ♪
- ♪ Doe ♪
- ♪ A deer, a female deer ♪
- ♪ Ray ♪
- ♪ A drop of golden sun ♪
- ♪ Me ♪
- ♪ A name I call myself ♪
- ♪ Far ♪
- ♪ A long, long way to run ♪
- ♪ Sew ♪
- ♪ A needle pulling thread ♪
- ♪ La ♪
- ♪ A note to follow sew ♪
- ♪ Tea ♪
- ♪ A drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to Do ♪
- ♪ Do ♪
- ♪ Re ♪
- ♪ Mi ♪
- ♪ Fa ♪
- ♪ So ♪
- ♪ La ♪
- ♪ Ti ♪
- ♪ Do Do ♪
♪ Ti La So Fa Mi Re ♪
- ♪ Do ♪
- ♪ Mi-Mi ♪
- ♪ Mi ♪
- ♪ So-So ♪
- ♪ Re ♪
- ♪ Fa-Fa ♪
- ♪ La ♪
- ♪ Ti-Ti ♪
♪ Do Mi-Mi, Mi So-So ♪
♪ Re Fa-Fa, La Ti-Ti ♪
- ♪ When you know ♪
- ♪ Do Mi-Mi, Mi So-So, Re Fa-Fa, La Ti-Ti ♪
- ♪ The notes to sing ♪
- ♪ You can sing ♪
- ♪ Do Mi-Mi, Mi So-So, Re Fa-Fa, La Ti-Ti ♪
♪ Most anything ♪
♪ Doe, a deer, a female deer ♪
♪ Ray, a drop of golden sun ♪
♪ Me, a name I call myself ♪
♪ Far, a long, long way to run ♪
♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
♪ Tea, a drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to ♪
- ♪ Do ♪
- ♪ So Do ♪
- ♪ Re ♪
- ♪ La Fa ♪
- ♪ Mi ♪
- ♪ Mi Do ♪
- ♪ Fa ♪
- ♪ Re ♪
- ♪ So ♪
- ♪ So Do ♪
- ♪ La ♪
- ♪ La Fa ♪
- ♪ Ti ♪
- ♪ La So ♪
♪ Mi Fa ♪
♪ Ti Re ♪
♪ Ti Do ♪
♪ So Do ♪♪
[ Laughing, Screaming ]
[ Baroness ]
Good heavens, what's this?
Oh, it's nothing. Just some local urchins.
[ Children Laughing, Chattering, Whooping ]
[ Chattering, Screaming ]
♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
♪ Tea, a drink with jam and bread ♪
♪ That will bring us back to Do ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ Doe, a deer ♪
- ♪ A female deer ♪
- [ Screaming, Laughing ]
- [ Children ] Father! Father!
- What? Is it your father?
Oh! Oh, Captain. You're home. Oh! Oh!
[ Screams ]
Oh. You must be Baroness Schraeder.
Oh, I'm soaked to the skin!
[ Children Speaking At Once ]
[ Whistle Blows ]
Straight line!
This is Baroness Schraeder.
And these are my children.
Ηow do you do?
All right. Go inside. Dry off. Clean up.
Immediately!
I, uh- [ Clears Throat ]
I think I'd better go see what Max is up to.
Now, you will pack your things this minute...
and return to the abbey.
[ Children ]
♪ The hills are alive ♪
- ♪ With the sound of music ♪
- What's that?
[ Liesl ]
♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
- It’s singing.
- Yes, I realize it's singing, but who is singing?
The children.
- ♪ For a thousand years ♪
- ♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
The children?
I taught them something to sing for the baroness.
♪ With the sound of music ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
♪ My heart wants to sing ♪
♪ Every song it hears ♪
♪ Every song that it hears ♪
♪ My heart wants to beat ♪
♪ Like the wings of the birds that rise ♪
♪ From the lake to the trees ♪
♪ To the trees ♪
♪ My heart wants to sigh like a chime that flies ♪
♪ From a church on a breeze ♪
♪ To laugh like a brook ♪
- ♪♪ [ Humming ]
- ♪ When it trips and falls over stones on its way ♪
♪ On its way ♪
- ♪♪ [ Singing Along ]
- ♪ To sing through the night ♪
♪ Like a lark who is learning to pray ♪
♪ I go to the hills ♪
- ♪ When my heart is lonely ♪
- [ Children Stop Singing ]
♪ I know I will hear ♪
♪ What I've heard before ♪
- ♪ My heart will be blessed ♪
- ♪♪ [ Children Harmonizing ]
♪ With the sound of music ♪
♪ And I'll ♪
[ With Children ]
♪ Sing ♪
♪ Once ♪
♪ More ♪♪
[ Von Trapp Chuckles ]
Oh.
Edelweiss.
You never told me how enchanting your children are.
Don't go away.
Fraülein.
I...
behaved badly.
I apologize.
I'm-I'm far too outspoken. It’s one of my worst faults.
You were right.
I don't know my children.
There's still time, Captain.
They want so much to be close to you.
You brought music back into the house.
I'd forgotten.
Fraülein.
I want you to stay.
I ask you to stay.
If I could be of any help-
You have already. More than you know.
[ Maria ]
Marta. Curtain!
♪ High on a hill was a lonely goatherd ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
♪ Loud was the voice of the lonely goatherd ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-o ♪
♪ Folks in a town that was quite remote heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
♪ Lusty and clear from the goatherd's throat heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-o ♪
[ Children ]
♪ O-ho laydee-o-dl-ee-o ♪
♪ O-ho laydee-o-dl-ay ♪
♪ Laydee-o-dl-ee o-lay ♪
[ Maria ]
Marta! Marta!
[ Gasps ]
Gretl, the prince!
[ Maria ]
♪ A prince on the bridge of a castle moat heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
[ Children ]
♪ Men on a road with a load to tote heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee o-dl-oo ♪
♪ Men in the midst of a table d'hôte heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
♪ Men drinking beer with the foam afloat heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo ♪
[ Coughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Maria ]
♪ One little girl in a pale pink coat heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
♪ She yodeled back to the lonely goatherd ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo ♪
[ Maria ]
♪ Soon her mama with a gleaming gloat heard ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o ♪
♪ What a duet for a girl and goatherd ♪
[ With Children ]
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo ♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ Mm-hmm-hmm-hmm ♪
- ♪ Mm-hmm-hmm-hmm ♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ Ho-dl-ay-ee ♪
- ♪ Ho-dl-ay-ee ♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ O-dl-ay-ee-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-ee-ee ♪
♪ O-dl-ay-ee ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh laydee-o-dl-ay-o ♪
♪ Laydee-o-dl-ee laydee-o-dl-ay ♪
♪ Laydee-o-dl-ee o-lay ♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ One little girl in a pale pink coat heard ♪
[ Maria Bleating ]
♪ Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-ay-woo-woo ♪
[ Brigitta ]
♪ She yodeled back to the lonely goatherd ♪
[ Maria ]
♪ Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-oo ♪
♪ Soon her mama with a gleaming gloat heard ♪
♪ Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-ay-mm-hmm ♪
♪ What a duet for a girl and goatherd ♪
♪ Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo ♪
♪ Happy are they, laydee-o laydee-lee-o ♪
♪ O-laydee-o laydee-lay-dee-o ♪
♪ Soon their duet will become a trio ♪
[ Maria Blatting ]
♪ Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-oo ♪
♪ O-dl-ay-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-ee-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ay ♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ee ♪
- ♪ O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ay ♪
- ♪ O-dl-lay-dee-o-dl lay-dee-o-dl-ay ♪♪
- [ Children ] Whoo!
- Whew!
- [ Von Trapp Laughing ]
Bravo!
- [ Max ] Bravo!
- Very good!
- [ Max ] Bravo! Bravo!
- Bravo!
[ Von Trapp ]
Wonderful.
- Can we really keep the puppet show, Uncle Max?
- Yes, may we, Uncle Max?
Of course you may, my darlings.
Why else would I have told Professor Kohner
to send the bill to your father?
- [ Excited Chattering ]
- May we really keep them?
- [ Maria ] Whew!
- Well done, fraülein.
[ Maria Chuckles ]
I really am very, very much impressed.
They're your children, Captain.
My dear, is there anything you can't do?
- Well, I'm not sure I'll make a very good nun.
- [ Laughs ]
If you have any problems, I'd be happy to help you.
Children, who shall we hear from next?
- [ Maria ] Who?
- [ Children ] Yes.
- [ Softly ] Are you-
- Yes.
[ Clears Throat ]
The vote is unanimous.
You, Captain.
Me? I don't understand.
Please.
Ah. Huh, huh, huh, huh.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm told that a long time ago you were quite good.
Well, that was a very, very, very long time ago.
- I remember, Father.
- Play us something we know.
- Oh, please, Father.
- Please.
Well.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- What?
To bring along my harmonica.
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Every morning ♪
♪ You greet me ♪
♪ Small and white ♪
♪ Clean and bright ♪
♪ You look happy ♪
♪ To meet me ♪
♪ Blossom of snow ♪
♪ May you bloom and grow ♪
♪ Bloom and grow ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Bless my homeland ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Edelweiss ♪
[ Together ]
♪ Every morning you greet me ♪
♪ Small and white ♪
♪ Clean and bright ♪
[ Together ]
♪ You look happy to meet me ♪
♪ Blossom of snow ♪
♪ May you bloom and grow ♪
♪ Bloom and grow ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Bless my homeland ♪
♪ Forever ♪♪
Anytime you say the word, Georg,
you can be part of my new act-
- [ Chuckles ]
- The Von Trapp Family Singers.
I have a wonderful idea, Georg.
Let's really fill this house with music.
You must give a grand and glorious party
for me while I'm here.
- A party?
- [ Children ] Please, Father! Please!
I think it's high time I met all your friends
here in Salzburg and they met me.
- Don't you agree?
- I see what you mean.
- [ Children ] Oh, please, Father!
- It’s time to go to bed.
Come, now, say good night.
- [ Louisa ] Good night, Father.
- [ Gretl ] Good night, Father.
- [ Baroness ] Good night.
- [ Von Trapp ] Good night.
Good night, Baroness Schraeder. Good night, Father.
[ Marta ]
Good night, Father.
Good night.
[ Friedrich ]
Good night, Uncle Max.
It'll be my first party, Father!
- Captain.
- Evening, Herr Zeller.
Baroness Schraeder. Ηerr Zeller.
- Good evening, Ηerr Zeller.
- Baroness.
- How do you do?
- Baroness Schraeder.
Good evening.
- The women look so beautiful.
- I think they look ugly.
You just say that because you're scared of them.
Silly, only grown-up men are scared of women.
I think the men look beautiful.
Ηow would you know?
- Liesl, who are you dancing with?
- Nobody.
[ Brigitta ]
Oh, yes, you are.
- May I have this dance?
- I'd be delighted, young man.
Why didn't you children tell me you could dance?
We were afraid you'd make us all dance together.
The Von Trapp Family Dancers.
♪♪ [ Orchestra: Waltz ]
[ Gretl ]
What's that they're playing?
It’s the ländler. It’s an Austrian folk dance.
- Show me.
- Kurt, I haven't danced that since I was a little girl.
Oh, you remember. Please?
- Well-
- Please.
All right. Come on over here.
- Now you bow, and I curtsy.
- Like this?
Fine. Now we go for a little walk. This way.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
One, two, three. Step together.
Now, step, hop. Step, hop.
Now, turn under.
Not quite. This way. Ηop, step, hop.
And under.
- Kurt, we'll have to practice.
- Um, do allow me, will you?
[ Kurt ]
Mm-hmm.
[ Maria ]
Ladies and gentlemen...
the children of Captain von Trapp
wish to say good night to you.
♪ There's a sad sort of clanging
from the clock in the hall ♪
♪ And the bells in the steeple too ♪
♪ And up in the nursery an absurd little bird ♪
♪ Is popping out to say cuckoo ♪
♪ Cuckoo, cuckoo ♪
- ♪ Regretfully they tell us ♪
- ♪ Cuckoo ♪
- ♪ But firmly they compel us ♪
- ♪ To say good-bye ♪
- ♪ Cuckoo ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ So long, farewell, auf Wiedersehen, good night ♪
♪ I hate to go and leave this pretty sight ♪
♪ So long, farewell, auf Wiedersehen, adieu ♪
♪ Adieu, adieu to you and you and you ♪
♪ So long, farewell, au revoir, auf Wiedersehen ♪
♪ I'd like to stay and taste my first champagne ♪
- Yes?
- No.
[ Laughing ]
♪ So long, farewell ♪
♪ Auf Wiedersehen, good-bye ♪
♪ I leave and heave a sigh and say good-bye ♪
♪ Good-bye ♪
♪ I'm glad to go ♪
♪ I cannot tell a lie ♪
♪ I flit, I float ♪
♪ I fleetly flee, I fly ♪
♪ The sun ♪
♪ Has gone to bed ♪
♪ And so must I ♪
♪ So long ♪
♪ Farewell ♪
♪ Auf Wiedersehen ♪
♪ Good-bye ♪
♪ Good-bye ♪♪
I wonder what grass tastes like.
I feel awful.
[ Brigitta ]
When Fraülein Maria wanted to feel better...
- she used to sing that song, remember?
- Yes.
Let's try it.
♪ Raindrops on roses and whiskers on kittens ♪
♪ Bright copper kettles and warm woolen mittens ♪
♪ Brown paper packages tied up with strings ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
Why don't I feel better?
♪ Girls in white dresses with blue satin sashes ♪
[ Maria's Voice Joins In ]
♪ Snowflakes that stay on my nose and eyelashes ♪
- ♪ Silver white winters ♪
- [ Kurt ] Fraülein Maria, she's back!
♪ That melt into springs ♪
♪ These are a few of my favorite things ♪
♪ When the dog bites ♪
- ♪ When the bee stings ♪
- [ Friedrich ] Fraülein Maria!
♪ When I'm feeling sad ♪
♪ I simply remember my favorite things ♪
♪ And then I don't feel ♪
♪ So bad ♪♪
- Oh, children, I'm so glad to see you!
- We missed you!
Oh, I missed you. Kurt, how are you?
Ηungry.
- Gretl, what happened to your finger?
- It got caught.
- Caught in what?
- Friedrich's teeth.
- Liesl, you all right?
- Just fair.
Many telegrams been delivered here lately?
None at all, fraülein, but I'm learning to accept it.
- I'll be glad when school begins.
- Oh, Liesl.
You can't use school to escape your problems.
You have to face them.
Oh, I have so much to tell you all.
- We have things to tell you too.
- I'm sure you do.
[ Tolling Continues ]
♪♪ [ Organ ]
♪♪ [ Organ Continues ]
[ Nuns ]
♪ How do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
♪ How do you catch a cloud and pin it down ♪
♪ Ηow do you find a word that means Maria ♪
♪ A flibbertigibbet, a will-o'-the-wisp ♪
♪ A clown ♪
♪ Many a thing you know you'd like to tell her ♪
♪ Many a thing she ought to understand ♪
♪ But how do you make her stay
and listen to all you say ♪
♪ How do you keep a wave upon the sand ♪
♪ Oh, how do you solve a problem like Maria ♪
♪ How do you hold a moonbeam in your hand ♪♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ Sew, a needle pulling thread ♪
- ♪ A needle pulling thread ♪
- ♪ La, a note to follow sew ♪
- ♪ A note to follow sew ♪
- ♪ Tea, a drink with jam and bread ♪
- ♪ A drink with jam and bread ♪
- [ Children ] ♪ A drink with jam and bread ♪
[ Maria, Children ]
♪ Jam and bread, with jam and bread ♪
♪ Tea with jam and bread ♪
♪ Tea with jam and bread
Jam and bread, jam and bread ♪
- ♪ Tea with jam, jam and bread ♪
- ♪ Jam and bread ♪
♪ Tea with jam, jam and bread ♪
- [ Maria ] ♪ With jam ♪
- [ Children ] ♪ A-B-C, A-B-C ♪
- ♪ With jam ♪
- [ Children ] ♪ Do Re Mi, Do Re Mi ♪
[ Together ]
♪ Tea with jam and bread ♪
♪ With jam and bread, with jam, with jam ♪
♪ And bread ♪♪
[ Applauding ]
My fellow Austrians...
I shall not be seeing you again,
perhaps for a very long time.
I would like to sing for you now...
a love song.
I know you share this love.
I pray that you will never let it die.
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Every morning you greet me ♪
♪ Small and white ♪
♪ Clean and bright ♪
♪ You look happy to meet me ♪
♪ Blossom of snow ♪
♪ May you bloom and grow ♪
♪ Bloom and grow forever ♪
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Bless my homeland forever ♪
♪ Edel- ♪
♪ Small and white ♪
[ Children Join In ]
♪ Clean and bright ♪
♪ You look happy to meet me ♪
[ Audience Joins In ]
♪ Blossom of snow ♪
♪ May you bloom and grow ♪
♪ Bloom and grow forever ♪
♪ Edelweiss ♪
♪ Bless my homeland ♪
♪ Forever ♪♪
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, thank you.
The festival competition has come to its conclusion...
except, of course, we don't know yet
what that conclusion will be.
And while the judges are arriving at their decision...
I have been given permission to offer you an encore.
[ Applause ]
♪ There's a sad sort of clanging
from the clock in the hall ♪
♪ And the bells in the steeple too ♪
♪ And up in the nursery ♪
♪ An absurd little bird ♪
♪ Is popping out to say cuckoo ♪
♪ Cuckoo, cuckoo ♪
- ♪ Regretfully they tell us, but firmly they compel us ♪
- ♪ Cuckoo, cuckoo ♪
♪ To say good-bye ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ So long, farewell, auf Wiedersehen, good night ♪
♪ We hate to go and miss this pretty sight ♪
♪ So long, farewell, auf Wiedersehen, adieu ♪
♪ Adieu, adieu to you and you and you ♪
♪ So long, farewell, auf Wiedersehen, good-bye ♪
♪ We flit, we float, we fleetly flee, we fly ♪
♪ The sun has gone to bed and so must I ♪
♪ Good-bye ♪
[ Von Trapp ]
♪ Good-bye ♪♪
[ Applauding ]
[ Chorus ]
♪ A dream that will need ♪
♪ All the love you can give ♪
♪ Every day of your life ♪
♪ For as long as you live ♪
♪ Climb every mountain ♪
♪ Ford every stream ♪
♪ Follow every rainbow ♪
♪ Till you find ♪
♪ Your ♪
♪ Dream ♪♪