We lost 300 ryo, thanks
to your meddling.
We won't go back empty-handed.
If your hands are so
empty, will you hold this?
Is it true they hired you
for only twenty ryo?
Yes.
The sword we stole was a treasure
given to them by the Shogun.
And they'll only pay
twenty to get it back?
Ridiculous!
They're a poor, small clan.
Trying to swindle 300 ryo for
a sword is asking too much.
Shut up! Damn you!
Looks like a nasty
storm's brewing...
Can't waste my time here!
Ninja Scroll
Oh, I'm sorry for you.
That was one hell of a storm!
That's right! My roof got blown
off and scared my wife so bad...
...that she went into labor.
It was really something.
That's your seventh kid, right?
Nope, the ninth.
Whoa! You must really
love your wife!
Isn't that Sakichi's daughter
from Shimoda Village?
What's with her?
What's wrong?!
All... dead...
Everybody's dead.
Dead?!
Plague... Plague did it...
My god !
This area's off limits!
No one goes through!
This road's closed until
the epidemic is over.
Epidemic?! The hell with that!
What is it?
Sir, my scout saw a
strange group of men
ride toward Shimoda
Village late last night.
It might have something
to do with this
epidemic so I came to
tell you, Chamberlain.
Meaning what? That they spread a plague
as they passed through the village?
Ridiculous! Why
would they do that?
Something's fishy.
Let it alone.
On second thought, we can't.
This is the order to
all of you Koga ninja.
Go to Shimoda Village and
find what really happened.
Sir!
One more thing. If any of
your people get infected...
Understood, sir.
The first group will follow the
Shirakawa River from the north.
The second will cross
Taro Pass from the west.
You'll reach Shimoda Village
in about an hour. Understand?
Hikoza saw them. There were only eight.
No match for us.
Our real enemy is this epidemic.
True.
Kagero...
You intend to leave
me behind, Hanza?
You have your own
duties, don't you?
Poison tasting is very important.
Don't forget that.
While our lord is away from his
domain, the work isn't necessary.
Until he returns...
I am one of the Koga ninja!
I cannot take you.
You could all be
killed out there.
How can I just sit and
wait here alone?!
Kagero's gotten even
more beautiful.
All the more reason to pity her.
It's her destiny.
She must hate it.
Enough. Where are
Hikoza and the others?
They were right behind us.
I'll have a look.
Hey! What are you doing?
What the...?!
There!
Shit!
Who was that freak?
Forget it. I don't want
to see him again, anyway.
I am
Kagero of the Koga ninja.
Jubei. Kibagami Jubei.
The town of Kakio is to the west.
Our paths part here.
Oh, hi...
I know the way now, so...
Ow...
Okay, I got it. Are we done now?
There's no reason we
should kill each other.
If you're not going to end this...
I will!
Like hell!
Strange skill you have. But
it can't hurt my body.
Seems that way.
What's wrong, Monster? Your
skin's starting to crumble!
Die!
Splendid !
Your sword flew swift
as the wind itself and
slashed your enemy like
a cyclone's touch.
He was no match for you.
Why don't you join me?
Your skills will be of great help
for me to fight the likes of him.
You're joking. Who'd want to
fight a monster like him again?
You'll have to. They
won't leave you alone.
You just killed one of the
Eight Devils of Kimon.
You didn't beat him
by yourself, though.
That Koga ninja woman...
Interesting technique she uses.
Lord Genma. All is
proceeding as planned.
It arrives from the Shogun of the
Dark by six tomorrow evening.
Very well. Write
to him in return.
"We return in three days. There's
nothing to worry about."
At once.
Where are you headed?
No place in particular. You?
I'm looking for somebody, and you
look exactly like him, so...
Strangers can look alike. I'm
Kibagami Jubei, a wanderer...
It was most certainly your face.
Tessai was able to make
an impression of it.
Just leave me the hell alone!
A cast-off skin.
She shed it like a
snake and escaped.
A gang of freaks, one and all.
You've no obligation. I just
didn't want you to die yet.
Who are these Eight
Devils of Kimon?
A group of ninja who work
for the Shogun of the Dark.
You know of the
Shogun of the Dark?
He wants to rebuild the Toyotomi
clan, the former rulers of Japan.
He has 16 lords behind him and is
trying to expand his influence.
The most dangerous enemy
of the Tokugawa Shogunate.
His power is supported in the
shadows by the Eight Devils.
What are they up to
here in Mochizuki?
That's what I came here to find out.
It's a tough job.
Why don't you work for
me, for 100 ryo?
A Tokugawa spy wants
to hire a ninja?
I'm afraid I have no choice.
It's an emergency.
Only I managed to make
it here to Mochizuki.
The Eight Devils killed everyone
else in my party on our way here.
I need your help by all means!
You'll never get away from them.
You'll have to fight
them sooner or later.
Join me. You can kill two
birds with one stone, right?
I don't think so. Now why don't
you just leave me alone?
I see. Too bad.
Such a pity...
You'll lose your precious life.
You're stubborn.
No, what I speak of is literally of
life or death importance to you.
You see, that shuriken
was poisoned.
It won't kill you instantly,
but in a day and a
night, when it starts to
work, nothing can stop it.
Unless you get the antidote.
And only I know what it is.
Work for me and I'll tell
you the antidote along
with the hundred ryo
when the job is done.
You're bluffing.
I speak the truth.
Tell me now. What's
the antidote?
Not until you work for me. Kill
me and you've killed yourself!
Now you'll need the
antidote for yourself.
Poor boy... You've
so much to learn.
That isn't the one that hit you.
I threw THAT one away.
Shit!
Kibagami Jubei... You've lost...
amateur!
My name is Dakuan.
How do you do?
So, Benisato...
This man, Kibagami Jubei, is a
remnant of the Shogunate's spies?
Possibly.
Why didn't you kill him?
Someone interfered.
No excuses!
If he's a government spy,
he'll show up here soon.
Be sure to kill him this time.
I don't need your
advice to do that.
Jubei...
There's something
I've been wondering.
Are you, by chance, the
ninja who killed the chief
retainers of the Yamashiro
clan five years ago?
He was supposedly a master
swordsman, like you.
The retainers had
gorged themselves with
gold they secretly dug
out of a hidden mine.
The ninja must have killed
them by order of the lord
who wanted to report the
mine to the government.
Because if the government found
the hidden gold mine first...
the lord would have
lost his fief.
But does that ninja know that after
the retainers were killed...
the government received
no report about the mine?
Why?
If a government spy like you knows all
that, then why don't you do something?
No... Even the government can't
move without definite evidence.
Our spies tried many
times to infiltrate the
clan to find evidence,
but none returned alive.
The Shogun of the Dark...
He stopped them by
using the Kimon ninja.
Why is the Shogun of the Dark
helping the Yamashiro clan?
Simple. He wants the
gold mine for himself.
Do you know how he found the
mine before the government?
Somebody gave him
the information.
Somebody who was the leader of
the ninja of the Yamashiro clan.
Himuro... Genma?!
Precisely.
I doubt that. He isn't
in this world anymore.
No, he's still very much alive.
And you'll see him soon.
Himuro Genma is the boss
of the Kimon monsters.
Shh! Not so loud !
You can't trick me
the same way again!
Don't be hasty. You'll
soon know the truth.
But you must admit that you
and he share a strange fate.
Stop! You'd kill
your own friend?!
The lord orders it!
As did our leader!
It's a trick!
Now that we know the
traitors' secret they want
to get rid of us by making
us kill each other.
This is a trap for all of us.
Shinkuro, believe me!
Jubei... Forgive me.
Shinkuro!
His word...
...is law!
I avenged Shinkuro and the others myself.
Genma can't be alive.
We're getting close. This place
is thick with ghosts and blood.
Beyond lies Hell itself.
Heaven must have sent
this mist to help us.
Hey!
Double damned mist!
How could he have
dodged Shijima's claw?
Who are you?
I heard a voice
chanting the sutra.
I was praying for
the dead villagers.
Don't you know an epidemic
plagues this village?
Poor soul! You'll never
leave this village alive.
Here now, let us go to the
land of Buddha together.
Have you seen a
traveling monk here?
He'll meet Buddha soon enough.
I'll send him there.
Such a benevolent nun...
Shit! Another cast-off skin!
Gone... He uses a
strange technique...
As do you. Very strange indeed !
Answer me. Are there any others
with you besides the monk?
Of course. And not
just ten or twenty.
You can send a snake for
each and it won't be enough.
Liar!
All right! I'll
tell you the truth.
There's two. One's the traveling monk.
The other...
...is right behind you.
Lose the snakes. Down
to the last one!
You'll be dead soon.
Get rid of them!
Now it's your turn to answer.
What are you doing in this village?
Talk!
Twice failed. Unforgivable.
I cast another line onto your
neck, but you didn't notice.
In the end, just a
foolish amateur.
Idiot! There's still time
to suck the poison out!
Poison doesn't work on me.
My body's immune to it.
I think I've cleared
my debt to you.
Yes. You saved me.
Your name's Kagero, right?
What are you going to do now?
That's none of your concern.
If it isn't, then what the
hell am I doing here?!
I have to discover their plan.
By yourself? Impossible!
They're too strong.
Think this over.
Stay out of my way.
I've no reason to
take orders from you.
Hold a moment, Kunoichi of Koga.
My name is Dakuan. Why
don't you join me?
This man is my
trustworthy assistant.
I wasn't planning on
helping a government spy.
Oh, quit complaining !
What do you say, woman?
Our aims may differ, but we
three share a common enemy.
And three is mightier than one.
And I happen to have some
information you don't know.
Such as who is giving
them their orders.
I'll tell you on the way.
I need no friends.
But I may need your information.
Very well.
My, she's a lovely, sexy
little thing, isn't she!
What's running through that
twisted skull of yours?
Well now, that Kunoichi
could prove very useful.
She has a technique to poison
the man she sleeps with.
The big guy you killed had
been poisoned by her.
Your skill is as
marvelous as ever.
No... He was able to kill a
mighty ninja like Tessai.
Don't be off guard. It's
possible he got away.
The four of you
will check it out.
You're a cautious one, Yurimaru.
We have an important mission.
We take every precaution.
I know, I know. Don't worry.
Only things he killed
were the fish.
Good. Otherwise we
wouldn't get our chance.
It's getting quite
interesting, isn't it?
How is it? Just as we thought?
They poisoned the wells
and killed the villagers.
And then blamed it on plague.
A trick to keep the
villagers away.
They're planning something...
quite extraordinary.
I'd like to know what it is.
That's fine, just don't get
yourself involved too deeply.
It could prove fatal.
I see. Guide the others.
Run for it!
We can't outrun them.
Kagero...
So, the pollen is mixed
with a sleeping potion.
But how long will
it hold them back?
Why, you!
Girl!
You have to hold them off
till Jubei kills him!
Do whatever it takes!
Call off your bees!
I'm afraid you must
beat me first.
You don't know anything, do you?
Do you think I ran in
here to escape you?
No, I don't.
I have lots of questions for
you, but no time to ask them.
No, just one thing. Tell
me, is Himuro Genma alive?
So what if he is?
I ask because I sent
him to Hell before.
Is that so? Then I'll
have to be careful.
Unlike Genma, I don't have the
technique to reincarnate myself.
Reincarnation?
Fool! You've damaged the hive!
The second you come up for
air is the second you die!
He's mine! Keep
your hands off him!
What about the
Kunoichi and the monk?
My bees should finish
them off soon.
How far is he trying to run?
What a poor loser!
Do you think he's fallen
victim to the throat needle?
No... The bees in the hive are
trying to escape the water.
Desperately stinging his body as
they do so... Mushizo's lost.
Took his time about it, but
he finally killed him.
Reincarnation? Did he mean Himuro
Genma's come back to life?
Impossible!
Reincarnation? I've heard
about the technique.
You must control your flesh and
blood down to the tiniest bones.
If your limbs or even your head were
cut off, you'd be able to rejoin them.
Reincarnation... That's a
technique of immortality.
It can never be achieved
by a human being.
Well, well... That's
a hell of a trick!
Anyway, the Kimon monsters
are now all after you.
That means I can move easily.
If you're lucky,
we'll meet again.
Why did you join him?
He hired me... For 100 ryo.
You're a mercenary ninja? One
who'd do anything for money?
You could say that.
But he suckered me into it.
Trapped me.
I'll die of his
poison in half a day.
He promised me an antidote
along with the gold.
That's why I work for him.
I can't back out now.
You'd better run for it while
I divert their attention.
I can't do that. I'd
owe you another debt.
Forget about any debts.
And I told you I don't have
to take orders from you.
Besides, I'm ready
to die any moment.
Relax. Stop pretending
you're so tough.
What?!
It's this humid weather!
I wish a storm would come and
cool off that hot head of yours.
You're in no position
to worry about me.
Storm...
They came on the night
of that big storm...
Hey, where can I get a
good look at this area?
How about there?
Nothing.
Keep looking !
Hanza...
Wait!
Hanza!
There's a cliff in front of you!
Stop!
Damn!
Gotcha!
Shit!
Fool! They got you so soon?
We still had a lot to do.
The scent of blasted flesh,
grilled to perfection...
Such a lovely smell.
Don't... move...
That's enough. Let me go.
It's my fault I fell
for their trap.
Shut up! Don't talk!
Let go of me! I don't
want your help.
Shut up!
Go on, grab it!
I am Utsutsu Mujuro. I've been
longing to challenge you.
He's here for me. Stay here.
You lured me here because I'm blind?
Is that your plan?
If you want to kill me,
then don't make a sound.
That's impossible. But maybe I can
turn your skill to my advantage.
I told you to stay back!
Your sight is your weakness.
Outta the way!
Impossible...
The cargo from the ship that ran
aground in the storm two days ago.
That's what they're after.
They butchered the villagers
like animals for it.
Where does this road lead?
Chamberlain!
Lord Hyobu, is it true?
That the Koga ninja who went to investigate
Shimoda Village were wiped out?
Exactly.
But how?! This is an emergency.
I'll take my men to the
village immediately.
No!
If this is serious
enough to jeopardize the
safety of our clan, we
must move very carefully.
That's how small clans
like ours survive.
But...
The Kunoichi who survived is
continuing the investigation.
Wait for her report.
Those wheel tracks lead
to Kashima Harbor.
They're probably going to
transport the cargo out by boat.
If I don't stop them...
those dead villagers and the Koga
ninja will never rest in peace.
Listen well, you who labor
for the Shogun of the Dark.
This mission could very
well decide our fate!
This ship will reach
Mochizuki in a few hours.
We must retrieve the
cargo at any cost!
Understood? At any cost!
The towns must have cleared out
out of fear of the epidemic.
One horse was enough to
scare them all away.
So, you're still alive.
I've been worried.
It's nice to see you, too.
They're waiting for a boat
to transport the cargo.
Did you check what the cargo is?
No, I couldn't reach it. But
I can guess what it is.
Actually, I guessed before
I came to Mochizuki.
What?!
You haven't figured it out?
It's something that has
to do with your past.
It's gold, boy.
Gold produced from that
secret Yamashiro mine.
The ship ran aground
during the storm...
Probably on its way to the Shogun
of the Dark with caskets of gold.
Gold that's probably been
hidden for the last five years.
If it reaches his hands,
he'll be powerful enough to
topple the Tokugawa government...
...and plunge the country
into another civil war.
We have to stop it at any cost!
Dakuan, you've got a tail.
What?!
Kunoichi, what are you doing?!
I'm calling a Koga ninja
bird that's in this village.
Calling a bird? What for?
It'll carry my message to
the castle chamberlain.
I've discovered
what they're after.
Ln two hours, his army
will surround the town.
It's not as easy as you think.
The Mochizuki clan will probably
ignore this whole thing.
Why?!
The future of the
clan is at stake.
This is a power struggle between the
Tokugawa and the Shogun of the Dark.
If a small clan like the Mochizuki
got involved, it'd be smashed !
See nothing, hear nothing. That's
the best course for the clan.
We'll find out soon whether or
not the Mochizuki will move.
Shit!
Uh-oh!
Kunoichi in Custody
Kunoichi in Custody It must have
happened when I went off for a moment.
Kunoichi in Custody
She's most likely dead.
Well, we've got work to do.
We'll get no help from
the Mochizuki clan.
Don't fall for their trap.
Wait!
What if their ship comes
while you're at it?
Let her alone! A dead Kunoichi
isn't that important!
Not important compared
to the great mission?
You're as much of a
monster as they are!
Fool! When you fight monsters, you
become one yourself or you can't win!
You damn fool boy! Go ahead !
GO TO HELL!
Damn you... !
Are you all right?
Kagero!
You're hard to kill, but...
Woman, release his pain.
Kibagami Jubei?
Yes. But we've already
killed them all.
Idiot! They still live.
I'll kill him, for sure!
Stay where you are. Lure
them there and kill them.
Understand?
Yes.
Never would I have
imagined to see him here.
I look forward to seeing
you again, Jubei.
Genma!
I'm sorry.
Forget it. I take it the castle
retainers haven't taken any action?
It's been two hours.
I see.
Why... You knew it was a trap,
but you came to help me.
It was stupid. Why
risk your life for me?
Because I can't just
toss aside my comrade.
Comrade?
Yes. We've saved each other
over and over since yesterday.
You're a precious friend to me.
Stay!
The Mochizuki clan is
staying out of this one.
Your mission is over.
No, it isn't. I'm
still in debt to you.
You can pay it back later.
Not if you're dead !
I'll repay it here!
What are you doing?
The old man told me how
to counteract the poison.
"Kill poison with poison."
He said if you make love to a
poison-taster like me, you'll be cured.
Take me...
We've been waiting ! Load
the ship immediately!
You! Well, I warned
you, didn't I?
We've lost. We'll never
beat that many men.
I don't intend to let them go.
We'll make our stand soon.
What are you planning?
When they finish
loading the gold...
...go to the tower
and ring the bell.
While they're distracted,
I'll sneak onboard the ship.
When we're out at sea,
we won't need any storm.
I'll sink it myself.
Very well.
By the way, did you make
love to that Kunoichi?
None of your damn business!
Now get going !
Genma... Where are you?
When I die, I'll take
you to hell with me!
The Mochizuki clan?! They're
moving against them!
Ah, Kunoichi! You've
done a fine job.
Hurry, before they get away!
Where are the others?
Don't worry. They've got
this place surrounded.
Then hurry!
Jubei...
Kagero!
Stop! It's a trap!
Fool! Sakaki Hyobu
died two days ago.
I killed him personally.
Genma!
Sir, please get aboard
the ship quickly.
The retainers of the Shogun
of the Dark are waiting.
Leave Jubei to me. Upon my
honor, I will not fail.
Please grant me this one wish.
Very well then. Go.
Stay out of this. Don't shame me
any more than you already have.
So, you are Genma?
The Mochizuki clan
suspects nothing, correct?
Yes. All is well.
You've done a splendid job. I
admire you Devils of Kimon.
The Shogun of the
Dark will be pleased.
Writhe in pain before you die.
Yurimaru seems to have
suffered some ill fortune!
How careless of him to
have fallen into my trap.
It was your own fault, Yurimaru.
Let's go.
Kagero!
Hang on! Kagero!
Jubei...
I told you not to come.
I wanted... to apologize...
It was the first time...
You didn't treat me like
some poison-taster...
...but like a normal woman.
Jubei... I'm glad...
I met you...
Genma, with the gold's help our
dream will soon be reality.
"Our" dream?
Our great dream to topple the Shogunate
and restore the reign of the Toyotomi.
You don't understand...
How we, the former retainers
of Toyotomi, have suffered.
Now it'll be the Tokugawa who
suffer the agony and torment.
We'll use the gold to buy advanced weapons
from Spain and defeat the Tokugawa.
That is the dream of all of us who
work for the Shogun of the Dark.
Nonsense.
What did you say?!
I said nonsense.
Hold your tongue!
You're a mere ninja!
My dream is different.
The gold isn't going to
the Shogun of the Dark.
What?!
We, the Devils of Kimon,
will take the gold.
You impudent... !
I'll use it to organize the most
powerful army of ninja ever.
And we'll rule the country with
terror and power from the shadows.
Anyone who opposes me,
Tokugawa or Toyotomi...
...even the Shogun of the
Dark himself, shall die.
Meaning the true Shogun of the Dark...
will be me.
Well now, you're here! I was
just wishing you'd come.
I'm glad to hear that.
Of course.
Without your help, sinking a big
ship like this would be impossible!
Pathetic old fool!
Over here.
What's wrong?
Fire in the hold !
We're gonna sink!
Idiot! Put out the fire!
Impossible! It's a sea of flame!
Put it out! Fight it!
Move it! Move it!
Forget it! Run!
Master Genma!
Pass this message to everyone:
"Abandon ship and hide yourselves.
I'll call for you someday."
Go.
Genma!
I see you brought back some
devils from your trip to Hell.
Kibagami Jubei...
I should've finished
you with my own hands.
Stop your whining.
It's too late.
You want to avenge
the Kunoichi Kagero?
She was trash in comparison
to what I've lost.
You alone I can't forgive!
I won't kill you yet. Not
before I make you suffer.
I'll make you pay for
smashing my dream.
Your dream? That you were going to
be the true Shogun of the Dark?
Don't make me laugh.
If you became shogun, you'd
make this a world of devils.
If you enjoy their company so much...
then go back to hell!
I'll kill you!
No one can kill me.
You of all people
should know by now...
I am immortal.
Is that so?
If you keep coming
back to life...
...then I'll kill you as
many times as it takes!
You fool!
Genma! HERE YOU DIE!
Jubei!
You seem to be rid of the
poison, thanks to Kagero.
The combination of a poison-tasting
Kunoichi and a talented lone wolf
worked out even better
than I had planned.
Go away.
By the way, I'm sorry about losing Kagero.
A real pity, that!
But for a scant few
moments, she was able to
be an ordinary girl and
make love with you.
Was that part of your plan, too?
Exactly. To read and control peoples'
hearts is the true secret of the ninja.
Still, only true sincerity
can move the human heart.
A twisted old bastard
like me couldn't do it.
You're a hell of a guy.
I really admire you.
As promised, I'll be waiting
in Edo with your 100 ryo.
Come and get it, if
you're still alive.
That makes us even. Now
never cross my path again.
You've beaten me. I thought I'd
shut your mouth in Edo, but...
Still, in your condition you likely
won't even make it to the shore.
Everything will end
just as I planned.