We lost 300 ryo, thanks
to your meddling.
We won't go back empty-handed.
If your hands are so
empty, will you hold this?
Is it true they hired you
for only twenty ryo?
Yes.
The sword we stole was a treasure
given to them by the Shogun.
And they'll only pay
twenty to get it back?
Ridiculous!
They're a poor, small clan.
Trying to swindle 300 ryo for
a sword is asking too much.
Shut up! Damn you!
Looks like a nasty
storm's brewing...
Can't waste my time here!
Ninja Scroll
I won't kill you yet. Not
before I make you suffer.
I'll make you pay for
smashing my dream.
Your dream? That you were going to
be the true Shogun of the Dark?
Don't make me laugh.
If you became shogun, you'd
make this a world of devils.
If you enjoy their company so much...
then go back to hell!
I'll kill you!
No one can kill me.
You fool!
Genma! HERE YOU DIE!