Tell him to send it over
to the cargo shed.
It's on its way.
Ray.
Ferrier. Whoa.
I need you back in four instead of 12.
I got half of Korea coming in at noon.
No, no, no, I can't.
I'm on a 12-hour blow. Call Tedesco.
Come on. Tedesco can't move
40 containers in an hour.
I gotta have somebody
who can do double picks.
I wish I could help you, Sal.
It's the goddamn union regulations.
Come on.
I'm in a position here, Ray.
You remember
the union regulations, Sal.
You know what your problem is?
I can think of a couple women
who'd be happy to tell you.
Three and two...
Steven, look at this.
- What's up?
- Check it out!
You ever see something like that?
Springtime, maybe.
Not this time of year.
Come on, we can see better
from the back yard.
You gotta come see this!
- That is so weird.
- What?
The wind is blowing
toward the storm.
That is weird.
Hey, watch it!
Rachel,
you wanna see something cool?
It's okay.
- I wanna go inside.
- It's okay.
I wanna go inside.
Okay, you go ahead.
That's enough weather for me.
Don't wanna go by myself.
It's kind of fun, isn't it?
- No.
- Come on, like the Fourth of July.
- No, it's not.
- O, say can...
It's okay. You're fine.
- It hit right behind our house.
- Yeah, well, it's...
It's not gonna hit there again, okay,
because lightning doesn't strike
twice in the same place. Oh, shit!
Where's Robbie?
I don't know.
Is Robbie okay?
Are you okay?
Where's the thunder?
Why won't it stop?
Is it over?
Where are you going?
Just... I'm just checking things out.
Just wait... Wait there.
- Are we gonna be okay?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No, I meant, I just... Just...
Rachel, please.
Just stop asking so many questions.
Just wait here.
Turn everything off.
Everything is off.
I can't get one freaking thing
to turn on.
You believe this, Ray?
Every single car.
Oh, Jesus. Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
- The car just stopped, and...
- You're okay?
- Are you okay? You all right?
- The lightning started to hit.
- And me and this other guy...
- Where the hell did you go?
- Over on Lincoln Avenue.
- Lincoln Avenue?
- By the church.
- You saw the lightning?
Yeah, 26 times we counted,
over and over again.
The lightning started to hit.
It opened up this hole or something...
- Twenty-six times?
- Yeah.
- You're okay?
Good. All right, well,
your sister is in the house,
and I want you to go in that house
and I want you to stay with her, okay?
The next time you take my car with
no driver's license and no permission,
I call the cops.
You better be there when I get back.
- Yeah.
- Robbie.
Manny, Manny.
Manny, what is it, dead?
All of them. Everything.
Look at this.
- The starter's fried.
- Lightning hit it?
Not even close.
I thought if I changed it...
- Any idea what's going on?
- I'm on my way to find out.
Try changing the solenoid.
It's probably fried.
Right, that's what I said.
I told you that. The solenoid.
Hey, they're saying all the
lightning struck down by the church.
What the hell is going on
around here?
- Let us through.
- Hey.
- Let us through here.
I never seen anything like this before.
That many strikes of lightning
in one spot?
- Is this the only place?
- Come on, put that down.
- You wanna step back, please?
- Step back.
- You're gonna fall in.
- Get back.
Back up, people.
People, back up back there.
Move back. Everybody back up.
Move back.
- Is it hot?
- Back up.
- No.
- It's freezing.
- What is that?
Oh, wait. Move. You feel that?
- I feel that.
- Hey, Bobby, come check this out.
- You feel that?
- Feel that?
- Yeah, I feel that.
- What is it, the subway?
- There's no subway here.
- F train, maybe?
That can't be the water main.
There's nothing else down there.
- Water main doesn't run through here.
- Feel that?
There's something down there
and it's moving.
Everybody move back.
Whoa. Back it up. Come on.
Let's go.
Come on, folks. Back up.
Get back.
Help me out here. Get back.
- Go! Move!
- Everybody get out of the way!
Everyone back up!
Everyone clear the intersection!
Get out of the way! Back up!
Back up! Get out of the way!
- Forget it! Get back!
- Get the hell out of the street!
Move away!
Come on, we gotta
clear this area now!
That's my car!
Go, go.
Get the hell out of here!
Oh, my God!
Come on, people! Let's go!
Come on, back up!
Please! Move back!
Watch it!
Oh, my God.
Ray, no. Stay, man.
Just stay.
- Just stay back here. Stay back!
- Wow.
Come on.
I don't think it's a fire.
- See? That looks like smoke to me.
- What's happening?
I can't tell you now.
We've only got about another minute.
Please.
- Just keep it down.
- Ray, I'm standing right beside you.
Can you please answer me?
Just get in the front seat, Robbie.
- Whose car is this?
- Just get in.
Whose car is this?
Hey. Hey, Ray.
You were absolutely right.
That is exact...
I had to change the solen...
Ray? Hey.
Hey, Ray? Ray.
All right, get out of the truck. I'm not
kidding now. Get out of the car, Ray.
I'm not gonna get in.
I'm not getting in.
- Manny, get in with us.
- I'm not gonna get in trouble.
- Look, I'm not fooling around...
- Close the door, Robbie. Close it.
Ray, bring the car back, Ray.
It's not my car.
Get down!
Get down, get down! Get down!
- Just get down. Get down! Get down!
- Holy shit!
I wanna know everything you know.
This...
This machine,
it crawled out of the ground,
started torching everything.
It was killing everybody.
That machine,
it was already buried.
Maybe it...
...it came down in the lightning storm.
- They came down in a lightning storm.
- What do you mean, came down?
- You said it was buried.
- No, the machine I'm talking about
was buried, but what
came down in the lightning storm,
what operates it,
that's the... You know.
- The what?
- That's...
Why aren't there any helicopters
or airplanes?
Robbie, get the door.
Mom!
- Mom!
Mom? Tim?
- Mom?
- Tim?!
- Tim?
Tim?
Mom?
They're gone.
Is she dead?
She's not dead. All right?
She's just not here, okay?
- They were never here.
- How do you know?
Because they're
on their way to Boston.
And so they just...
...kept on going up to Boston.
Probably at your grandma's house.
If everything's fine, why do we
have to sleep in the basement?
- We've got perfectly good beds.
- Hey, it's like a slumber party.
What are you afraid
is gonna happen?
Nice basement.
I wanna sleep in my bed.
Got back problems.
Is the lightning back?
- What's that sound?
- I've never heard that before!
Is it them? Is it them?
We gotta go.
Where do we go?!
Robbie, this is your house.
Down here.
Were you on this plane?
Are you...?
Are you a passenger?
How you doing?
Wanna help me open this?
Are you a passenger?
He's deaf.
The shell went off right beside him.
Camera on his shoulder saved his life.
You hear that, Max?
Your stupid camera
saved your stupid life.
Where were you?
Out there in the Pine Barrens.
We were attached to
a National Guard unit.
The 83rd Mechanized.
They moved on one of those things
around midnight.
They got some kind of shield
around them.
You can't see it, but everything we fire
at them detonates too early,
before we can get close enough
to cause any damage.
When they flash that thing,
everything lights up like Hiroshima.
There's more than one?
You gotta be kidding me, right?
We were feeding New York,
but New York went dark.
So we patched over to D.C.,
they went down.
L.A., Chicago, uplinked to London.
Even called the affiliates to try
to get them to catch the feed,
but nobody answers.
It's the same everywhere.
Once the Tripods start to move,
no more news comes out of that area.
You hear that?
We're getting the hell out of here.
Get in, get in, get in, get in.
Hey, were you on that plane?
That's too bad.
It would've been a really great story.
You're doing good. You're doing good.
Keep your eyes on me.
I'm going right to Boston.
- We're gonna see your mom.
- I'm not gonna look, Dad.
That's a girl. That's my girl.
Now listen.
- I want you to close your eyes, okay?
- Okay.
Got them closed? There you go.
- Keep them closed for me.
- Okay.
Robbie, get in.
Get in.
- Why aren't we on the turnpike?
- I don't want everybody
to see that we've got a working car.
We'll stay along the Hudson
till we find an open bridge or ferry,
then we're gonna cross the Hudson.
We'll take the back roads across
Connecticut, all the way to Boston.
I'll close my eyes.
Why don't you drive for a bit.
I don't have a license.
Since when has that stopped you?
Ray.
Ray! Dad!
You think you could...?
Do you think you could...?
Don't stop.
Don't take your foot off. Okay?
I got it, but keep your foot on.
Okay, I got it. I got it.
- Where is everybody going?
- I don't know, Rach.
But we do, right?
Yeah, we do.
- Be careful.
- How'd you fix this?
- How'd you fix the car?
- Please! Why won't you help us?
I'm sorry, I can't. I can't.
Please, get away from the car.
Hey! Stop the car.
- Stop the car!
- Get off the car!
You could carry 20 people in there!
- Stop the car!
- Get off the car!
Stop the car!
Are you okay?
No, wait! Wait!
No! Just wait! Okay! Wait! Stop!
- Just stop!
- Daddy!
Rachel!
Get out of there!
Robbie!
- Ray!
- Get in the car!
- Help!
- Rachel! Get out of the car!
Rachel, get...
Get out of the car.
- Get out!
- Daddy!
- Take it easy!
- Get off the car!
Get off!
Get off the car! Move!
Move!
- Where's my son?
- You don't need that, man.
- Where's my son? Robbie!
- Cool down, man.
- Put the gun down, man.
- Robbie!
Okay, now, listen.
- Put down the gun. I'm taking the car.
- My daughter's in the car.
- I'm taking the car, man.
- Please. All I want...
- Put down the goddamn gun!
- All I want is my daughter.
- I'm taking the car, man.
- Please, I just want my daughter.
Let me just take my daughter.
Can I...?
- All I want is my daughter.
- Yeah. Okay, go ahead, man.
Robbie.
Take me with you!
Have you seen this girl?
This is my daughter.
He needs his medicine.
We've got it the worst,
that's what I heard.
The U.S., mostly.
South America and Asia, some.
There's nothing going on in Europe.
Europe got the worst of it,
that's what everybody's saying.
- Completely wiped out some of it.
- I don't give a shit who it is.
I got up close to one of those things
in Stanfordville.
If they're all over the place,
we're dead.
- Looks like the power's still on here.
- Yeah.
Yeah, power's still on.
Because nothing bad's come up
from the ground.
- Hold on. Hold on, move back!
- Watch out there, lady!
I said, move back!
Unless you are O-positive
and RH-negative,
thank you very much, but we already
have more blood than we can use.
Again, if you are O-positive,
RH-negative, identify yourselves.
If you are not, thank you very much.
We already have more blood
than we can use for the transfusions.
Let's go, folks.
This way. This way.
Keep it moving.
Keep it moving. This way.
Let's go, folks. Keep it moving.
Please move forward calmly.
The boat can make more than one trip.
Take your time. Don't rush.
Ray! Ray! Ray!
- Sheryl?
- Yeah. Hey.
Oh, my gosh, is this your...?
- Are these your kids?
- Rachel.
Hi, I'm Sheryl.
This is my daughter, Nora.
- Nora. I've heard about you, Nora.
- Hi.
- This is my son, Robbie.
- Just like Dad.
- It's good to see you as well.
- Trees are funny.
We're gonna move a few cars out
of the way to make some more space.
You're gonna have to give us
a few minutes.
But don't worry,
there'll be plenty of room for everybody.
We got sick people here.
Let us on.
Cast off. Get that ramp up.
Cast off now. Get that ramp up.
Cast off.
No more people. No more people.
We're taking the ramp up.
Stay close. Stay close.
Everybody stop. Everybody stop.
- Wait, wait, wait. Just...
- Back up. Back up.
- There's room.
- Just stay back.
No more room.
There's no more room.
Just listen to me.
There's three of us.
- Five. There's only five of us.
- There's no room.
Okay, man, just don't push me.
- Sir, there's no more room.
- There's plenty of room.
- There's room for hundreds more.
- Sir...
- Everybody, wait.
- Hold on.
- You just stay with me.
- Okay.
Grab my jacket.
Everybody back up.
Back up.
I got you, Ferrier.
- Oh, Jesus.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- Okay, Jesus. Oh, my God.
Watch out.
Come on.
Oh, Ray.
Ray!
Come on. Come on.
Go. I can go with him.
Sheryl?
Go with them. Go.
- Ray.
- Sheryl?
- Everybody...
- There's room on the boat.
- Let us through, goddamn it.
- There's still room on the boat.
- She's a child.
- Robbie.
- There's room on the...
There's still room on the boat.
There's room on the boat.
- Robbie.
- Just stay with me.
Stay with me, Robbie.
Oh, my God.
Robbie!
Swim. Swim this way!
- Robbie, help me with her.
- Here, Rach.
Don't stop. Don't stop.
Don't stop.
Oh, my God.
Robbie.
Don't move. Don't move.
Now for God's sake, stay right here.
I'm coming right back.
- Robbie!
- Stop those people.
- Turn around. Turn around.
- Robbie.
Robbie.
What the hell?
Why are you doing this?
Pull back.
Five hundred meters to my 10 o'clock.
Jekyll, no effect on target.
No effect.
Roger. No effect.
Our mission, lieutenant,
is to delay their advance
till those refugees get to safety.
Now, keep firing.
You've gotta listen. Turn around!
I want you to listen to me.
Listen to me.
Go back down the hill!
All of you, just turn around!
What are you doing here
all by yourself?
Sweetie, you gotta come with us,
please.
- My dad's right there.
- Please, come.
- Please, my dad's right there.
- Listen to me...
I need to be here. I want to see this.
Wait. Wait... Just stay for Rachel.
Stay for your sister.
Please, let me go.
You need to let me go.
All right. Okay. All right.
- You're coming with us.
- Dad.
- We're going now.
- I can't.
Dad!
Dad.
Let me go! Dad!
Guide on. Guide on.
Black Six. Attack. Attack. Attack.
Stop.
- That's my dad.
- I'm her father. I'm her father.
- We're so sorry.
- We thought she was alone.
- She was standing by the tree...
- She's fine. Let's go! Let's go!
Robbie.
Robbie!
Over here.
Over here!
Hurry.
Are you all right?
Hey.
What about you, huh?
There you go.
Is that comfortable?
I need you to close
your eyes now, okay?
You need some sleep.
Dad?
He's gonna meet us.
Hey. Robbie's gonna meet us, Rach.
In Boston, at your grandma's.
What do you think
Mom's doing right this minute?
Mom?
Boston. She's waiting.
And I know she's not sleeping,
because she is so worried about you.
And she's in Grandma's kitchen,
and she's...
She's making that awful tea
she makes.
And they're all just...
They're all just counting the minutes
until they see you again.
What is this?
I won.
You won?
The walk, trot and canter.
Third place.
Peach schnapps.
Disgusting, I know it.
Found a whole case of this shit.
Thank you.
I'm sorry about your son.
We got separated. He's...
He's gonna meet us in Boston.
Did you...?
Did you lose anybody?
All of them.
Harlan Ogilvy.
Ray Ferrier.
I got water.
Food enough for weeks.
You're welcome to stay. Both of youse.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna get some sleep.
Those machines, those...
...Tripods they got?
They buried them.
Right under our feet.
Since before there...
There were even people here.
They've been planning this
for a million years.
We're beat to shit.
Please.
- My daughter...
- Think about it.
They defeated the greatest power
in the world in a couple days.
Walked right over us.
And these are only the first.
They'll keep coming.
This is not a war
any more than there's
a war between men and maggots.
This is an extermination.
Are you afraid?
Of course I am.
I been around death plenty.
I drive an ambulance in the city...
Drove an ambulance in the city.
That's all over now, huh?
You know the people
that make it, Ray?
The ones that don't flatline
before the hospital?
It's the ones
that keep their eyes open.
That keep looking at you.
Keep thinking.
They're the ones that survive.
We can't lose our heads, Ray.
Running.
That's what'll kill you.
And I'm dead set on living.
Dead set on living...
Thank you for taking us in.
Not gonna be exterminated.
It's okay. Come on.
I wanna show you something.
We're gonna fight them, Ray.
They gotta have a weakness.
Come on. Take a look.
Somehow they killed
a few of these things in Osaka.
That's what I heard.
You telling me the Japanese
can figure it out, but we can't?
We can do this, Ray.
We can do it. We can get them.
We can figure it out.
Stay right there.
I have a daughter.
Why did you bring us here?
To fight them together, Ray.
Now we'll be the ones coming up
from underground.
When the time is right...
...take them by surprise,
the way they took us.
Take them by surprise.
We're right under their feet, Ray.
Right here. Under their feet.
You miss your mommy?
I had a little girl.
Nearly your age.
You know, if anything happens
to your daddy,
I'll take care of you.
Rachel.
You don't have
anything to say to her.
Do you understand?
If you wanna talk to somebody,
if you wanna ask a question,
you ask me.
What exactly is your plan, Ray?
I know what I'm gonna do.
How about you?
You gonna sit here?
Wait for them to come get you?
Is that your plan?
Maybe you wanna get caught.
Couple days hiding in a basement
too much for you, I bet.
You'll probably turn yourself right in.
Listen.
It stopped.
Maybe you'll be okay.
Maybe you'll get lucky,
and they'll train you as their pet.
You know, feed you,
train you how to do tricks.
No.
No. No.
Ray. Ray.
Ray. Ray. Ray!
Ray!
Keep your voice down. Quiet!
Not my blood. Not my blood.
Not my blood.
Not my...
Not...
...my...
Not my blood.
- Not my blood.
- Stop it.
You gotta be quiet.
- You want them to hear you?
- They drink us.
- Please, they'll hear you.
Then they spray us, like fertilizer.
You gotta be quiet.
- Drink us, and...
- They're gonna come back down here.
Then they spit us out all over
the goddamn red weeds.
Do you understand
what I'm gonna have to do?
I can't let my daughter die
because of you.
This tunnel will get us to the city.
We'll have tunnels there.
Ready-made.
- Stop it.
- Subway. See what I'm saying?
- Hide an army down there.
- Stop it.
We'll go underground.
Sneak attacks at night.
You stop it!
We're the resistance, Ray.
They can't occupy this country.
Occupations always fail. History's
taught us that a thousand times.
This is our land.
We eat it, we breathe it,
only we can live on it.
They can't survive here, Ray.
They weren't built for it.
They're gonna kill you, brother,
not me!
- What are you doing, Dad?
- Not my blood!
Whatever you hear,
don't take this off.
- Dad?
- Rach?
- What was that song?
- That lullaby that I didn't know?
- Not my blood!
- "Hushabye Mountain"?
- Yeah, sing it.
- They can take you!
- Please, Rach, sing it.
- A gentle breeze
- Your daughter!
- Don't stop.
- Not me!
- On Hushabye Mountain
- They're gonna kill you!
- That's my girl.
Softly blows over Lullaby Bay
- Forget it! Tunnel!
- It fills the sails
Of boats that are waiting
Waiting to sail
Your worries away
Rachel?
Oh, my God, no.
Rachel? Rachel?
Rachel? Make some noise, baby.
Rachel?
Rachel? Talk to me, baby. Come on.
Rachel!
No, no, no!
No!
Hey!
What is happening?
Rachel!
Rachel.
Rachel. Rachel.
Rachel?
Rachel.
Dad.
No!
Pull me! Pull me!
Pull! Pull!
Pull me! Come on, pull!
- Dad!
- One, two, three!
We got him! Keep pulling!
Everybody down!
Keep it moving, folks.
Keep going, sir. Keep moving.
I don't know what's going on.
Hold Grandma's hand.
Let's go, folks.
Keep moving forward.
Put that down.
Right this way, ma'am.
Right this way, thank you.
To the left, there, ma'am,
just to your left. Thank you.
What happened to it?
It's dying.
Keep moving forward.
Keep moving, it's all right!
You can pass on through.
Move along!
- What happened here?
- I don't know.
Something's happening to them.
Please, keep moving.
- Let's go, move out.
- Let's go, people.
- Something's happening to them?
- Go. Go, just keep moving, sir.
Let's go, sir. Let's go. Do not stop.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Excuse me. What's happened here?
Did you guys take it down?
No, sir, it was behaving erratically,
walking in circles,
then it went down on its own
about an hour ago.
Now, please, let's go! Let's go!
Keep moving! Come on! Don't stop!
Do not stop! Let's go! Thank you!
How is it dead all by itself?
- Rachel, I'm not sure.
- Coming through.
Coming through. Make a hole.
Coming through.
Calm down.
Calm down and get in the tunnel.
It's safer in here.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Bring out the Javelin!
Clear! Get from behind! Clear!
- Let me know when you're tracking!
- Tracking!
- You got a lock?
- I got a lock!
Fire the Javelin!
- Fire the Javelin!
Fire!
It's okay.
I love you.
- It's okay. You're gonna be okay.
- Let's go!
Keep those civilians out of there.
Back. Stay back!
Come on, folks, back up!
Come on, guys, get on the line.
Get up there now.