[ Thunder Rumbles ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Motor Whirring ]
[ Motor Stops ]
[ Shouting ]
See how it's done?
Yeah, I think I got
the hang of it.
You better.
Boss'll chew my head off
if these cores get messed up.
Don't worry.
We're at 26 feet.
You let Jason
operate the drill?
Yeah, he can
handle it.
[ Motor Slows, Stops ]
[ Crunching ]
[ Cracking ]
I didn't do
anything!
Gimme your hand!
Let go of the drill!
Forget it, Jack!
It's too late!
You're not
gonna make it!
Jack!
Gimme your hand!
[ Yelling ]
I got you!
[ All Shouting ]
What were you thinking?
[ Sighs ]
- What's happening?
- The whole damn shelf
is breaking off!
That's
what's happening!
[ Cracking, Rumbling Continue ]
[ Jack ]
What we have found
locked in these ice cores...
is evidence of a cataclysmic
climate shift,
which occurred around
10,000 years ago.
The concentration of these
natural greenhouse gases
in the ice cores...
indicates that runaway warming
pushed the planet
into an ice age...
which lasted two centuries.
[ Speaking
Foreign Language ]
I'm confused.
I thought you were talking
about global warming,
not an ice age.
Yes, it is a paradox,
but global warming can trigger
a cooling trend.
Let me explain.
The northern hemisphere
owes its temperate climate
to the North Atlantic current.
Heat from the sun arrives
at the equator and is
carried north by the ocean.
But global warming
is melting the polar ice caps
and disrupting this flow.
Eventually,
it will shut down.
And when that occurs,
there goes
our warm climate.
Excuse me.
When do you think this
could happen, Professor?
When?
I don't know.
Maybe in a hundred years.
Maybe in a thousand.
But what I do know is
that if we do not act soon,
it is our children
and our grandchildren
who will have to pay the price.
And who's going to pay
the price of the Kyoto Accord?
It would cost
the world's economy hundreds
of billions of dollars.
With all due respect,
Mr. Vice President,
the cost of doing nothing
could be even higher.
Our climate is fragile.
At the rate we're burning
fossil fuels and polluting
the environment,
the ice caps
will soon disappear.
Professor, um, Hall,
our economy is every bit
as fragile as the environment.
Perhaps you should keep that
in mind before making
sensationalist claims.
Well, the last chunk of ice
that broke off...
was about the size
of the state of Rhode Island.
Some people might call that
pretty sensational.
[ Men Chuckling ]
[ People Shouting ]
Stop global warming!
[ Man ]
I'm here at the Global Warming
Conference in New Delhi,
where, if you can believe
your eyes, it's snowing.
The coldest weather
on record...
has thrown the city
into chaos with numbers
of homeless people--
Taxi! Taxi!
I enjoyed
your testimony, Professor.
It was very spirited.
Oh, thank you.
It's what we're here for,
right? Put on a good show?
Quite. Uh,
I was wondering if
I could talk to you...
about your theory
on abrupt climate shift.
The name's Rapson.
Terry Rapson.
Professor Rapson?
Of the Hedland Center?
That's me.
I've read your work
on ocean currents.
What do you say
to a spot of tea?
Absolutely.
If we can hail a cab.
Oh.
[ Loud Whistle ]
Over here!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Bell Clanging ]
[ Man ] Welcome back
to Glasgow, Scotland,
[ Beeping ]
where Manchester United
leads 3-1 over hometown Celtic,
[ Man Snoring ]
in this pivotal champions'
league match.
We return
to the action 63 minutes
into the second half...
Dennis, NOMAD buoy 4311
is showing a temperature drop...
of 13 degrees.
- Hmm? Where is 4311?
- Well, it's, uh,
- Georges Bank.
- Oh, it's rough seas out there.
Must've knocked it about.
[ Sheep Bleating ]
[ Gulls Squawking ]
[ Television Chatter Continues ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Announcement In Japanese ]
[ Announcement Continues ]
- [ Sirens Chirping ]
- [ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Woman On Phone
Speaking Japanese ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Woman Continues ]
[ People Screaming ]
[ Man ]
Parker, this is Houston.
We're seeing
some bad weather
over Canaveral.
Doesn't look like
you're coming back
this week.
[ Chuckles ]
Your wife's gonna
give me an earful.
[ Chuckles ]
Roger that.
[ Man #2 ]
Hey, come take a look
at this storm system.
It's enormous.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thunderclap ]
I can't believe
I'm spending two weeks
alone with my mum.
Be patient with her, all right?
She's been looking forward
to this holiday for months.
I know.
[ Both Chuckle ]
I love you.
I love you too.
Hey. Hey, hello.
Bye-bye.
[ Man ] The cause
of this extreme weather
remains a mystery,
although some meteorologists
believe sunspots are to blame.
This is very odd.
There's a buoy here
registering a 13 degree drop
in ocean temperature.
Oh, yeah. That's right.
That buoy malfunctioned
the other day.
I'll put a call in,
see if there are any ships
near Georges Bank to get it.
This buoy isn't
in Georges Bank.
It's just off Greenland.
[ Man ]
What?
What are the odds
of two buoys failing?
Remote.
Make that three.
[ Barking ]
- [ Roaring ]
- What's got into them?
[ Animals Howling, Calling ]
I have no idea.
They're all worked up today.
[ Howling ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
Who is it?
Terry Rapson here. Sorry
to call you so early.
No, Professor.
That's all right.
What is it?
Well, we've found
something extraordinary--
extraordinary
and disturbing,
that is.
You recall what you said
in New Delhi...
about how
polar melting might disrupt
the North Atlantic current?
Yes.
Well,
I think it's happening.
What do you mean?
One of our
NOMAD buoys...
registered a 13 degree drop
in surface temperature
the other day.
I sent you
an e-mail.
Hold on.
At first we thought
it was a malfunction,
but there are four more
across the North Atlantic
showing the same thing.
[ Jack ]
This is unbelievable.
You predicted
it would happen.
Yes, but not
in our lifetime.
This is too fast.
There are no forecast models
remotely capable
of plotting this scenario,
except yours.
My model is a reconstruction
of a prehistoric climate shift.
It's not a forecast model.
It's the closest thing
we have.
Nothing like this
has every happened before.
At least not in
the last 10,000 years.
[ Ringing ]
Shouldn't you be monitoring
the weather or something?
This is L.A.
What weather?
[ Motor Running, Faint ]
Wait.
What's that noise?
What noise?
[ Motor Running, Louder ]
[ Motor Stops ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
Honey, I'll be
right back.
[ Woman ]
The coast guard has
closed the beaches...
as waves have been too big
for even the most experienced
of surfers.
L.A. Weather Center.
It's Tommy!
I'm down at the beach!
I'm in the middle
of something.
What do you need?
There-- Ooh! Uh.
There's-- There's hail
the size of golf balls
coming down here!
[ Tommy Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Man ] Low pressure system
moving along...
the California coastline
is creating a cyclonic system
across the L.A. basin.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Yeah. Hello.
Hey, boss, turn on
the Weather Channel.
I think we have to issue
a tornado warning.
What are
you talking about?
[ Woman ]
Palmdale and Lancaster
are reporting...
wind speeds in excess
of 70 miles per hour,
Hold on a second.
conditions that are
highly unusual for California.
[ Woman ]
We have live coverage now
from our Fox 11 chopper.
Are you there, Bart?
Uh, yes, I'm here.
These tornadoes are forming
so fast-- What?
[ Bart ]
Oh! Oh, my God!
Lisa--
Are you getting this on camera?
This tornado just came
and erased the Hollywood sign.
The Hollywood sign is gone.
It's just shredded.
[ Wind Roaring ]
[ People Screaming ]
[ Lisa ]
Bart, what can you see?
Is anyone hurt?
[ Bart ]
I wouldn't be surprised. There
is so much damage down there.
And there are people
down there taking pictures!
Hey! What the hell
are you guys doing!
Go for cover!
You can't stay here!
Get outta here!
What you're seeing are two
actual tornadoes striking Los
Angeles International Airport.
Wait. Wait. It looks like
they've joined and formed
one large tornado.
Tommy!
Oh, my God!
[ Man ]
Urge all of our viewers to stay
away from the area.
- Jeff, where are you?
- I'm on, uh, Yucca and Vine.
I'm on my way in now.
Jeff, you're on TV!
You're right
in the middle of it!
God. Oh, my God!
You gotta get
out of there, man!
Oh.
[ Bart ]
That bus just got dropped
on top of that Porsche!
[ Line Busy Tone ]
Oh, my God. I hope
no one was in that car!
[ Woman ]
And for our national audience
just joining us now,
we are going live
to downtown Los Angeles
right now.
- Tommy?
- If you look over there
behind me, that's a tornado.
Yes! A twister
in Los Angeles.
It's one of the many
tornadoes that are
destroying our city.
There's another one!
That's the Los Angeles
skyline!
It's unbelievable!
It's huge! I've never
seen anything like that!
[ Gasping ]
What's happening?
[ Rumbling Stops ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Car Alarms Blaring ]
[ Chattering ]
All right. All right.
Listen up, everybody.
Listen up, please.
We've got a lot of work to do
and we don't have much time.
So, let's get started,
please. Vorsteen?
All our grid models
are worthless.
I don't think grid models
are gonna be a lot of help here.
The Canadians are reporting
tremendous circulation
moving down from the Arctic.
In Siberia, there's
a low pressure system
unlike anything we've seen,
and Australia just saw
the strongest typhoon
ever recorded.
[ Man ]
Hang on. Are you saying that
these things are interconnected?
[ Booker ]
We have to consider
the possibility.
The only force strong enough
to affect global weather
is the sun.
- What's NASA have to say?
- We've already checked.
Solar output is normal.
What about
the North Atlantic current?
[ Vorsteen ] What about it?
I got a call last night
from Professor Rapson
at the Hedland Center.
He thinks the current
has changed.
[ Murmuring ]
Come on, Jack.
How could that be?
The current depends upon
a delicate balance of salt
and fresh water.
- We all know that.
- Yes.
But no one has
taken into account...
how much fresh water
has been dumped into the ocean
because of melting polar ice.
I think we've hit
a critical desalinization point.
[ Murmuring ]
It would explain
what's driving
this extreme weather.
Hedland had some pretty
convincing data.
They've asked me to feed it into
my paleoclimate model to track
the next set of events.
Hold on, Jack. Are you
suggesting these weather
anomalies are gonna continue?
Not just continue--
get worse.
I think we're on the verge
of a major climate shift.
[ Murmuring ]
Tom!
What are you gonna tell
the administration?
What do you expect me
to tell them?
The government has
to start making long-term
preparations now.
Jack, all you have is a theory.
Then give me the mainframe
and let me prove it!
No.
You have 48 hours.
[ Sighs ]
Professor Hall.
Yes?
I think your theory
may be correct.
Walk with me.
Just a few weeks ago,
I monitored the strongest
hurricane on record.
The hail, the tornadoes--
it all fits.
Can the model
you're working on
factor in storm scenarios?
Oh, we haven't had
the time.
Maybe I can help.
Welcome aboard.
Thanks.
Jack. Jack.
We got the results.
Six to eight months.
That can't be.
That time scale
isn't in months.
It's in weeks.
So far, the terrible weather
hasn't hit the D.C. area,
but local residents
aren't taking any chances,
as people stock up
for what is already
being billed...
as the worst storm season
on record.
You better be sure
about this, Jack.
My ass is on the line.
You saw the model.
And I hope to God
it's wrong.
Oh.
Mr. Vice President.
Tom.
You know
Professor Hall.
Yes, we've met.
Uh, Professor Hall has some
new information I think
you should take a look at.
We just got these results
from our simulation model.
They explain what's causing
the severe weather.
I'll look at this later.
I have a meeting with
the director of FEMA now.
This is very urgent, sir.
Our climate
is changing violently.
It's going to happen
over the next six
to eight weeks.
I thought you said this
wouldn't happen for another
hundred years or so.
I was wrong.
Well, suppose
you're wrong this time.
I wish that I were, but I'm sure
that you're aware of what's
happening all around the world.
We're making all the necessary
preparations for this storm.
What more do you expect?
You have to start
thinking about large scale
evacuations right now,
especially in
the northern states.
Evacuations?
Yes.
Have you lost
your mind, Hall?
I have to go.
Mr. Vice President,
if we don't act now,
it's going to be too late.
Come on, Jack.
[ Man ]
It's been 24 hours now since
the snow started falling...
across the British Isles
and over northern Europe,
and it shows no signs
of letting up.
No. No, no, no.
You gotta stop worrying.
No.
It's fine. We got plenty
of supplies with us.
We're just snowed in.
Yeah. No, it's all right.
It's all right.
You stay
where you are, okay?
I'll be fine.
Yeah, I love you too.
Okay. Bye.
[ Sighs ]
- Hey. How's Jeanette?
- Oh, fine.
Ferry just landed.
Must be nice in Spain.
I wish I was there.
[ TV: Reporter ]
The search and rescue team has
been deployed by helicopter...
to airlift
the royal family to safety.
You think
they'll come get us,
since we got snowed in?
Not likely.
Luckily,
we got our own genny,
enough tea and biscuits
to sink a ship.
Oh, we'll be fine.
As long as the loo
doesn't back up again.
[ All Chuckle ]
In Ireland, those remaining
in Belfast and Banbridge
have been urged to evacuate...
to Dublin as soon
as possible.
The north continues
to receive the worst
of the storm--
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
[ Man ]
We've got zero visibility.
Maintain heading and speed.
- [ Man #2 ]
What's our heading?
- Zero, three, five, sir.
Approximately 40 kilometers
from Balmoral Castle.
[ Man ]
We've lost visual contact
with you.
This gauge here
can't be right.
[ Man #3 ]
Wind speed has dropped to zero.
We have vertical walls
of cirrus cloud formations.
[ Man ]
What the hell
is going on?
Bloody fuel lines
are starting to freeze!
[ Men Shouting ]
Port engine pressure's dropping!
The rotor R.P.M. is dropping!
We've got a flame-out
on the starboard side as well!
Prepare
for crash landing!
Select emergency fuel!
Come on,
you bastard!
Come on!
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Rapson ]
What I'm about to tell you
is supposed to be confidential.
Several hours ago,
three helicopters went down
over Scotland.
They crashed because the fuel
in their lines froze.
At what temperature does--
[ Rapson On Speaker ]
Negative 150 degrees Fahrenheit.
We had to look it up.
The temperature dropped
phenomenally fast.
On the ground, people froze
before they could
get out of their cars.
- Get me a satellite picture
of Scotland two hours ago.
- Yeah.
We've got mountains of data
but nowhere near enough
computer power to analyze it.
- Can you help us?
- Send us what you've got,
and we'll do our best.
[ Rapson ]
Thanks, Jack. Bye for now.
This is Scotland at the time
the temperature dropped.
[ Frank ]
This thing looks
just like a hurricane.
[ Janet ]
Only hurricanes don't form
over land.
It's a mob scene here
at Grand Central Station.
Over half the platforms
are flooded,
and service has been
suspended on all trains.
With planes still grounded
and trains now out of service,
that's bad news--
Victor's coming to pick me up.
Do you guys want a ride
to the train station?
Stranded
since this morning.
Not anymore.
In Nova Scotia earlier,
the ocean rose by 25 feet
in a matter of seconds.
What we have feared
for the past few days
has indeed happened.
The cold front moving down
from the Arctic...
has created an enormous
storm system in Canada,
which, incredible as it sounds,
looks like a tropical hurricane.
I gotta go pick up
my little brother.
Do you guys want a ride?
Where is he?
He's in a boarding school
in Philadelphia.
If this system moves south,
we could see a wind-driven
storm surge...
that could threaten
the entire Eastern Seaboard.
Okay. Bye. Victor's stuck
in traffic on Fifth Avenue.
It'll be easier
to head out of town
if we meet him over there.
All right.
You mean walk?
No, not in this.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
We should take
the stairs.
We're on the top floor.
I guess we're walkin'.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Horns Honking,
People Shouting ]
Maybe we should just stay here.
I think the young lady
is right, sir.
No. We need to get home.
Come on!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Goats Bleating ]
[ Growls ]
Hey, Cesar, come here.
What are you doing?
The wolves!
They're gone!
[ Man On News ]
Just to give you an idea
of the situation,
which seems to be becoming
worse with each passing minute,
at the moment, we have flooding
in most parts of the island.
We've got traffic snarl-ups
because the electricity
is now out...
to almost every part
of Manhattan.
No traffic signals,
car accidents-- at least 200--
and Lower Manhattan, we've been
told, is virtually inaccessible.
[ Man ]
No one is to be on the streets.
Please go inside.
[ Excited Chattering ]
Sir, just calm down.
Public library's right up here.
Make your way up there.
You can stay warm and dry.
Come on, guys.
This way.
Excuse me.
Your bad.
Goddamn $1,500
waterproof raincoat!
Please shut up, man.
There must be rats
everywhere.
That's 'cause it's New York.
Hey! Hey!
Open up, big poppa!
It's out of service.
It's out of service!
No, no. I'll give you
$100 to put it in service.
You don't have to do that.
No, no. Really, $200.
I won't have it.
Oh, God, I love buses.
This is just so much fun.
[ Shouting ]
Hello?
I can't reach my driver.
I lost the signal.
This is insane.
We should just go back
to your apartment.
[ Brian ]
Yeah. I vote for that.
What? Are you kidding?
We have to get higher!
Come on.
Up to the library.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
- [ Child Screams ]
- [ Thunderclap ]
[ Man On News ]
There is a wall of water
coming towards New York City!
Everybody--
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
- [ Woman Screams ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
Oh, my--
Laura!
No! No!
No, Sam! Sam, no!
Laura! Laura! Laura!
Come on!
[ Gasps ]
Come! Come on!
- Sam!
- Go!
[ Dog Barking ]
Here he is.
Jack, were you able
to re-create the thermal cycle?
Yes. The storm's rotation
is pulling super-cooled air
down from the upper troposphere.
But shouldn't the air warm up
before it reaches ground level?
It should, but it doesn't.
The air's descending
too rapidly.
Is this
an isolated incident?
I'm afraid not.
We've located two other
supercells in addition
to the one over Scotland.
There's one over Northern Canada
and another one over Siberia.
And do we know
their projected path?
Yes. Our previous estimates
of six to eight weeks
weren't even close.
This one storm is going
to change the face
of our planet.
Here's a projection
of 24 hours out.
This is 48 hours out.
And in seven to 10 days.
When this storm is over,
we'll be in a new ice age.
My God.
Professor, it's time
you got out of there.
I'm afraid that time
has come and gone, my friend.
What can we do?
Save as many as you can.
[ Feedback On Line ]
[ Disconnect Signal ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
Jack. Something's
happened in New York.
No. The power is out.
I've been in here all day.
[ Officer ]
Who needs help?
Over here. Over here.
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
Hi.
[ Man ]
Hello.
[ Dog Whimpering ]
What?
This is the last one.
Enjoy it. Greedy.
[ Operator ]
All circuits are busy.
[ Dialing Phone ]
Did you reach
your little brother yet?
No. There's still no service.
Damn cell phones.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Are there any pay phones
on the upper floors?
No. No.
But there are some
on the mezzanine.
Great.
- But I think it's underwater.
- Where are you going?
The power's out.
Older pay phones draw their
power directly from the line.
[ Woman On P.A., Indistinct ]
Oh, God. I've been trying
to reach Sam.
So have I.
I kept trying to call you,
but I couldn't get through.
It's been a madhouse
around here. Come on.
Are you sure about this?
Ah. Oh.
- [ Dial Tone ]
- It works.
Jack? Sam's on the phone.
Line four.
- Sam?
- Dad!
Where are you?
Are you all right?
We're at the public library.
Sam, it's Mom.
I'm so happy you're okay.
Mom, can you call
Laura and Brian's parents
and tell them we're all right?
Yes. Of course.
- Sam, what's that noise?
- Sam? Sam?
[ Gasping ]
What is going on out there, Dad?
Sam? Sam, listen to me.
Listen very carefully.
Forget what I said
about trying to head south.
It's too late for that.
The storm is just gonna
get worse.
It's gonna turn into
a massive blizzard with an eye
in the center, like a hurricane.
- Uh-huh.
- The air is gonna be so cold,
you could freeze to death
in seconds.
- Sam?
- What should we do?
Listen to me, son.
Do not go outside.
Just burn whatever you can
to stay warm and try
to wait it out.
I will come for you.
Do you understand me?
[ Shivering ]
Sam! Sam, come back!
[ Jack ]
Sam? Sam, did you hear me?
Did you hear me?
[ Gasping ]
[ Shivering, Panting ]
[ Sobbing ]
I thought you drowned.
Let's find some
dry clothes for you.
Yeah.
Where did you store
the arctic gear?
You can't make it
to New York, Jack.
I've walked that far
before in the snow.
This is not the same.
Jack, this is not the same!
Lucy, tell him.
I have to do this.
I know.
Frank told me about Sam.
I'm not gonna try
to talk you out of going,
but there's something
I need for you to do first.
You have to explain your results
to the administration.
I already tried that.
I know this time
will be different.
You're gonna brief
the president directly.
[ Officer ]
Is that the last of it?
[ Laura ]
Yeah. Pretty much.
Okay.
We also found this radio,
but I don't think it works.
Let me see it.
[ Barking ]
Buddha, be quiet!
You ain't even supposed
to be in here anyway.
- [ Barking Continues ]
- [ Loud Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Barking Continues ]
Come on, guys.
Oh, my God.
[ Glass Shattering ]
The basic rule of storms
is that they continue...
until the imbalance
that created them is corrected.
In this case, we're talking
about a global realignment.
The superstorm will
last seven to 10 days.
When it's over, ice and snow
will cover the entire
Northern Hemisphere.
The ice and snow
will reflect sunlight.
The earth's atmosphere
will restabilize...
but with an average
temperature close to that
of the last ice age.
What can we do about this?
[ Sighs ]
Head as far south as possible.
That is not amusing,
Professor.
Where do you suggest
they go?
The farther south they go,
the safer they'll be.
Texas. Parts of Florida
that aren't flooded.
Mexico would be best.
Mexico? Maybe
you should stick to science
and leave policy to us.
Well, we tried that approach.
You didn't want to hear
about the science...
when it could
have made a difference.
What exactly are you
proposing, Professor?
Evacuate everyone
south of that line.
What about the people
in the north?
I'm afraid
it's too late for them.
If they go outside,
the storm will kill them.
At this point,
their best chance
is to stay inside,
try to ride it out,
pray.
What do you think he'll do?
I don't know.
Jack, thanks.
And good luck.
You too.
We're all gonna need it.
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Generator Chugging ]
Sorry, mates, but we're
just about out of petrol.
Hey, is there any chance...
that it will run... on this?
[ Chuckles ]
Are you mad?
That's a 12-year-old scotch.
[ Laughs ]
Gentlemen. To England.
To mankind.
To Manchester United.
[ All Laughing ]
Come on, Buddha. Come on.
Do your business.
Look. There's nobody around.
[ Buddha Whimpering ]
Okay. You know what?
I'll turn around. I won't look.
I promise.
[ Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
What?
Hey, man.
There's people out there.
I was walking my dog.
There's hundreds of 'em.
They're walkin' on the snow.
[ Chattering ]
[ Officer ]
Where are they all going?
They're gettin'
out of the city
before it's too late.
[ Wind Howling ]
I got it.
You're supposed to be
on a bus heading south.
I've been watching
your back for 20 years.
You think I'd let you
go alone?
All these years, I thought
I was watching your back.
Where are the keys?
In the truck.
Where do you think
you're going?
Neither one of you
knows how to navigate
worth a damn.
Without me, you'll
end up in Cleveland.
I'll try to give you
updates on the storm
as it heads your way.
Good luck, Jack.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Woman Reporting ]
Breaking news from
the U.S.-Mexico border.
Just half an hour ago,
Mexican officials
closed the border...
in the light
of so many U.S. refugees
who are fleeing south...
in the wake
of the approaching storm.
These people came here
in anticipation of crossing
into Mexico.
Instead, they've been met
with closed gates--
Here it is.
Oh, this fireplace
probably hasn't been used
in about a hundred years.
All right.
- What are you doing?
- What do you think
we were gonna burn?
You can't burn books.
No. Absolutely not!
You wanna freeze to death?
I'll go get some more.
I'll help you.
I'm going with them.
Okay. Do you have
a cafeteria or a lunchroom?
Just an employees' lounge
with a few vending machines.
[ Buddha Barking ]
We're not gonna last very long
on M&M's and potato chips.
What about the garbage cans?
There's always somethin'
to eat in the garbage.
[ Buddha Whimpering ]
[ Gasps ]
Are you all right?
Yeah. I'm fine. I just
cut my leg the other day.
[ Radio Static ]
Did you get a signal?
Yeah. For a minute.
And?
Man, this storm is everywhere.
It's hit the entire
Northern Hemisphere.
Europe is buried
under 15 feet of snow.
And they say it's gonna
get just as bad here.
I mean, I don't think
your dad's gonna make it.
No. He'll make it.
He'll make it.
[ Man On News ]
The White House has ordered...
the following national disaster
alert for all northern states:
Continued exposure
to the approaching storm
is deadly.
Remain indoors and take
all measures to stay warm,
burning any fuel sources
until the storm is over.
Roads are impassable
across New York State...
and as far south
as Pennsylvania.
Where are we?
[ Man On News Continues,
Indistinct ]
Looks like we're
just north of Philadelphia.
[ Man On News ]
Rescue workers say
they have no idea--
Look out!
You guys okay?
Yeah.
- Once again, roads across
the northern states...
- Sorry, boss.
are impassable.
Unpack the snowshoes.
We're walking from here.
Come on, men.
Let's get up and get going.
We've only made it to Brooklyn.
Maybe we should just turn back.
What for? Half the city's
frozen underwater.
There's nothing to go back to.
It's time to get up.
Keep moving.
We should've stayed
in the library.
Come on, men.
Okay, guys.
Let's get moving.
Wake up.
What are you doing?
Insulatin'.
Newspaper's best,
but this'll do it.
You know, you spend
some years on the streets,
and you learn how to keep warm.
Hey.
Thanks.
[ Grunting, Screaming ]
[ Groaning, Whimpering ]
[ Jack ]
Frank!
Are you all right?
I'm fine!
Just dropped in
to do a little shopping.
I gotta lose this sled.
Hold on!
We'll pull you up!
Jason! You gotta
support Frank's weight!
Okay! I'll try!
[ Grunting ]
Okay! I think
I have his weight now!
I'm coming to you!
[ Glass Cracking ]
[ Grunting, Whimpering ]
The glass is breaking!
Too much weight!
It's not gonna hold.
No! No!
Frank!
I can get you out!
[ Jack ]
Don't do it!
- No! Frank! Don't!
- Frank, no!
Frank!
[ Radio:
Chatter, Indistinct ]
Get this convoy
moving now.
[ Whispering ]
I know. I know.
Mr. President.
All right.
I'm sorry, sir.
We can't wait any longer.
We're the last ones.
All right.
[ Pilot ]
Mexicali Control,
this is Delta 2-6.
We're carrying an urgent message
for high command.
Request priority
on landing zone one.
[ Chattering, Shouting ]
[ Radio Chatter Continues,
Indistinct ]
Sir.
Thank you, Corporal.
Carry on.
Madam Secretary?
Raymond.
The president's motorcade
got caught in the storm.
They didn't make it.
She wouldn't
wake up this morning.
I-I-- I mean, last night
she only had a fever.
I don't understand.
God, she's awfully pale.
Well, guys, look.
none of us has had anything
real to eat in days.
[ Jeremy ] I'm telling you,
it's hypothermia.
How could it be hypothermia?
We've all been--
Maybe it's just
the flu, you guys.
No, no,
it's not the flu.
Yeah?
And how do you know?
Books can be good for
something other than burning.
Let's go over her symptoms.
I told you. She has a fever
and a really cold sweat.
[ Woman ]
How's her pulse?
It's really fast.
Did she have any injuries,
like a cut or something
that might have gotten infected?
She was complaining
about a cut on her leg
a few days ago.
I didn't-- I didn't
think anything of it.
Oh, my gosh.
That's blood poisoning.
Um, septicemia.
She could go into septic shock.
I've seen that before.
That can get bad.
She needs a massive dose
of penicillin...
or a broad-spectrum
antibiotic immediately,
or--
Or what?
I've never seen
anything like it.
There's no point of reference.
All I can see
is cloud cover.
What are you doing?
Taking infrared image
of thermal currents...
sent to Houston, Korolev,
your weather service.
[ Parker ]
I'll help you.
Tom?
Tom, wake up.
[ Groans ]
I just received
some satellite images
from the space station.
You'd better take a look.
How big is this thing?
The vortex is
50 miles in diameter
and growing.
The two cells
over Europe and Asia
are even bigger.
[ Tom ]
Good God.
This one's gonna hit New York
inside an hour.
[ Gasping, Panting ]
Jack--
Jason!
Are you all right?
[ Panting, Gasping ]
[ Barking ]
- What are you doing?
- There's gotta be medicine
on that ship.
I thought you said
it was too dangerous
to go outside.
I know I did.
Where'd you find
those chairs?
[ Gasps ]
There!
[ Lock Rattling ]
Ohh! Come on!
Damn it!
- [ Grunts Loudly ]
- [ Growling ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Yells ]
[ Panting ]
- It's all in Russian. I--
- [ Sam ] I know.
- H-H-Hey, guys, I found it.
- What? How do you know?
Because it says "penicillin"
on the bottom.
[ Growling ]
Wait. This is the mess hall.
We should find some food
while we're here.
We don't have time.
None of us are gonna survive
without food, including Laura.
Okay.
[ Exhales, Clears Throat ]
[ J.D. ]
Sam, over here!
What?
Bingo.
[ Laughs ]
[ Sam Laughs ]
[ Glass Clattering ]
[ Inflating Loudly ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Sam ]
Brian?
[ Brian ]
I'm okay.
[ J.D. ] What happened?
Okay, okay. All I did
was open up a cupboard.
[ Quiet Snarling ]
We can use it.
Put food in it.
[ Loud Snarl ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Growling ]
[ Panicked Yelling ]
- [ Continues Yelling ]
- [ Grunting ]
Pull him in!
[ Wolf Whimpers ]
[ Whimpering, Growling ]
You all right?
[ J.D. Groans ]
My leg.
Here, use this.
[ Shuddering, Groaning ]
Oh, yeah. Here. Ohh!
It should be
over New York by now.
Satellite readings
are showing a temperature drop
of 10 degrees per second.
[ Sam ]
You guys, I think
we're in the eye of it.
We gotta get back right now.
Look,
I'm gonna go outside...
and I'm gonna lure the wolves
out of the room.
- When they leave,
you lock the door.
- Good luck.
- [ Crunch ]
- [ Growling ]
[ Yelling ]
Aah!
[ Gasps ]
[ Muttering, Grunting ]
[ Growling, Snarling ]
Aah!
[ Panting, Gasping ]
- [ Wolf Whimpers ]
- [ Panting ]
[ Groans ]
Brian, hurry!
[ Muttering ]
Come on! Hurry!
[ Snarling, Growling ]
[ Groans, Panting ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Banging On Door ]
Brian!
Brian, open the door!
We have to get out of here now.
Brian, get the supplies.
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Crackling ]
Let's go!
Pull! Pull, Brian!
Come on! Pull!
Take the medicine to Laura!
[ J.D. Groaning, Yelling ]
We're almost there, man!
Come on! Aah!
[ Grunts ]
Brian, close the door!
Don't let the fire
go out!
What's happening?
Buddha,
come away from the door!
Come, Buddha, come!
More books! More books!
How long
have I been out of it?
Couple hours.
How do you feel?
Okay.
What happened?
Well, we had to get inside
in kind of a hurry,
so I sort of pushed you in.
I should be used to
you pushing me around.
Good to have you back.
What are you doing?
The eye of the storm
has passed,
and we're 40 miles
from Manhattan.
Shouldn't we wait
one more day?
Sam may not have
one more day.
What do you think's
gonna happen to us?
What do you mean?
I mean us.
Civilization.
Everybody.
Mankind survived
the last ice age.
We're certainly capable
of surviving this one.
All depends on
whether or not we're able
to learn from our mistakes.
I sure as hell would like
a chance to learn from mine.
You did everything you could.
I was thinking about Sam.
Jack, you know
the chances of Sam--
I made my son a promise.
I'm going to keep it.
[ Man On Radio ]
Parker, this is Houston.
Do you read?
Roger, Mission Control.
Go ahead.
We're getting scattered reports
that the storm is dissipating
over North America.
Can you confirm?
[ Parker ]
Affirmative.
It's finally clearing.
We're over Europe right now.
I can see landmass
for the first time in days.
How much further is it
to the library?
It should be...
right here.
I'm sorry, Jack.
Sam?
Who is that?
My father.
You made it.
Of course I did.
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
Mr. President.
I just received
a shortwave radio transmission
from Jack Hall.
He made it to New York.
He says
there are survivors.
Thank you, Tom.
That's--
That's good news.
Jack!
It's good to see you!
Come on.
Let's go get on board.
Look at that.
What?
Have you ever seen the air
so clear?