Doctor's log.
It's day 243 in this...
portobello purgatory.
My only companion
is a rock I named Stone.
The question is,
for whom am I narrating this?
<i>It seems I've become a featured
player in the theater of the absurd.</i>
<i>Marooned in deep space
by that wretched blue rodent.</i>
<i>But it's all good,</i>
<i>thanks to a breathable atmosphere
and my supreme intellect,</i>
<i>sharpened against the only
competitor savvy enough to bring it.</i>
Chanterelle to d4. Mmm.
<i>I've been striving to make fungi
into a functional drink of choice...</i>
Mushroom coffee.
<i>With limited...</i>
<i>limited...</i>
<i>success.</i>
<i>But today, day 243,</i>
<i>has brought a new optimism
to my most pressing endeavor...</i>
<i>Planetus exodus to returnicus
and kick blue butticus.</i>
If my calculations are correct,
and there's no reason to say
"if" because they always are...
this quill is going to power
my masterpiece.
Let's light this candle...
and see who comes
a-knockin'.
Greetings!
<i>Klaatu barada nikto.</i>
Agent Stone? Now!
Thank you, Stone.
It's time to say goodbye to
this piece-of-shiitake planet!
Huh?
Where did you get that?
From a little blue menace
on the planet called Earth.
I'd be happy
to show you the way.
How excited are you,
going to Hawaii with me? Oh, Hawaii.
Oh, yeah!
Wow.
Welcome to Sonic Air,
the fastest way to travel.
Now boarding groups one and two.
Oh!
Sonic, this is so fun!
There we go.
Okay, you're free to go.
Enjoy your trip.
Bye-bye now.
Okay.
Okay, use this one
to get back home.
Oh!
All right, we're off.
Miss you already! Okay?
Have fun at Rachel's wedding!
Let's do this.
<i>♪ Na-na-na-na ♪</i>
<i>♪ Here comes the hotstepper
Murderer ♪</i>
<i>♪ I'm the lyrical gangster
<i>♪ Pick up the crew in-a de area
Murderer ♪</i>
<i>♪ It's how we do it, man ♪</i>
Whoo-hoo!
<i>♪ Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na ♪</i>
<i>♪ Na-na-na-nah ♪</i>
<i>♪ Yeah, man ♪</i>
<i>♪ It's how we do it ♪</i>
<i>♪ Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na ♪</i>
<i>♪ Na-na-na-nah ♪</i>
If these readings
are accurate, he's here.
I found him!
I just hope I'm not too late.
Hmm. He's close.
I just need a way to reach
him without being spotted.
Standard human transport.
Perfect.
<i>♪ This is how we do it ♪</i>
<i>♪ It's Friday night ♪</i>
Uh-oh.
Oh, boy.
<i>Aloha!</i>
<i>- How's it going, bud?
- Oh, you know.</i>
Just a quiet night at home,
settling in with a good book.
<i>And you? What's up with you?</i>
I was just calling
to say we're here.
Don't worry.
Everything here
is completely normal.
Uh-huh. Night, bud.
All right, Ozzy,
it's movie night at Casa de Sonic,
and it's your turn to pick.
<i>But I am not watching
Snow Dogs again.</i>
Blackout!
Ozzy!
Oh, sorry, buddy.
Everything's okay.
Whoa!
Uh, excuse me.
We did not order a poltergeist.
Eggman?
Hello, hedgehog.
Did you miss me?
I don't know how you got back,
but you made
a big mistake coming here.
<i>Au contraire, mon frère.</i>
The mistake
was thinking you'd won.
But that was just a prelude,
an hors d'oeuvre,
an aperitif, an amuse-bouche.
I get it.
I don't think you do.
But you're about to.
And so will that idiot
sheriff and his wife.
And your little dog too!
Pitiful.
What? Who are you?
Where are my manners?
Sonic, meet Knuckles.
My new BFFAE.
Bestest friend forever and ever!
Look, Robotnik, I don't care
who you brought to help you.
You're never going
to get my power.
Do I look like
I need your power?
So nice when diabolical evil
lives up to the hype.
Where is it?
Oh, you want it? Here it comes.
I was expecting more of you.
You're unskilled.
Untrained.
You forgot one. Unstoppable.
It is my destiny to do
what my ancestors could not...
To restore the ultimate power
to the home of my people.
Ultimate power?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You've got the wrong guy.
Ultimate power?
Now you speak-ee my language.
Come on. Get in!
I'm on your side.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
Get us out of here!
Go, go, go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
What is going on?
Robotnik's back?
And who is Clifford
the Big Red Rage Monster?
That's Knuckles,
the last of the Echidnas
and the most dangerous warrior
in the galaxy.
He's obsessed with finding
the Master Emerald.
Are you serious?
The Master Emerald?
That's just a bedtime story.
Well, he believes it's real.
And he must think
you're the key to finding it.
Red light! Give me the wheel!
Hey, what are you...
Move your foot.
Just let me... Come on!
What are you doing?
We're flying.
Foxy move.
You want something done right...
You have to hire someone
you can push around.
All caps.
<i>♪ I waited till I saw the sun ♪</i>
<i>♪ I don't know why
I didn't come ♪</i>
Doctor,
where are you?
Freak.
Oh, I, uh... I'm sorry, folks.
Uh, I have to close early.
Everybody out!
Everybody out. Thank you
for visiting the Mean Bean.
All right, good night.
Good night.
He's back.
He's back!
That's more like it.
I've been re-hatched!
So, my massively
metacarpaled friend,
you mentioned...
Ultimate power.
Back at the house?
The Master Emerald?
It does not concern you.
I got you off that planet and
you brought me to the hedgehog.
We have no more use
for each other.
Well, I hate to be
a contrarian, but...
I think we might.
You think these machines
are a match for me?
Oh, they are stairs.
You see, Earth is my turf, G.
If you don't know how to floss,
you'll be lost without me.
I understand nothing
of what you just said.
I help you retrieve the Emerald,
and you use it to...
destroy the hedgehog!
You're suggesting an alliance.
Around here we simply
grip each other's hands tightly.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
You truculent space bumpkin!
You've crushed my favorite hand!
Really? My hand is uninjured.
Ugh.
But I'm now convinced
of your commitment.
"Oh, goody,"
he exclaimed,
while he reset two of his knuckles.
I'm...
delighted to be
on the same team.
Road trip!
I'll let you stick your
nose out the window.
According to this map,
the first clue is in Siberia.
It's a compass that
will lead to the Emerald.
And with Knuckles already here,
it's a race.
We're gonna get there first.
<i>♪ Me and you
Maybe sunshine, maybe rain ♪</i>
Doctor. It's really you.
You look different.
Papa's got a brand new 'stache.
Ha!
I knew it. I knew it!
I knew you'd come back, sir.
I never stopped steaming
your Austrian goat's milk.
Could use some mushroom.
You brought something.
Some kind of, uh,
space porcupine.
Porcupine? I am an Echidna!
Welcome to the team.
That means he trusts you, Stone.
Now let's renovate this dump!
Latte with steamed
Austrian goat milk!
"Just chilling. Watching TV."
Dot, dot, dot.
Doctor,
why are we working
with this imbecile?
Because that simpleminded space trash
is the key to something extraordinary.
Something to help you
get revenge on the hedgehog.
Think bigger, Stone.
The emerald he seeks
could power my wildest designs.
My genius wouldn't
just be recognized on Earth.
It would spread virally
to every corner of the galaxy,
allowing me to harness all the
negative forces of the universe
and commune
with Darkness itself.
Wow. That sounds big.
It's been on my vision board for
years. It's the Law of Attraction.
<i>Didn't you see The Secret?</i>
Kaplooey!
Kaplooey.
"Another boring night at home."
The hedgehog has returned home!
<i>Falsa.
Which is Latin for "wrong-o."</i>
According to my worldwide network
cell tower triangulation, he's lying,
all the way
from the majestic hinterlands
of Eastern Siberia.
He's a long-distance liar!
Kuh! Kuh! Kuh!
Nga-nga-nga-nga-nga!
Yeah, there's more
where that came from.
I pinpointed the coordinates.
It's right up ahead.
Wow.
Hey, Tails. Wait up.
Whoa.
Check this out.
Can you translate that?
Uh, yeah.
<i>Ages ago,
a fearsome group of warriors,</i>
<i>known as the Echidnas,</i>
<i>forged the Seven Chaos Emeralds</i>
<i>into the most unstoppable
weapon ever created.</i>
The Master Emerald.
<i>With it, a single warrior</i>
<i>could defeat entire armies.</i>
<i>Believing no one should
have such power,</i>
<i>an order of heroes
recovered the Emerald</i>
<i>and swore to protect it
from evil.</i>
Sounds like
the Owls and the Echidnas
have been fighting
each other for centuries.
Whoa.
Wait a second.
I've seen these symbols before.
Here we go.
Well, that did something.
Whoa! The compass!
This will lead us
to the Emerald!
Hey, you got
a little something on your...
Oh, no. Tails, get back.
Run!
That guy again?
Heads up, my little stalagmites.
Someone call an Uber?
Hey, thanks for doing
all the hard stuff.
But we'll take it from here.
Oh! Whoo!
Good one!
I'm sure that wasn't important.
Tails, that's our exit. Come on.
Uh-huh. Let's split up.
Right.
Quick little stretch
and here we go.
That's new.
Whoa.
Sonic!
Snowball fight!
Surrender the compass!
You are no match for me.
My rings!
Has anyone ever told you
you've got serious anger issues?
You mock me
with your weak jokes,
but you know nothing
about me, hedgehog.
Well, I know you Echidnas have a habit of
showing up uninvited and ruining my life.
Sonic! Are you okay?
Tails, take the compass
and get out of here!
Yeah!
Later, haters!
Tails!
Tails, come on. Wake up.
He chose helping the fox
over pursuing the compass.
Of course he did.
New friend,
same pathetic weakness.
Hmm.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
We're in real trouble here.
Come on, Tails. I need you to fly
us out of here. Time to wake up.
See ya, kids.
Enjoy the fresh powder.
Did you...
What? This better
be important. I just...
<i>Are you skiing?</i>
I need you to use the ring I gave
you to save me. Like right now.
<i>Okay,
slow down. I don't even know where you are.</i>
You just gotta picture
where you want the ring to go.
So picture this.
Oh, my God. Okay, okay. Hang on.
What?
<i>Did you throw it?</i>
<i>Oh, God. What? Tell me what "Oh,
God."</i>
I mixed up the rings
when I was teasing Jojo.
<i>What? Where is it then?</i>
You don't want to know.
before I become
a hedgehog-flavored snow cone.
Hang tight, buddy. I got this.
With this ring, Rachel...
Hey! Hi.
Uh... Everything okay, bud?
Not really. What are you doing?
This is gonna sound crazy,
but I need to see that ring
for just one second.
Have you lost your mind?
I'm gonna give it
right back, I promise.
Please, Randall, it's really important. No,
bro. Go sit down.
With this ring... Yes, baby.
I'm so sorry about this.
Snow, my God. Oh, boy.
Incoming!
Oh.
Anybody hurt?
Sonic! Hawaii.
Are you okay?
What's happening?
Are you hurt?
No, no, I'm fine. Okay, good.
Because you're in
so much trouble!
Okay, you calm down.
You talk.
Okay, quick version.
Robotnik is back on Earth
and he's after a magic emerald.
We need to get it back
or the world is doomed.
Tails!
Wait! All this happened
since yesterday?
Wait. Who's Tails?
Tails, can you hear me?
Oh, Lord,
there are two of them now.
Okay, let me think.
Tails, come on, buddy.
Hey!
Randall,
why do all of your friends have weapons?
It's okay, everyone.
We're federal agents.
You, too, Agent. Go ahead.
Aunt Maddie? Yeah.
Sonic and his friend
dropped this.
I have an idea.
Hey, come on.
You can't just leave us in here.
My friend is hurt! He needs a doctor,
a vet, anyone!
Tails,
you got to wake up, buddy.
Please wake up.
All clear.
Shh! Shh!
We got her.
Move in.
Okay.
I did not mean to do that!
Whoo!
Maddie! Maddie!
We're busting out of here.
How'd you get past the guards?
Because that little fox
is into some crazy stuff.
Come on.
Let's go. You're amazing.
Ah.
What's happening?
Wait for it.
Yes. Eureka!
I've found it!
Sonic.
What is that? A big problem.
The compass led Robotnik
to the Emerald.
That's got to be
hundreds of miles away.
All right.
Huddle up.
Let's figure out a plan.
Together.
I'm not letting
anyone else get hurt
because of me.
I'm gonna fix this
while I still can.
Sonic!
Sonic, wait!
Hold on. Wait. Don't move.
Take it easy, little guy.
You're hurt.
But we have to help him. You
don't know what he's up against.
Ugh. Water.
Why did it have to be water?
Okay, you can do this.
Gotta go fast.
Oh!
I don't want to die
like this! It's derivative!
Make room for Daddy!
Two and two. Great!
We're still bipedals,
more or less.
Fire in the hole!
I've solved it. There is a
booby trap every seven seco...
That was a little early. Mmm.
Oh! So glad it didn't
cut off my mustache.
Hey, Little Red Wrecking Ball.
I know you're dying
to get your Emerald on,
but can we be a little bit more
mindful of our surroundings?
May I?
<i>In 30 feet, turn left.</i>
Work smarter, not harder.
My pelvis.
Okay, Secret Temple,
let's see what you've got.
Whoa!
No, no, no! No!
No.
Yes!
<i>You have
arrived at your destination.</i>
Wow. That really
opened up the space.
I can't even picture it
with an impenetrable wall now.
And the rubble
is always a nice touch.
At last. The Master Emerald.
Ultimate power.
Soon order will be restored.
All because of what
we have done together.
Such a lovely sentiment,
Knuckles.
I think I feel
a single tear forming.
Sadly...
You're as useful to me now
as a backstage pass
to Limp Bizkit.
Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Nailed it.
This guy is always trying
to spoil a bad thing!
Ah! You guys are here, too?
Took the long way, huh?
Is everything a joke to you?
Why must you constantly
interfere with my destiny?
Because my destiny is to
protect my friends and family.
I think I just threw up
in my mouth.
And if you want that emerald,
you're gonna have to go through me.
Whoa!
The Echidna's
taking no prisoners today!
Sonic has heart,
but will he lose the quill to live?
I don't want to fight you,
but you're not giving me much choice.
Too easy. Let's do this.
Huh?
Hi there, beautiful.
You're the real deal,
aren't you?
Say goodbye, hedgehog.
Knuckles, stop.
Robotnik's stealing the Emerald!
Mine.
Wait! That wasn't the deal.
Oh, you poor, naive creature.
It's not your fault.
A more advanced intellect would
have seen this move coming a mile away.
Or 1.6 kilometers.
But I trusted you!
You were my friend!
I'm sorry.
That just hit me funny.
Let this be
my final lesson to you,
you dim-witted
celestial skin tag.
Friends...
are open, honest
and vulnerable with each other.
Which means X squared times
the hypotenuse of Y squared,
divided by the absolute value
of friendship, equals...
dookie!
Oh, no.
Chaos is power!
Let's get out of here!
That sly little fox!
Come on, Knucklehead.
We're not beat yet.
Doctor, you're here.
Yes,
I'm here, and yet I'm...
not all there.
Sir, are you feeling okay?
I'm more than okay.
I'm upgraded.
Sinister 3.0.
My game is next level.
Hi.
I can smell the electricity
in your brain.
You smell like a snack plate.
Yeah, no, that's fair.
I had a couple today.
Sit down.
I didn't know.
'Cause he was in the chair,
so I didn't... Okay.
Sir? We have a problem.
- All teams in position!
- Set up a perimeter!
Move! Move! Move!
<i>Incorrectus, my trusty barnacle.</i>
After all these years,
what I finally got...
is a solution.
Commander. Status report.
Robotnik is in there with Stone
and a hostage. Possibly local PD.
Um...
Okay.
Rockin' that new
spring collection, I see.
Well, if it isn't
the Pastry King.
The Donut Lord.
A real genius would remember
the name of the guy
who helped kick your butt
off this planet.
And I'll do it again
if you mess with Green Hills.
Congratulations on your
oh-so-temporary sense of superiority.
You're finished, Robotnik!
We've taken everything.
Your lab, your drones,
your funding!
Let's see how big of a man you
are without your silly little robots.
Would you like to see how...
big a man I can be?
Welcome to the new norm.
My God!
Doctor! Take me with you!
He's taking everything apart.
He's building something.
That can only be one thing.
The fearsome power
of the Emerald.
If that thing really
turns thoughts into power,
we are in big trouble.
Robotnik has a lot
of bad thoughts.
Whoa.
Sir, you're magnificent!
Thank you, sycophant.
Your admiration is inevitable.
World Domination playlist.
Fall back.
Fall back! Quick! Retreat!
Sonic!
Like a blister,
he keeps coming back!
He's on the okay-to-kill list. Shoot
the missiles. Make a decision.
I need a moment, sir. I'm
trying to figure out how to do this.
Did you even glance at a manual?
No! I'll do it.
Pardon my lightning.
You might want to
ground yourself.
Whoa!
Hang on!
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
Oh,
yeah! Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo! Close one.
Sonic!
Robotnik!
Deceiver!
Die, mosquito.
Ooh! I felt that.
Oh! Whoa!
What just happened?
It's the Stache Masher.
Right here in the manual.
Return to sender.
Stone?
Oh, great.
Next thing you know, there'll be a
report about a hostile work environment.
Time to fight.
We have to find his weak spot.
Hedgehog!
Look out!
Let's go!
All right, mustache.
Come and get me.
You don't tell me
about coming and getting.
I am on the cutting edge
of coming and getting!
Coming, getting.
Go! Move, guys! Move back! Let's go,
that's it! Go, go, go!
Keep going! Go! Go!
No, no! Stop! Stop the truck!
Tom, what happened here?
You thinking what I'm
thinking? Let's get our kid.
We need your truck!
Coming,
getting. Whew!
Yoo-hoo!
So what's the
plan here?
Huh?
You gonna build
a big robot house?
Get yourself a big robot wife?
I'm going to enslave humanity and
force them to service my machines.
First, Green Hills.
Then the universe.
Then the multiverse.
Then who knows?
Maybe that'll be enough.
Full disclosure?
You won't be there.
Snot rocket!
No, no, no!
Giving up already?
Not so tough when you're fighting
someone 700 times your size, are ya?
You can't beat me!
I'm all-powerful! All-knowing!
All-seeing.
Looks like your fancy robot
has a glitch.
Is it me?
What about me? I'm over here.
Up top! Down below!
Behind you!
I'm
over here. Sorry! Over here.
Too slow! Try again.
You can't outsmart me.
Missed me again.
I'm the outsmarter-er!
Robotnik!
I am also a hologram.
Disloyal.
"Dis" is how I roll.
Where's my Emerald?
No, no, no, no!
Computer, auxiliary power.
Move, you hunk of junk!
Come on.
There he is! Go! Go, go, go!
No!
We got you, Sonic.
Hold on!
- You guys okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I got the Emerald.
We could still defeat him.
Come on, come on. How does
this thing work? What do I do?
What?
No. No, no, no!
Look at the happy little family.
No!
I got him!
I finally got him!
What was that?
It's over, Eggman.
I like the
new look. It works for you.
What do you say
we just let bygones be bygones?
I did some things,
you did some things.
There are good people
on both sides.
Surely two intelligent beings
can work these things out!
Come on, buddy.
Get him, Sonic! Come on.
Yeah. Come on.
It's like that?
Okay, we're not friends.
Later, hater!
Sonic! Buddy!
Mmm.
Oh, you got to try this.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Sonic! Whoa!
Bring it in, bud.
It's good to be back in blue.
Whoa! You fixed it.
I've spent my whole life
questing for this.
Now I have it.
Now we have it.
We must make a vow to use our
powers to keep the universe safe,
Oh, I know!
A power bump!
Good idea.
It's an Earth custom.
An unbreakable promise.
Very well.
A power bump it is.
Power bump!
It's truly a beautiful day
for baseball here
in Green Hills.
An exciting lineup today
with the debut appearance
of two new players!
On the mound,
rookie sensation from across the galaxy,
Miles "Tails" Prower,
facing off against the powerhouse,
Knuckles the Echidna.
Don't think about it too much.
Just keep your elbow up,
eye on the ball
and give it a ride.
Power bump!
Ha! Victory is mine!
Hey, no fair!
That shouldn't count.
First base is also mine!
I think that was our
only ball.
I have conquered
the second of the bases!
Who wants ice cream?
Knocked the cover off that.
Ice cream! Ice cream, yeah!
I'm proud of our little guy.
I really like his new friends,
especially the red one.
He cracks me up.
Heck of a swing too.
Come on, fox.
Our dessert adventure
awaits. Whoo!
Good job, guys. Yeah.
You too, baby.
Let's go get some ice cream.
Come on, come on.
I'm happy for you, pal.
Got your wingmen.
Perfect friends to grow up with.
Come on,
Knuckles. Ah! My victory chariot!
Race you to the truck.
One, two, three, go!
No, don't go easy on me.
I want your best.
Sonic, I have just been told
they have sprinkles.
Ice cream and sprinkles?
This is your new destiny.
What a perfect meal to celebrate
my victory over you in base of ball.
What? I mean,
you barely beat me.
Ha! You've never been
beaten so hard.
Agent, I want an update.
Still searching,
sir. We haven't found any sign of Robotnik.
No one could've
survived that crash.
He's toast. Good riddance.
What a mess that lunatic made.
Sir, there's something else.
When we were wiping Robotnik off
our database, we found something.
A file buried deep in our system
and dating back over 50 years.
What was it?
Coordinates, sir.
Coordinates? To what?
<i>A secret research facility.</i>
<i>It was a black site, sir.</i>
<i>Someone worked very hard
to keep this hidden.</i>
<i>Project Shadow.</i>