Thundershowers are
expected in the Crocodile Falls area
and some of the surrounding gullies,
so take out your...
COdyI
Yeah, Mom?
- What about your breakfast?
- I've got some sandwiches in my pack.
- Be home for supper.
- No worries, Mom.
I know, I'm coming.
Hustle up, Nelson.
Faloo's sounding the call!
Come on, little Wombats, hurry!
Who's caught this time?
You don't know her, Cody.
Her name is Marahute,
the great golden eagle.
Where is she?
She's caught, high on a cliff
in a poacher's trap.
- You're the only one who can reach her.
- I'll get her loose.
Righto. Hop on, no time to lose.
She's up on top of that ridge.
Be careful, little friend.
Marahute!
Calm down, calm down.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
That's a girl. Stay still.
It's okay.
No, wait! I'm here to help you.
Easy! Easy!
You're free!
Higher!
You're a mom!
They're very warm.
Are they gonna hatch soon?
Where's the daddy eagle?
My dad's gone, too.
Help! Someone, help!
McLeach took a little boy.
Send for help!
Code red, code red! Attention
all Rescue Aid Society delegates.
All delegates report immediately
to the main assembly hall.
This is an emergency meeting.
I repeat, this is a code red
emergency meeting!
Order!
Yes, I know it's late, but I'm...
Really? Pajamas?
Hello, Frank, how are you?
Nice to see you!
And Esmerelda, there you are!
Quiet now, please,
everyone pay attention.
There has been
a kidnapping in Australia.
A young boy needs our help.
This is a mission
requiring our very finest,
and I know we are all thinking
of the same two mice.
What's this? Gone?
We must find Bernard
and Miss Bianca at once!
Pea soup.
Pea soup!
To my dear Bernard,
and our wonderful partnership.
Yeah, wonderful.
You've been very quiet this evening.
ls there something on your mind?
Well, actually...
- I was wondering...
- Yes, darling?
I... Miss Bianca, would you...
Would you...
Would you excuse me for a minute?
Pardonnez-moi, Mademoiselle Bianca,
I have important news.
Yes, Frangois? What is it?
You and Bernard
have been asked to accept
a dangerous mission to Australia.
The poor boy. This is dreadful.
Now where is Bernard?
I must tell him at once!
Allow me, madame,
I will tell him immediately.
Miss Bianca, will you marry me?
Quickly, Monsieur Bernard!
I must speak with you.
- Not now, Frangois, I'm busy!
- No, monsieur, you don't...
- Bernard, did you talk to Frangois?
- Yes, but there's something I want...
I know what you're going to say.
Frangois told me about it.
He did? How did he...
it doesn't matter,
I think it's a marvelous idea.
You do?
I mean, you really want to?
I don't think it's a matter of wanting,
it's a matter of duty.
Duty? I never thought of it...
Well, all right.
How does next April sound to you?
Heavens, no!
We must act immediately, tonight!
Tonight? But wait!
Bianca, this is so sudden. I mean, don't
you at least need a gown or something?
No, just a pair of khaki shorts
and some hiking boots!
Hiking boots?
There you are.
Come along, come along.
Delegates, we have
an important announcement.
Bernard and I have decided
to accept the mission to Australia.
Australia?
Good show!
Now, you must fly out immediately!
It's a little nippy outside,
but we won't let that stop us, will we?
Miss Bianca,
I'm not sure it's a good idea
to fly this soon after eating!
Darling, you'll be just fine!
But aren't you supposed
to wait 45 minutes?
Just knock on the door
and see if Orville is there!
Nobody's home, let's go.
This is no time to play in the snow.
I wasn't playing in the snow.
It was an avalanche.
Look, Bernard!
"Under new management, see Wilbur."
Come on, darling. Let's get a move out!
I'm the cat's pajamas
Always run around
with crazy little mamas
Mr. Wilbur!
Get down there, son!
Hello?
Pick it, boy, pick it! Yeah!
Here we go! Let's walk!
Look out! Excuse me, sir.
Do something! He can't hear us!
Big time, big time!
The girls all look when I go by...
Who killed the music?
That's better.
Excuse us for interrupting.
We're from the Rescue Aid Society.
I am Miss Bianca, and this is my...
The Miss Bianca? I don't believe it.
My brother, Orville, told me all about
you. Boy. This is an honor to have...
May I just say, "Enchanté, sefiorita, "
to you? May I?
We need to charter a flight.
You've come to the right place,
buddy boy. Welcome to...
"Albatross Air.
A fair fare from here to there."
Get it? A fair fare?
It's a play on... Never mind.
I've got tons of exotic
destinations, faraway places,
custom designed for
a romantic weekend getaway.
The finest in-flight accommodations.
Speaking of which, what can I get you?
How about a nice mango Maui cooler?
Very nice, very tasty.
No, thank you.
A coconut, guava nectar?
It's carbonated.
I got little umbrellas for each one,
and a little coconut thing.
- It's urgent that we leave immediately!
- Nothing? Nothing at all?
- How about a cream soda?
- We need a flight to Australia.
Australia? The land down under?
That's a fabulous idea!
So when can I pencil you in?
After spring thaw?
Mid-June would be very nice.
We must leave tonight.
Tonight?
Come on, you're kidding me, right?
Have you looked outside?
It's suicide out there.
No. No.
I'm afraid yourjolly little holiday
will have to wait.
What a bunch of jokers.
But you don't understand,
a boy needs our help. He's in trouble.
Boy? You mean, a little kid kinda boy?
He was kidnapped.
Kidnapped? That's awful.
Locking up a little kid.
A kid should be free.
Free to run wild through the house
on Saturday mornings.
Free to have cookies and milk,
and get those little white mustaches.
Nobody's gonna take
a kid's freedom away while I'm around.
Does that mean you'll take us?
Storm or no storm,
Albatross Airlines, at your service!
Passengers are requested
to fasten their seat belts
and secure all carry-ens.
We'll be departing following our
pre-flight maintenance. Thank you.
Loosen up, get the blood flowing
up to the head.
And a couple of these...
Okay, one's enough, there we go.
Yeah! That feels better. Baby.
Tie your kangaroos down, sports fans!
Here we come!
Let's go for it! Hey!
I didn't adjust for the winds.
All right, we're gonna make it!
Gotta duck down lower.
Go under the wind, go under it!
Here we go!
This is cold!
Slippery! Ice!
We got ice!
Hang on now!
Here we go!
Cowabunga!
Captain, is this
a non-stop flight to Australia?
Well, not exactly no.
I could definitely say no.
We're gonna have to make
connections with a bigger bird.
Non-stop? What do I look like,
Charles Lindbergh?
Ladies and gentlemen, Flight 12
is now approaching Sydney airport.
Make sure your seat belts
are fastened and tables secured.
Enjoy your stay in Australia.
- Are we there yet?
- Yes.
Perhaps we should wake up Wilbur.
All right, I'll get him up.
Wilbur.
Wilbur!
Just five more minutes, Ma.
- Wilbur!
- That's all I need, five more minutes.
Wilbur, are you awake?
- Get up, we're there!
- I'm up, I'm up.
Watch out!
Must have been sleeping on a bolt.
Oh, boy.
Throw another shrimp on the barbie,
'cause here I come!
- Here we go again!
- Cannonball!
Gangway! Coming through.
Mice on board!
Clear the way!
Move over madam, there you go!
Coming through, sir. Thank you.
Next stop, Mugwomp Flats.
Did we lose anyone back there?
Miss Bianca, from now on,
can't we just take the train?
Well, Sparky,
you've had this coming for a long time.
And now, you're gonna get it.
Wise fly.
Mugwomp tower,
this is Albatross 1-3
requesting permission to land. Over?
Albatross? Let's see.
Finch, wren, scrub-bird, lorikeet,
freckled duck, galah,
Kookaburra, parrot,
cockatoo, alba... It's a jumbo!
Negative, you'll have to turn back.
- Our runway isn't long enough for you.
- Not long enough?
Look pal,
I can land this thing on a dime!
Wilbur,
if the runway isn't long enough...
You can't let radar jockeys
push you around. Leave it to me.
I say again, mate,
our runway is too short.
And I say again, mate, I'm coming in!
Crazy Yank. Quick, Sparky,
we gotta extend the runway.
Here we go!
We'll never make it!
Hot!
Passengers, please remain seated
until the aircraft comes
to a full and complete stop.
Thank you.
Quick, Sparky,
we need to make a drag line!
Don't try and tell me
the runway's too short.
Hold this for me, will you, pal?
Bloke ought to have his wings clipped.
Captain thanks you
for flying Albatross Airlines...
Crazy Yanks.
They think they can do any fool thing
without regard for...
Welcome to Australia, ma'am.
Name's Jake. If there's any way
I can make your stay pleasant,
don't hesitate to ask.
- How kind.
- Allow me to get that bag for you.
I've got a lot of luggage here.
Let me give you a hand with those.
Part of the friendly service
at Albatross...
Big time hurt!
Back! It's out!
- Are you all right?
- Don't worry, I'll handle this.
Sparky, watch the tower.
We gotta get this bird to the hospital.
Can't go down, can't go up.
Take the bags!
Now we just gotta
figure out how to get there.
So are you and your husband here
on a little outback excursion?
No, we're not married.
In fact, we're here
on a top secret mission.
Very hush-hush.
Gonna rescue that kid
McLeach nabbed?
Why, that's right! How did you know?
You'll find it's tough
to keep secrets in the outback, miss.
So which way you taking?
Suicide Trail through Nightmare
Canyon, or shortcut at Satan's Ridge?
-"Suicide Trail"?
- Good choice.
More snakes, less quicksand.
Then once you cross Bloodworm Creek,
you're scat-free, that is until...
Dead Dingo Pass.
Wait a minute, I don't see
any of that stuff on the map.
A map's no good in the outback!
What you really need is someone
who knows the territory.
Mr. Jake, will you guide us?
At your service!
Better take my arm, miss.
It's gonna be a treacherous hike.
I remember the time it was just me
and 400 of these big, giant...
Doesn't even know how to fold a map.
This is how we get around
in the outback, Miss B.
The only way to travel, Berno.
Yeah, it's just a little bumpy back here.
Cinch up your seat belts, mates.
We're coming in for a landing.
Hold it, not yet!
Maybe I should go...
Maybe I should go look for him.
Don't you worry about Jake.
He can handle himself.
Yeah, I noticed.
I am just sure he'll be back in no time.
You know,
now that we're alone, there's...
There's something that
I've been wanting to ask you.
Yes? What is it?
Well, it's like this.
Miss Bianca, I would be most honored
if...
Look out!
No mice for you, Twister, not today!
There!
Miss Bianca!
I've been looking all over for you.
Now look.
We got a long way to go,
and you're gonna take us there.
You're not gonna give us
any trouble about it.
Right?
Jake's been gone...
They're harmless once you look them
in the eye, let them know who's boss.
Been gone a long time.
Ain't that right, mate? Now get.
It's all right, Bernard.
Jake has everything under control.
Yeah, I noticed.
You know, Miss Bianca, truth be told,
I used to be quite a dingo wrestler.
There was this one time,
it was just me and 300
of these ferocious,
mouse-eating dingoes.
Had me surrounded...
Show him who's boss, Berno!
Okay, you guys, she fell for it.
Looks like the coast is clear.
Girls? Girls, I'm here!
Where are you, you little chickees, you?
Wilbur?
Wilbur!
Don't ever do that to me again!
Boy, I lost a lot of feathers on that one.
Wilbur, am I glad to see you!
- Help me with these eggs, will you?
- Sure.
Wait a minute, what the heck
are you doing up here?
The kidnapper took the boy and Jake.
Miss Bianca.
Miss Bianca's in trouble?
That's terrible! We gotta do something!
Bernard, I'm disappointed in you.
Hiding under a nest
while Bianca needs help.
- I gotta talk to you, mister.
- Wilbur.
You should start searching the desert
for her, and I'll scan the coastline!
That's what I'll do.
Ask the chicks on the beach.
What?
Listen! There's some chicks
here that need help.
Really?
No. Wait a minute. Hold it.
I know what you're thinking,
and you're wrong. Don't even, no.
Don't look at me! You're getting "no."
Understand?
I will not ever sit on those eggs!
Nuts!
Gotta learn to be more assertive.
No is no is no.
Hey, quit moving in there!
Oh, my gosh!
Excuse me.
Look, I've got a long way to go,
you're going to take me there,
and you're not going
to give me any trouble, right?
Good.
NOW, get!
Help! Help!
It's okay.
Come on.
Thanks, little mate.
Bernard, you are magnificent.
You are absolutely the hero of the day.
Miss Bianca,
before anything else happens,
-will you marry me?
- Bernard.
Of course, I will!
Well done, mate.
Come on, Marahute, let's all go home.
Help!
Anybody!
Bernard!
Bianca!
Where are you?
Okay, that's it, I'm out of here.
This is ridiculous.
You can't leave me here alone.
I'm gone! I am gone.
No, stay in those eggs!
That's a direct order!
Hey, you're kind of a cute little feller.