Every night, the same dream,
the same strange planet.
But why?
What are they trying to tell me?
It's been 34 years
since they arrived on this planet.
And not a day passes
that the survivors...
...forced to live in barrier cities,
do not live in fear.
I have vowed to end that fear.
I believe my dreams hold the key.
The question is, will I be
in time to save the Earth?
Where are you?
This is a restricted area.
Do not move!
- What's she doing here captain?
- I don't know, but we're getting her out.
- You're coming with us.
- Behind you!
Hold it right there!
Damn it. Let's move, people!
Two coming through the wall!
Hold your fire.
Those tanks are flammable!
Ryan, Neil, let's go!
Captain, the transport is not going
to wait for us much longer.
- I understand that.
- It's in bad shape.
I need a minute to extract it.
Miss. That's a minute we do not have.
I'm afraid he's right about that ma'am.
Phantoms! We have incoming.
Everyone, up top!
Go, go, go!
- Transport, requesting immediate evac.
- Affirmative.
Up here!
- Captain! - They're right
behind you! - Captain, come on!
I've got you!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
All right, everybody, here they come.
You okay?
- Welcome back, captain.
- We're clean.
- Let's make sure of that shall we?
Yes, sir.
- Yes, sir.
Okay, next.
You know, my security rating
allows me to bypass this.
Not today it doesn't.
Something's not right.
- About this mission? Or that woman?
- Both.
Next.
Oh shit!
- Captain!
- They got him.
There must be a mistake.
You came in contact with a Phantom sir.
Please remain calm.
Administering treatment shield.
- What level is he?
- Blue. It will be code red in 3-1/2 minutes.
We have to treat him. Now!
I'm sorry, but that's impossible.
We'll transfer him to the treatment center.
There's no time for that.
Get him to the table.
Hang in there, captain.
Locating pathogens.
Jesus, look at that thing!
- How much more time?
- Not enough.
When he reaches code red,
the treatment shield won't be
able to hold the alien particles.
Engaging bio-etheric laser.
We've lost contact.
Infestation is moving deeper.
His treatment shield is failing.
Found it.
Come on.
It's all right.
Don't worry.
You'll be back to normal in no time.
Uh.. Doctor, we need
to scan you for infestation.
That won't be necessary.
I'll take responsibility.
Hey, doc.
Thanks for saving him.
It's a match. We've found it.
Yes.
The sixth spirit.
It seemed today you broke
nearly every protocol.
How long do you think this would
have survived outside the barrier?
Aki, you know there are
elements in the council and
military just waiting for
an excuse to shut us down.
If we attack the meteor with this, we will
eliminate the Phantoms at their source.
General Hein, calm down.
At our last meeting, We voted 6 to 2...
...to postpone using the Zeus cannon
to attack the Leonid Meteor.
We have re-convened today to vote
on that very issue again.
Now, I'd like to ask the director
of the Bio-Etheric Center to speak.
- Dr. Sid, please.
- Thank you.
As you all know, the Phantoms' nest
is in the Leonid Meteor...
...that landed here 34 years ago.
What you see now are the records
of every assault on the meteor to date.
Physical attacks have had
utterly no effect.
This scene took place three months ago
during a full-scale bombardment.
Now please note the Phantoms outside
the meteor are indeed destroyed.
However, inside, many that
were dormant come to life...
...and as you see,
overall Phantom density remains the same.
The newly risen aliens
respond to the attack...
...by burrowing even
deeper into the Earth.
Now, this is very interesting to me Dr. Sid...
...because we see
the same thing during surgery...
...when using bio-etheric lasers
on Phantom particles, do we not?
Yes, indeed we do.
You see. the injured particles escape...
...burying or digging themselves deeper
into a patient's body.
And when we increase the laser power
to destroy these deeper particles...
...we have had incidents resulting in
further injury to a patient...
...and in some cases...
...death.
And what exactly does that mean doctor?
It means there's a very good chance...
...the beam from the Zeus cannon
will burn the Phantoms in the meteor.
Exactly! Thank you.
However, it also means that
the beam energy may be too strong...
...injuring the Earth.
Injure the Earth?
You mean the Gaia.
- I mean...
- You mean the spirit of the Earth.
Yes, the spirit of the Earth.
Did he say what I think he said?
What are you doing?
I know what I'm doing and
whatever you do, keep your mouth shut.
This is ridiculous.
Dr. Sid, the Gaia theory
has not been proven.
Even if Gaia does exist, won't we
still have to remove the Phantoms?
I think if there's any chance of success,
we should take it.
- Don't you agree?
- Well, of course i do.
But there is an alternative
to the space cannon.
Another method?
- Yes. A means of disabling the Phantoms.
- Please.
As we know, the aliens display
a distinct energy pattern.
Now, it is a fact that
two opposing bio-etheric waves...
...placed one over the other
will cancel each other out.
It is theoretically possible
to construct a wave pattern...
...in direct opposition
to the Phantom energy.
We are currently assembling such
a wave and are nearing completion.
Members of the council...
...gathering plants and animals...
...from around the world to fight
the Phantoms is utter nonsense.
The Zeus cannon is a proven,
effective weapon.
It will kill Phantoms.
Can we afford to wait
for some crazy invention...
...some army of
touchy-feely plants and animals...
...An invention that offers no solid evidence
that it will destroy the aliens?
There is evidence!
Our partially completed energy wave...
...has successfully stopped
Phantom particles from spreading...
...through a terminally-infected patient.
Doctor, do you claim to have evidence
that a terminal patient has been cured?
Not cured. The wave is not complete.
But we've succeeded in containing the
particles safely inside the patient.
You may have bought us some time Aki,
but i wonder at what cost?
Doctor, I can't keep hiding
in the background while you protect me.
I want what life I have left
to mean something.
Will you listen to me? When we find
the seventh and eighth spirits...
If we find them.
What we need now is some luck.
Luck has nothing to do with it.
Faith and hard work, girl...
...coz I'll be damned if
you're going to die before me.
Captain Edwards...
...you extracted a Dr. Ross from
Old New York several days ago did you not?
- Yes, sir.
- What were your impressions of Dr. Ross?
She seemed very capable and determined, sir.
You and the Deep Eyes are being
temporarily reassigned.
You will guard Dr. Ross
when she reenters the wasteland.
- Understood, sir.
- You don't understand yet, captain.
Report any aberrant behavior
in Dr. Ross to the major immediately.
Aberrant behavior sir?
The woman carries an alien infestation, captain.
We don't know what it may be doing to her.
The alien presence could be affecting her judgment.
They may be manipulating the doctor
for their very own purposes.
She's had prolonged exposure
to Phantom tissue.
If this begins to manifest itself in any way...
...Dr. Ross is to be placed under arrest
and transported here for observation.
It is, in fact, for her own good, captain.
Of course, sir.
I'm convinced that these dreams
are some form of communication.
Their message still eludes me...
...but they're coming faster now
and that can only mean one thing.
The Phantoms inside me are beginning to win.
Our target is 50 klicks west of Tucson.
- Roger.
- Phantom concentration?
Not good. We've got big metas everywhere.
So it's gonna be a real picnic.
Stick close to me. No heroics today. Okay?
Everything by the book.
By the book. Right.
If we drop energy buoys here,
here and here...
...we should be able to
land, acquire the target,
and get out before the Phantoms
even know we were there.
And the buoys will attract the Phantoms?
- Yeah.
- For a while.
So you're from the 307th's right?
Under General Hein?
Ever done wasteland recon before?
It can get pretty ugly.
Captain, rendezvous for evac at
vector 6, coordinate 279.
Roger that. Stay alert for hostiles.
Looks like they've taken the bait.
The seventh spirit should be
just beyond that line of wreckage.
I don't see how any living thing
could survive out here?
We'll find out soon enough.
This was the Phantom Cleansing Mission.
It was supposed to end the war.
My father's in here somewhere.
All right.
Let's move out, people.
I'll be damned.
A survivor.
What's it doing out here?
Hoping for life to return.
Is that our spirit, doc?
No.
We're closing in on the life form.
- Distance?
- Hard to say. We're very close.
I don't see anything.
- You're not gonna tell me it's him?
- That's impossible.
It's not the soldier. It's his ovo-pac.
How do you explain that? The pacs power
our weapons, the barrier cities...
I mean it's just bio-etheric energy.
And to create that energy we use
living tissue. Single-cell organisms.
- You're telling me his backpack is the seventh spirit?
- Yes.
We have incoming. Captain? Do you read me?
- Captain?
- What? Say again?
You read me captain? We have incoming.
Ryan, get the soldier's pac.
I need a hand! Sarge!
- Those buoys? They're not working.
- Yeah.
- Are you all right?
- Of course I am.
Let's get the hell out of here!
Something's not right.
This shouldn't be happening.
Something's attracting them.
Aki!
- They're right on us, sir. Closing in fast!
- Jane, take the lead.
Fire in the hole!
Get us out of here, Neil.
- Sir, I would love to, but...
- Just do it!
- Sir?
- It's okay, that's it.
That doesn't look good, captain.
We have to get her to a hospital.
- You have your orders, sir.
- What the hell is going on here?
Dr. Ross is to be taken into custody now, sir.
Lower your weapons. That's an order!
Sir. We have no choice,
but to relieve you of your command.
I won't let you do this soldier.
You'll gonna have to shoot me.
Stand down, captain!
Hang on, everyone!
That's enough.
Hands where I can see them. Everyone now!
Deep Eyes, hard to starboard!
The Deep Eyes are returning
from the wasteland, sir.
Apparently, there was an incident.
It would seem the Phantoms
were attracted to Dr. Ross.
The crew barely escaped with their lives.
And sir, Captain Edwards is still in command.
Issue an order.
I want Edwards and Dr. Ross
placed under arrest.
All research materials pertaining
to Dr. Sid's wave theory...
...are to be confiscated immediately.
That might not go over
too well with the council, sir.
What a tragedy that would be.
This is perfect, major.
The good captain has opened the door for us.
By tomorrow morning,
the council will be at our feet...
...thanking us for exposing
the traitors and imploring us...
...to save them from the Phantoms.
How is she, doctor?
- She is dying.
- There must be something you can do.
Aki is fighting with
only six of the eight spirits.
We'll have to implant the seventh
directly into her chest plate.
It took a bullet.
I think it might be damaged.
We have to repair this panel quickly.
Her vital signs are dropping.
Aki is slipping away from us.
She needs a sympathetic spirit
to help hold her in this world.
And I can think of no spirit better suited
for that task than yours, captain.
- I don't understand.
- You don't have to understand.
You just be with her now.
You keep her here with us.
Aki? Where are we?
On an alien planet.
How is that possible?
I'm not entirely sure.
You seem pretty calm.
I've been having this dream
every night for months.
Dream?
Well, whatever it is.
You're really here, aren't you?
What's happening to me?
Dr. Sid is implanting the seventh spirit
directly into your body.
Something you should see here, sir.
And I am watching what, major?
It seems Dr. Ross has been recording her dreams.
And why would I be interested in...
...her dreams?
This is it. This is our evidence.
She's under the influence of the Phantoms.
Dr. Ross' dreams should be all the council needs
to authorize the firing of the Zeus cannon.
The council is content to hide
powering inside this barrier...
...while the world dies a little more every day.
I believe they need a push
in the right direction, major.
Get together a group of your most trusted men.
What are they doing.
Why are they staring at us?
Not at us.
Welcome back, captain.
Is it over?
How is she, doctor?
She's gonna be fine.
But this is only temporary.
We'll need to find the eighth
and final spirit to cure her.
Aki, can you hear me?
I finished it.
I know what it means.
I know what the Phantoms really are.
Nobody move! You're all under arrest!
We have them, sir.
Sir?
My wife and daughter...
...were killed by Phantoms in the
San Francisco Barrier City was attacked.
Did I ever tell you that?
You've lost family, haven't you?
Yes, sir.
That's why I trust you.
You know what must be done.
Security override.
Perimeter breached.
Major, arrest these men.
- Take it easy.
- Stand up. Go.
You are relieved of your post.
Don't ask any questions.
Reduce power to Sector 31.
Sir, you do realize that the Phantoms...
What I realize, major...
...is that we must force the council
to take action against the enemy.
25% of energy pipe alpha redirected.
Lowering power output to Sector 31.
Barrier breached in Sector 31, general.
They're coming through now.
Oh I think we can easily handle
a few Phantoms in a contained space.
Relax, major. When this night's over,
you're going to be a hero.
Alright. Why do you think
we've never been able to determine...
...a relationship between the human-sized Phantoms
and the giant ones roaming the wastelands?
He's right. If you've spent as much time
in the field as we had...
...you know there is no relationship.
It's like a zoo out there.
Precisely. I think the giant ones are
like our whales or elephants.
But why would an invading army bring
a bunch of whales and elephants along for the ride?
Unless their ship was kind of
a crazy Noah's Ark?
We have always assumed that the meteor...
...was intended as a form of transportation.
Perhaps it wasn't.
The meteor is a chunk of their planet
that got thrown into space...
...when they destroyed their world.
But how could they survive the trip
across outer space on a hunk of rock?
They didn't.
I think that explains why we never had a chance.
All our strategies are based on one assumption:
That we were fighting alien invaders.
Think of the dream, Gray. How they died.
Since then, all they've known is suffering.
They're not an invading army.
They're ghosts.
How many Phantoms?
More than enough to convince the council, sir.
Excellent. Sound an alert. Send
a squad out to eliminate them.
Yes sir.
Alert status. Full deployment.
Sir. I have numerous Phantom contacts!
Well, of course you do.
Outside of Sector 31, sir.
And moving at incredible speed.
Major, What the hell is going on here?
They're in the pipes.
They're moving with the bio-etheric energy flow.
That's impossible. No living thing
could survive in those pipes.
Well, we've got a big one heading this way.
Meta class, sir.
Oh, my God.
Hold your fire!
What have I done?
- Here they come.
- But the others! Dr. Sid!
Deep Eyes'll take care of him.
Come on.
What's happening. Why can we see them now?
They must be carrying a residual charge
from passing through the barrier.
Behind you!
All aboard, captain!
We need to find my ship.
If it was towed inside the city,
it would be in the military hangar.
That's a big "if. "
Look out!
- Get us onto the platform.
- You got it.
Hang on, everybody!
- Captain.
Oh, God. Talk to me, sarge.
Ouch!
- Give me a hand, Jane.
- Right.
No wait! We're risking further injury.
We need the proper tools to cut him out.
They're in my ship.
- No. No, doc. No drugs.
- Captain?
You heard the man.
We'll find the ship and be back for you.
- I'll stay with him.
- Me too.
Nobody's staying.
- Just give me a gun.
- You got it.
Give him a weapon. Do it!
We'll be back for you, sergeant.
You hear me?
I hear you, captain.
Now, get out of here.
Let's move out.
A quad-axle ATV. This is good.
It can be used to retrieve Ryan
and transport him safely here.
However, we'll need to replace
these spent fuel cells.
There could be some live ovo-pacs in the hangar.
Gray, be careful.
You too.
Oh, yeah.
Neil, do you read me?
Loud and clear, captain.
This baby'll fly itself.
Flight path is set.
Beginning rotation.
Stop the airtray. We have a problem.
I'm reading an impound tractor
attached probably to the ship.
There's the problem.
The controls are locked, naturally.
What's happening down there?
Nothing we can't handle.
- Neil, what's your status?
- Almost there.
I want you two back inside.
We're fine, sir. Jane is negotiating
with extreme prejudice.
Talk to me, Jane.
No problem here, captain.
Yes! Captain, we are good to go.
Jane, get out of there.
Get out of there now! Go! Jane!
Get the hell out of there!
Over here, you son of a bitch!
Gray, come on!
I enlarged the scanning perimeter...
...to include an area that
we had previously overlooked.
The impact crater.
That's a strange place to find the eighth spirit.
Yes, really quite astonishing.
But nothing could survive in there except Phantoms.
Precisely.
Which suggests that
the eighth spirit is a Phantom spirit.
I can't explain it at the moment,
but once we get down there...
- ... you will understand...
- Wait, doctor. That's a one-way trip.
Yes, I expected that's how
you would evaluate our chances.
Well, am I wrong?
No, I agree. We probably...
...won't live long enough to extract
the eighth spirit from the crater.
Then why should we even try it?
Because we don't need to extract the eighth spirit.
If we can't bring the final spirit here...
...we can go there and complete
the wave inside the crater.
Yes, exactly.
And how do we do that, exactly?
I can construct a device that...
...would attach to Aki's chest plate
to gather the eighth spirit and then...
And then what?
And then we wait
and see what happens.
What caused the barrier
to fail, General Hein?
I'm afraid it was
only a matter of time...
...before the Phantoms developed
an immunity to our barriers.
But I am relieved to see that you
and the rest of the council...
...were able to evacuate to Houston without incident.
It was a terrible loss suffered this evening.
The council has reconsidered
your proposal to fire the Zeus cannon.
I see.
We are transmitting the access codes to you now.
And, general...
...best of luck to us all.
Prepare to fire the cannon.
The target, sir?
The Phantom crater.
Preparing to drop in three, two, one.
Powering the shield.
Okay, we're over the meteor.
Do you have it in sight, doctor?
There are so many of them.
Wait.
Yes! I'm tracking the eighth spirit
moving along the crater's surface.
All right. Now let's take a closer look.
Ready to fire in three minutes.
Ovo-pacs at maximum.
Transferring plasma flow to auto.
Counter-thrusters are engaged.
Lox flow de-coupled. Status is green.
We have something on radar
over the impact site, sir.
It's her.
Sir?
Just a traitor under
the influence of the enemy.
Continue the countdown.
We'll take them all out at the same time.
We're closing on the Phantom.
Contact in 30 seconds.
Target locked.
Ready to fire on your command.
It's a match! It's a perfect match!
- Target scanners ready, sir.
- Fire.
What was that?
It's the Zeus. They're firing on the crater.
- Aki, Captain, are you all right?
- A little shaken. Stand by.
Sid, the eighth spirit is not
on our scanner. Do you have it?
The eighth spirit...
...has been destroyed.
- What are we going to do now?
- Nothing. This mission is over.
- We have to get out of here.
- Incoming!
What is that?
If you're getting us out of here,
you better do it now.
Hold on!
I can't hold on to you.
Unable to maintain altitude.
Initiate emergency landing procedures.
Come in. Come in, please.
Aki, Gray, can you hear me?
Sid, I need to talk to the station.
Can you patch us through?
- What is that thing?
- I don't know, sir.
Incoming message, sir.
General Hein,
You must cease fire immediately.
What you are looking at in the crater is the
living spirit of an alien's home world.
Their planet was destroyed
and part of it landed here.
This is not an invasion. It never was.
I see and what have we been fighting
all this time, doctor? Ghosts?
Yes. Spirits that are confused,
lost and angry.
Right. And these spirits are
coming out of this Gaia thing.
General Hein, you have to listen.
Alien Gaia, Earth Gaia.
Doctor, even if I believed in such nonsense...
...the fact remains the Earth
is under attack from an aggressor...
...who must be destroyed at all costs.
The cost may be the entire planet, sir.
Firing on the alien Gaia will only make it stronger.
Well, since you're under the alien's influence, doctor,
I will take your protest to mean that we are...
...in fact pursuing the correct course of actions.
So i suggest you take your last few moments
and prepare to meet your Gaia.
Continue to fire until the invader has been destroyed.
General, the system is overheating, sir.
We're going to hit it again and again
and keep on hitting it until it's dead.
But, sir. We're not even sure
if it's having any effect on the creature.
No effect? We've got them on the run, soldier.
This is our moment of victory. I order you to fire.
- The system won't allow us to fire again.
- We'll see about that.
Our shield is out. We're sitting ducks in here.
Come on!
This is not a good place to be.
Hey, are you all right?
I'm fine. I have to talk to Dr. Sid.
Sid, do you read me?
Go ahead, I'm still here.
We're looking at Gaia.
Do you hear me, Sid? Gaia.
I think this explains why
the eighth spirit appeared here.
Yes.
Yes, that's it!
A Phantom must have changed into the eighth spirit...
...when it touched a new life born from our own Gaia.
If so, it would've been given
a different energy signature...
...that set it apart from the other Phantoms.
You two could not have hoped
for a better location...
...to find a new compatible spirit.
Whatever you do, don't move.
Stay right where you are.
Staying right where we are
may not be as easy as it sounds.
Don't shoot any of them!
You could very well destroy our last hope.
And what do you suggest I do, doctor?
Ask them to play nice?
Combat strategy is your area
of expertise, captain, not mine.
I have a reading here in the fissure.
Do you see it?
Yes! A compatible spirit.
It must be very near you.
Well? Which one is it? Which one?
I'm having difficulty narrowing it down.
Just a moment, please.
Doctor, it's getting crowded in here.
Aki, we don't have much time. Aki.
With the hope of new life...
...has Gaia changed
the Phantom within?
I have it.
Gray, get in here. I need you!
Do you hear me, Sid?
The wave pattern is complete.
Yes, I read you. This is wonderful.
I don't see how you could have found the final spirit.
It found me, doctor.
Oh, my word.
I hope you know
what you're doing, Aki.
- We can use the shield to project the wave.
- What?
Dr. Sid's theory was right.
I have it. The eighth spirit.
That's it. Shield on.
I'll blast you all to hell.
Oh, no. No!
Get down!
I know!
But it must be done.
Fire.
Fire, damn you!
Fire!
Don't leave me, Gray.
Told Sid this was a one-way trip.
Looks like I was right.
No, Gray. Hang on, please.
I still have the wave.
We can get through this.
Help me.
Listen to me.
You saved my life once.
Now I want you to save yourself.
Gray, no. Please?
Let me do this, Aki. Trust me.
I love you.
Oh, it's warm.