<i>They are an army unlike any other...</i>
<i>crusading across the stars
toward a place called UnderVerse,</i>
<i>their promised land...</i>
<i>a constellation of dark new worlds.</i>
<i>Necromongers, they're called.</i>
<i>And if they cannot convert you,
they will kill you.</i>
<i>Leading them, the Lord Marshal.</i>
<i>He alone has made a pilgrimage
to the gates of the UnderVerse...</i>
<i>and returned a different being.</i>
<i>Stronger. Stranger.</i>
<i>Half alive and half...</i>
<i>something else.</i>
Linin' him up for you. Port-side
shot comin' up. Steady. Here we go.
Steady.
<i>Take it. Take it!</i>
Take the shot!
Shit!
Toombs, we're runnin' out of road!
Shut up! I got it! Again!
Now!
Toombs!
Riddick.
<i>Three meters clearance port-side.
One and a half meters starboard.</i>
We got a choke point comin' up.
<i>What the shit was that?</i>
Tags, you got eyes on Riddick?
Tags?
Jesus.
He just ghosted two guys,
and I never even saw him.
What do you think, Toombs?
I mean, maybe we oughta just...
I think you're my new gunner.
Grab a Gat.
Stay on top of him this time.
<i>You made three mistakes.</i>
First, you took the job.
Second, you came light.
<i>A four-man crew for me?
Fuckin' insulting.</i>
<i>But the worst mistake you made...</i>
<i>Empty gun rack.</i>
- What's the bounty on my head?
- One mil.
- One-point-five.
- What slam pays 1.5 for a convict?
Private party.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Guy, guy! Easy! Anonymous.
- That's what the sheet said.
- What planet?
Helion Prime.
Whoa. Where you going'?
Last question.
And you better get this one right, merc.
Whose ship is this?
Mine?
Wrong Answer
<i>Knew they'd come for me.</i>
<i>Took 'em five years, but I knew.</i>
<i>You don't expect these mercs
to have any honor, any code.</i>
<i>But this new bounty from a holy man,</i>
<i>a guy whose neck I saved...</i>
<i>Well, lesson learned.</i>
<i>No such word as "friend. "</i>
<i>It can only end bad
when you let someone get too close.</i>
<i>Bad for them.</i>
<i>So now it's back to civilization</i>
<i> all the brightness...
and everything I hate.</i>
Just wanted to be left alone
<i>Helion Prime is on alert condition four.</i>
<i>Unrecognized craft. You need to follow me
to Spaceport Six for security inspections.</i>
<i>Hey! Do you hear me?</i>
<i>Follow me to Spaceport Six now!</i>
Imam, pray for us.
<i>It was confirmed
two seasons back. Yes.</i>
<i>They're coming here.
I mean, are we next?</i>
<i>Militants storm...</i>
<i>Yes. But going to the underground
shelters if it happens...</i>
<i>You're right.
That's what I thought too.</i>
<i>Are you staying or leaving?</i>
<i>It's the end of everything.
Everything!</i>
<i>Well, my neighbours...
Half my street is gone.</i>
What are we gonna do?
I don't know. I don't know.
<i>Hood of the devil.
That's what someone called 'em.</i>
Them? Who is them?
Some kind of new creature...
This is nonsense.
It's all nonsense.
<i>So tall that it touches the clouds.</i>
And there's nothing around this
statue, this colossus. Nothing left.
It's their calling card.
<i>Did you know all your doors were locked?</i>
<i>Five years ago,</i>
<i>I took two people off that planet...</i>
<i>A kid, Jack,
who everyone else thought was a boy,</i>
<i>and a holy man...</i>
<i>searching for New Mecca.</i>
<i>I told one man...</i>
where I might go.
I showed trust to one man.
Did I make a mistake, Imam?
There is no simple answer.
Whatever was said
was meant to give us a chance...
a fighting chance.
Were it not for the threat of invasion,
I never would have betrayed you.
So now who do I have to kill
to get this payday off my head?
<i>It is said the comet
always precedes them...</i>
these world-enders.
The Coalsack planets are gone.
<i>Eight million settlers missing.</i>
<i>The entire Aquilan System is gone too.</i>
Helion Prime shares its sunlight
with all worlds nearby.
If we fall, they fall.
And after that...
My God,
how do I save my family?
<i>Have you heard anything I've said?</i>
You said it's all circling the
drain... the whole universe.
<i>- Right?
- That's right.</i>
Had to end sometime.
The one you want is now here.
And whose throat is this?
If you cut my throat, I'll not be able to
rescind the offer that brought you here.
Nor tell you why it's so vital
that you did come.
The blade comes off
when the bounty comes off.
This is Aereon,
an envoy from the Elemental race.
She means you no harm.
There are very few of us who have met
a Necromonger and lived to speak of it.
Necromonger.
It is the name that will convert
or kill every last human life...
<i>There is a story, Riddick,
of young male Furyans...</i>
strangled at birth...
strangled with their own cords.
When Aereon told this story
to the Helion leaders,
I told her of you.
- What do you know of your early years?
- Do you remember your home world?
- Where it was?
- Have you met any others?
Others like yourself.
Sister, they don't know
what to do with just one of me.
<i>Open up in there!</i>
<i>- Stand back!
- Open up!</i>
I will send them away.
But wait one minute, please.
<i>Will you wait one minute
to save worlds?</i>
Not my fight.
So, you will leave us
to our fate,
<i>just like you did her.</i>
<i>Break it down!</i>
Get him!
Come. Let us try to send them away.
<i>Move it. Come on.
Leave us alone!</i>
There is no one here!
<i>You don't understand.
He can help us! He can help us!</i>
<i>Go!</i>
You're not afraid of the dark, are you?
<i>- Get him!
- Where is he?</i>
In there!
You mentioned her.
She, uh...
She went looking for you.
People died.
She went to prison.
I... I don't remember where.
But it was a world so hot
you could not survive on the surface.
- Crematoria.
- Young Jack.
She thought of you
as her older brother.
- She worshipped you.
- You were supposed to watch her.
<i>She never forgave you...</i>
for leaving just when
she needed you most.
She needed to stay away
from me.
You all do
Furyans.
Defiant to the end.
No, no.
We go to the shelter.
We take only ourselves.
Stay close.
<i>No!</i>
<i>Flight leaders, get all squads
off the ground now.</i>
<i>We have heavy inbound.</i>
<i>Follow me in!</i>
The next shelter.
This way!
Yeah!
<i>Whoo-hoo!</i>
I'll see if it's safe.
- Stay back!
- Come, Ziza.
Come!
Lajjun and Ziza!
- When it's over.
- Let me go. I must get to my family!
When it's over.
Aah!
In here.
Get in.
Shh.
<i>- Imam!
- Don't follow me.</i>
There will be
an afterlife for me.
Will there be for you?
Let's go replenish the ranks.
In this 'verse,
life is antagonistic
to the natural state.
<i>Here, humans in all
their various races...</i>
are a spontaneous outbreak...
an unguided mistake.
Our purpose...
is to correct that mistake.
Because there is another 'verse...
a 'verse where life
is welcomed and cherished.
<i>A ravishing, ever-new place
called UnderVerse.</i>
<i>So it is this 'verse
that must be cleansed of life,</i>
so that UnderVerse
can populate and prosper.
<i>Look around you.
Every Necromonger in this hall,</i>
every one of the Legion Vast that just
swept aside your defenses in one night...
was once like you.
Fought as feebly as you.
Every Necromonger
that lives today...
is a convert.
- There'll be no conversions!
- We all began as something else!
It was hard for me to accept, too,
when I first heard these words.
But I changed.
I let them take away my pain.
- You betrayed your faith!
- Just as you will change...
<i>when you realize that the threshold
to the UnderVerse will be crossed...</i>
<i>only by those who have
embraced the Necromonger faith.</i>
For those of you
who will right now...
drop to your knees
and ask to be purified.
- We will not renounce our faith!
- No one here will do what you ask.
It is unthinkable!
<i>This is a world of many peoples,
many religions!</i>
And we simply cannot
and will not be converted!
Then I'll take your soul.
<i>Join him...</i>
Or join me.
This is your one chance.
Take the Lord Marshal's offer
and bow.
I bow to no man.
He's not a man.
He's the holy Half-Dead
who has seen the UnderVerse.
Look, I'm not
with everyone here.
But I will take a piece of him.
A piece you will have.
<i>Stop him!</i>
Irgun. One of my best.
If you say so.
What do you think of this blade?
I think it's a half-gram heavy
on the back end.
In our faith,
you keep what you kill.
Are you familiar to me?
Have we met
on some distant field?
You'd think I'd remember.
You'd think I would too.
Take him before the Quasi-Deads.
Beautiful eyes.
Come.
The last six Lord Marshals
have called this home.
Magnificent, isn't it?
- I might have gone a different way.
- True of us all.
<i>Converts receiving the mark
of the Necromonger.</i>
They learn how one pain
can lessen another.
There now.
That is just... perfect.
The more you resist them,
the greater the damage will be.
<i>A new one.</i>
<i>You've brought us a new one.</i>
Interesting breeder.
<i>Making entry.</i>
<i>We've entered his neocortex.</i>
<i>- Ahh! The Riddick!
- Regress.</i>
<i>Scanning fresh memories.</i>
<i>Thoughts of someone called Jack.</i>
Riddick!
<i>Now we find thoughts of an Elemental.</i>
<i>The one race that would slow
the spread of Necromongers.</i>
<i>- Furyans.
- Furyans.</i>
Where does he come from?
Who are his people?
These are the things I need to know.
<i>We find energy.</i>
<i>We find Furyan energy.</i>
<i>-He's Furyan!</i>
<i>Furyan!</i>
<i>A Furyan survivor!</i>
<i>Kill the Furyan! Kill the Riddick!</i>
<i>Kill the Riddick! Kill the Riddick!
Kill the Riddick!</i>
Kill the Riddick.
Find him. Whatever it takes. Find him!
Let me guess.
A five-man crew this time.
Couple of things
you could have done better.
First, trash the locator beacon
inside my ship... the one you jacked.
<i>And second... and this is really
the more important part...</i>
dust my dick
when you get the chance.
- Any questions?
- Yeah.
What took you so long?
<i>Decoy launched.</i>
In and out, unsuspected and undetected.
Damn, I love a good smash-and-grab.
Not so fast. Not so fast.
<i>- Preparing to engage ion drive.
- So,</i>
where do we drop
your merc-killin' ass?
<i>Who's gonna pay
the most for you now?</i>
- Butcher Bay?
- Butcher Bay.
Ten minutes every other day
on the dog run.
Protein waffles aren't bad.
Hey, how 'bout Ursa Luna?
Nice little double-max prison.
They keep a cell open for me...
just in case I drop in.
<i>You know the problem
with these joints now?</i>
Health clubs
for waffle-eatin' pussies.
Maybe we should think about
uppin' our game here a little bit.
Think about someplace
truly diabolical.
What the hell is he thinkin' now?
<i>He's thinkin' a triple-max prison.</i>
<i>A no-daylight slam.
Only three of 'em left in this system...</i>
two of 'em outta range for a shitty little
under cutter like this one with no legs.
Leavin' just... one...
Crematoria.
That is what you had in mind,
right, Toombs?
Hey, how does he know where we're goin',
and we don't?
Dope it out.
I hate this run.
Just do it!
Don't know about this
new crew of yours.
They seem a bit skittish.
Probably shouldn't tell 'em
what happened to the last crew.
You know, you supposed
to be some slick-shit killer.
Now look at you...
all back-of-the-bus
and shit.
<i>I say we attack Helion Two next.</i>
Take it straight
into their teeth.
It'll cost you 20,000 heads, five
warrior ships. Nothing more, I swear it.
While I do prize brute force,
this approach
is perhaps more artful.
Start at the end.
Go straight to Helion Five,
the last planet
in the system.
We approach from the night side.
<i>Remove these cannon first,</i>
then attack
the larger placements at speed.
<i>We'll catch them on their rear flank.
And in ten days' time,</i>
<i>the rest of those worlds
will tumble before us.</i>
You see, as with most,
their blind spot...
is right behind them.
I've located an ion trail
which leads off-world.
Then you should be
off-world, Vaako.
I've deployed a tracker team.
One of the best.
Wherever Riddick has gone,
you lens him out and cleanse him.
You.
You want me to take a
frigate for one breeder?
Don't question it, Vaako!
Take it on faith.
<i>Mercenaries, Elementals,
Necromongers...</i>
<i>Shit, I've never been so popular.</i>
<i>Should probably slip these chains
and open up a few arteries.</i>
<i>But why drive,
when you can get driven?</i>
<i>A free ticket to Crematoria.
Thanks, Toombs.</i>
<i>Got me some business there
named Jack.</i>
<i>And once we settle up,
I'll walk away forever.</i>
<i>So, I'll just wait, all back-of-the-bus.</i>
<i>For now.</i>
- How unexpected.
- An Elemental.
<i>- Here?
- One of the captives.</i>
<i>And why, after 30 years,</i>
should it be you?
You be the good warrior.
Go after this Riddick.
I'll find out why the Lord Marshal
is so threatened by him.
<i>Destination reached.</i>
<i>Unlocking manual controls.</i>
All right. I make 700 degrees
on the day side,
300 below on the night side.
Let's not get caught in the sun.
If I owned this place and hell,
I'd rent this place out
and live in hell.
<i>- Blue angle... good.
- Stand by.</i>
<i>And...</i>
<i>Plotted course good.</i>
Hit it!
<i>Angle of approach, not good.</i>
<i>Look, Ma. No hands!</i>
Party poppers!
I think I shit myself.
Skittish, Toombs. Very skittish.
Comfy?
When the ride's over,
your goggles are mine.
Four-way split!
29.4 kilometers.
So, this is Riddick.
What in the bowels of Christ
are you talkin' about, 700K?
Don't take this one, boss.
See? Anatoli here
has a nose for trouble.
And this one, this Riddick guy...
Big, big trouble.
So, 700,000 is good money.
I'd take the money, Toombs.
<i>The guild pays us a caretaker's fee
for each prisoner each year.</i>
We pay mercs 20% of that total fee
based on a certain life expectancy.
<i>How's about this?</i>
You open that safe you got hidden
behind the console there,
show me the real books,
then we figure out my cut.
Then I'll be on my way.
Open my books.
This is what you suggest?
Wasn't a suggestion.
<i>These are dangerous days,
if you believe the talk.</i>
- Talk?
- About dead planets.
About some ghost army.
About them.
"Them"?
I'll run the numbers again.
It takes a couple of days,
probably,
so you can stay as my guest.
At least here, we are all safe.
<i>- Yes?
- Yes, boss.</i>
I'll give it a day.
One.
<i>There are inmates...</i>
<i>and there are convicts.</i>
A convict has a certain code.
And he knows to show
a certain respect.
<i>An inmate, on the other hand,</i>
pulls the pin on his fellow man.
<i>Does the guards' work for them.</i>
Brings shame...
To the game.
So, which are you gonna be?
Me?
I'm just passin' through.
Welcome to Crematoria.
They can be quite a test,
these deep runs...
tests of our inner selves.
Don't you find that true?
Some men do.
<i>Just being so far from the armada,</i>
the mind can start to fill
with strange thoughts, doubts.
Don't you ever have doubts, Vaako?
- Doubts?
- About the campaign.
About Lord Marshal.
First and always,
I am a Necromonger commander.
So if you're here to test my loyalty,
you succeed only in testing my patience.
Oh, no.
No, that's not why I'm here at all.
<i>A young warrior
once consulted a seer.</i>
<i>He was told a child would be born
on the planet Furya... a male child...</i>
<i>who would someday
cause the warrior's downfall.</i>
<i>Cause his untimed death.</i>
Furya? Furya's a ruined world.
No life to speak of.
For good reason.
This young warrior
mounted an attack on Furya,
killing all young males
he could find,
even strangling some
with their birth cords.
An artful stroke,
wouldn't you say?
So this warrior, the one who tried to
outwit the prediction, would later become...
That's why he worries.
...our Lord Marshal.
Which would make
the man-child...
He worries he missed
killing that child in its crib.
...Riddick.
Feeding time!
Here they come!
Aaah!
It's an animal thing.
Let's pop the cork.
Get some fresh air.
So they do go topside...
to swap out air.
Interesting.
Who the hell are you?
When it happens, it'll happen fast.
<i>Stay on my leg when I cut fence
or stay here...</i>
for the rest of your unnatural life.
Nobody outs this place.
Nobody.
<i>He ain't "nobody. "</i>
<i>Good news first.
Talked things over with my amigos here.</i>
We'll cut you in for 775K.
Well, all right.
What's the bad news?
They close the local whorehouse?
<i>No. The bad news is worse than that.
Much worse.</i>
Our pilot, he saw this.
It crossed a shipping lane.
<i>Any idea what this might be?</i>
Never saw nothin' like it.
<i>This ship charts back
to Helion Prime.</i>
You know, Anatoli's
got a nose for trouble,
<i>and he thinks
trouble follows you here.</i>
<i>Look. We dusted our tracks
and got the hell outta there.</i>
There is no way
we didn't lose them.
"Them"?
This is my prisoner. Mine.
Nobody else's.
And I want my money now.
<i>So...</i>
you stole a prisoner...
from "them"?
No.
<i>Riddick. No!</i>
Shoulda taken the money, Toombs.
You gonna kill me?
<i>Mercs.</i>
Some guards here,
but this can't be all of them.
<i>Check their slots in the back...
and be careful.</i>
<i>Don't bother.</i>
Guards ain't there.
<i>They figured out the Necros
are comin' for me.</i>
Plan was to clean the bank,
ghost the mercs,
break wide through the tunnel.
And then somebody got a lucky shot off
with this rocket launcher here...
and took out the sled.
Guards took off on foot but rigged
the door so no one could follow.
<i>They'll take the one ship in the hangar
and leave everyone else here to die.</i>
How come you know all this shit?
You weren't even here.
'Cause it was my plan.
I shoulda taken the money.
Riddick!
<i>What is this?
What is he thinking?</i>
<i>- Once that sun comes up...
- We'll last five minutes.</i>
Five minutes. We ain't gonna last
30 seconds out there.
It'll light you up like a match.
20-mile buffer zone
and 30 klicks to the hangar.
30 klicks over that terrain?
It's moving in the right direction.
We could make it.
Stay behind the night,
ahead of the sun.
There's gonna be one speed...
mine.
<i>If you can't keep up, don't step up.</i>
You'll just die.
<i>Riddick?</i>
Riddick?
Go, go! Go on! Go! Climb here!
Climb! Go! Go, go, go!
Boss!
<i>Up there.</i>
- Take a look.
- Because Anatoli says so?
Because his nose says so.
There's nothin' up here.
Oh, shit.
Riddick.
<i>They're heading right for the volcano
fields. They're going for our ship!</i>
No chance do they get to
the hangar first. No chance!
Next one! Next hole!
We'll catch 'em there!
<i>No more run for you.</i>
Where did the big guy go?
Ohh...
Close it!
What was that?
You don't care if you live or die?
If I kill them first, not really.
Maybe I do.
Keep moving!
<i>Kyra?</i>
Get that ass moving!
"One speed. "
Temperature differential.
Your rope.
It's too late.
We're never gonna make it.
Your rope! Gimme your rope!
And your water. All of it!
Stay in the shadow of the mountain.
Don't wait for me. Run!
Riddick!
Aaah!
Where the hell is that hangar?
<i>There it is.</i>
<i>Listen.</i>
Let me guess. Necros.
I figure we got three minutes before the sun
hits us again, burns out this whole valley.
- Wait.
- We gonna do this or not?
Just wait.
Aaah! Boss!
On the right!
Watch out!
Behind you!
<i>Kyra!</i>
Sybar!
<i>No!</i>
Kyra?
<i>I was supposed to
deliver a message to you...</i>
if Vaako failed to kill you.
A message from
the Lord Marshal himself.
He tells you to stay away from Helion,
stay away from him,
and in return,
you'll be hunted no more.
But Vaako will most likely
report you as dead.
So this is your chance.
Your chance to do
what no man has ever done.
The girl.
Where will they take her?
We all began... as something else.
I've done... unbelievable things...
in the name of a faith
that was never my own.
And he'll do to her
what he did to me.
The Necromonger in me
warns you not to go back.
But the Furyan in me...
hopes you won't listen.
<i>I have lost a Purifier...</i>
<i>but I have gained
a first among commanders.</i>
It is overdue, isn't it...
that we acknowledge
your many accomplishments,
<i>your steady faith,</i>
and above all,
your unflinching loyalty.
Obedience without question.
Loyalty till UnderVerse come.
Well done, Vaako.
This is a day of days.
<i>Now, tell me if it's true.</i>
Tell me the Furyan is gone, and I can close
this campaign without hearing his bootsteps.
If he is dead,
I sense I'm not far
from the same fate,
being of no further use here.
Shouldn't I tell you
that Riddick is still alive?
Don't try me, Aereon.
I could plough you under
with the rest of Helion Prime.
No one really knows the future.
Then tell me the odds
that Vaako met with success,
that I will now be the one...
who can carry his people across
the threshold into UnderVerse,
where they shall begin true life.
Tell me what I want to hear, Aereon,
and maybe
I'll save your home world... for last.
- The odds are good...
That Riddick is still alive
Ascension protocol!
We still have numbers out there, Lord
Marshal... sweep teams, recon ships.
They would be hard-pressed
to make it back...
Get my armada off the ground!
Final protocol.
Execute on my order.
Go inside.
<i>We found this Lensor dead.</i>
<i>Show me his last sight.</i>
Commander Toal.
He won't escape twice.
Stay your weapons!
He came for me.
<i>Consider this:</i>
<i>If you fall here now,</i>
you'll never rise.
<i>But if you choose another way...</i>
<i>the Necromonger way...</i>
<i>you'll die in due time...</i>
and rise again in the UnderVerse.
Go to him.
It hurts...
at first.
But after a while, the pain
goes away, just as they promise.
- Are you with me, Kyra?
- There's a moment...
when you can almost
see the UnderVerse through his eyes.
It makes it sound perfect...
a place where anyone
can start over.
Are you with me, Kyra?
Convert now...
or fall forever.
You killed everything I know.
Vaako.
Not yet.
Been a long time
since I've seen my own blood.
These are his last moments.
Give me your soul.
Never!
You're not the one to bring me down.
Help me, Vaako. Kill him.
Vaako?
Forgive me.
I thought you were dead.
Are you with me, Kyra?
I was always with you.
I was.
You keep what you kill.