Is that normal?
No.
- Someone's hacking the system.
- What?
The containment tank
is destabilizing.
He's waking up.
2024?
I've been trapped for 50 years?
- Move, move!
- Take positions!
Get on the ground now!
We've got you surrounded!
Okay, Captain, we got a
rogue alien on the loose.
How do we find
him?
Finally,
some action!
Okay, time to gear up.
We're
over the drop zone.
All right, here
we go. Showtime!
What happened here?
Looks like GUN
got their butts kicked.
Whoa! Are you guys seeing this?
- He looks just like you.
- Impossible!
Walk away, before you get hurt.
Whoa, whoa, easy, buddy.
We don't want to fight you.
Actually, Sonic, I
would like to fight.
Not now.
Why don't you stop throwing
cars at us for a second
and come down here to talk?
You jumped out of
a GUN helicopter.
There's nothing to talk about.
All right, then. Enough!
Knuckles, no!
Let us talk with our fists!
Knuckles!
Knuckles! Knuckles,
are you okay?
No, not really. Ow!
Who is this guy?
He is much more impressive
than the hedgehog I
fought previously.
Dude,
I'm standing right here
Now come on, he can't take us all at once
Ow!
Weakling.
Don't try to follow me.
Sonic, I know that look.
Going after him is a bad idea.
Coming through!
Watch out!
Yah!
Sonic!
Are you okay?
Sorry, buddy. I'm still
working on this teamwork thing.
So now what?
Well, I'm not jumping out
of any more helicopters
until we get some
answers from GUN.
We need somewhere to regroup.
I know just the place.
Commander Walters!
Sonic.
Thank God you're all okay.
I'm sure you have questions.
Who was that guy?
Shadow's story began a
lot like yours, Sonic.
But where you found family
and friends on this planet,
Shadow found only pain and loss.
It begins over 50 years ago,
with a meteor crash in a
quiet corner of Oklahoma.
The meteorite
contained a life-form.
The ultimate life-form.
Shadow's power...
his "chaos energy"...
went far beyond any
living creature.
The scientist who discovered
him believed this power
would usher in a new
era for humanity.
But Shadow's power
proved too dangerous.
A terrible accident
destroyed the lab,
taking human lives
with it.
The project leader was blamed
for the incident and imprisoned.
With the program
canceled...
Shadow was a loose end no
one knew how to deal with.
Too dangerous to
be walking free,
too valuable to destroy.
So I had him placed
into stasis
Wait a second. If Shadow's
been on ice for 50 years,
- someone had to help him escape.
- True.
But there's only a few
people in the world
who even know of
Shadow's existence.
Get down!
Egg drones?
But Robotnik is
supposed to be dead!
Commander Walters!
Commander
Walters, are you okay?
Sonic...
take this.
What is
it? A key...
to the most powerful
weapon GUN has ever built.
You're the only one I
trust to keep it safe.
Commander Walters...
Alpha team, fan out!
Do we have eyes?
Secure the perimeter!
Medevac is en route.
His launch key is missing.
Why are we
running from GUN?
Aren't we on the same team?
Until we get
more information,
we're not trusting anyone.
- Follow me.
- Get it... off!
Who are you?
It's the Goat Milker!
Relax. I'm not here to fight.
- Then why are you here?
- And why did you free Shadow?
Are you kidding?
The last thing we want is more
super-powered hedgehogs running around.
The doctor had
nothing to do with it.
And I can prove
it.
Please,
join me in the crab.
Pablo!
!¡Bastardo!
Buenos días, !¡hermano!
No!
Let that be a
lesson to you, Juan.
Family
is a field of
emotional claymores
that leave you
abandoned, betrayed
and weeping while you eat cake,
which creates copious
amounts of adipose tissue,
and what some calloused
individuals refer to as...
man boobs.
Ha.
Doctor, we have visitors.
Really?
I thought I was having an
anthropomorphic nightmare.
Where the only person I
could trust in the world
showed up with all
my worst enemies,
while I was in a bathrobe,
playing congas on
my big, fat belly!
Sorry, sir.
I don't believe
it. Eggman's alive?
And he's never looked worse.
Well, maybe,
this is what not giving a damn what
you think I look like looks like.
Sir, right now we have
an even bigger problem.
Oh, come on.
There's an imposter out
there using your technology.
Imposter. That's
impossi... What?
No.
My sweet mechanized spawn!
Whomever this party-pooping
posse is looking for
has stolen my persona
and the precious
babies from my egg sac.
Well...
I'll soon egg-xact my revenge.
You see what I did
there?
It's time for the
dramatic soap-opera twist,
where this Pablo
reveals his Juan!
By cross-referencing
the precise coordinates
of each drone's energy spikes,
I can track my babies
to the imposter's
base of operations,
right about...
there!
All right, Egghead.
I hate to say it,
but it looks like
we're partners.
On one condition.
Dude, you have serious issues.
Ow!
Let's...
do this!
Suck it in!
Tinker-tailor?
I need room.
Think Elvis, circa 1976.
But sir, I don't have
the proper materials.
Found some.
Resourceful.
Hey! This is a restricted area.
Oh, it's okay. She's the
professor's granddaughter.
He takes her everywhere.
Welcome to the lab, Maria.
I'm Captain Walters.
Oh, do you know
where my room is?
Yeah, down the hall
and to the right.
Make yourself at home.
But, um,
let's lose the
skates, okay, kiddo?
Okay.
Look out!
Professor?
It's good to see you, Shadow.
I knew you'd come home.
I can't get her out of my head.
The pain...
It's too much.
And that is why we
have to punish them.
This door is
six-inch-thick solid steel
on a pressurized latch.
I'll need a moment to
calculate the molecular density
and invert the
venting mechanics.
I unlocked it.
Subtle as
always, fist-for-brains.
Easy, Shadow.
Those are the guests
I've been expecting.
Let's give them a warm welcome.
Whoa.
What is this place?
It looks
like a military base,
but nobody's been
here for years.
Just a dark, creepy hallway.
Nothing to be afraid of.
You hear that, ghost?
You don't frighten me!
Get... a... grip.
Boo.
Whoa. Look at all this stuff.
He had a family.
Is that what I smell?
The stench of domestic harmony?
You ever wonder what your life would
have been like if you had a family?
Hmm... No!
Maybe you wouldn't have
gone full supervillain.
I have no parents,
no aunts, no uncles.
And something about my
attitude renders me...
undesirable to all
possible genders.
My future is a cul-de-sac!
The Robotnik name ends...
avec moi.
Yes, I know French.
Whoa.
Is this where you
grew up, Shadow?
No wonder you're so mad.
What happened here?
Where'd you go, hedgehog?
I wasn't finished
trauma dumping.
My darlings!
My eggy weggies!
♪ Memories ♪
♪ Light the corners ♪
♪ Of my mind ♪
♪ Misty watercolor ♪
♪ Memories ♪
♪ Of the way ♪
♪ We weren't ♪
I...
- don't believe it.
- Don't you?
- It's impossible.
- Is it?
- It couldn't be.
- Couldn't it?
I'm... Are you?
Imposter!
You stole my babies!
But they know who
their real daddy is...
drone-napper!
Magnificent creations, my boy.
I borrowed them to lure you here
and reunite our family.
You see, Ivo...
I'm your grandfather:
Gerald Robotnik.
My... grandfather?
But how? And why?
And who did what with whom?
You hail from an
ancestry of excellence...
tied directly à moi.
Yes, I know French.
You do look like me.
But fatter. And older.
And there's that funny smell.
But the resemblance is uncanny.
It's as if...
we're two
characters in a movie
being played by the same actor.
- But I need real proof!
- Ivo!
We have very little time.
But I could field a
couple of queries.
Name the most elegant
formula in mathematics.
Euler's Identity.
E to the I times pi
plus one equals zilch.
European capitals
arranged alphabetically
by the fourth letter.
Riga, Monaco, Sarajevo, Tirana.
The speed of light divided
by the speed of sound,
divided by the speed of
the bus in the movie Speed.
17,893.33333...
Rounding up? 17,894 MPH.
And, for all the marbles...
Good. I lost mine.
A rare lung disease,
and the longest word in
the English dictionary.
Um...
Pneumonoultramicroscopic-
silicovolcanoconiosis!
- Pap-pap!
- In the saggy flesh.
But looking pretty good
for a hundred and ten.
Oh, Grampy-poo!
Where have you been
my entire life?
Wait.
Where have you been...
my entire life?
Locked in a top-secret
prison for the last 50 years.
Made it kind of hard to
send Christmas cards.
Now...
you're probably wondering
why I brought you here.
You didn't bring me here!
I used my unparalleled
intellect to track you down.
Per the plan I concocted with
my unparalleled intellect.
You'll see.
I have the answer to everything.
Come on, kiddo.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no.
Someone tell me
this is some kind of
concussion-induced nightmare.
Double your villains,
double your fun!
Two Robotniks are
way worse than one.
Chest bump?
No.
Stone, why are you tied up?
Do that on your own
time. You sicken me.
You must be the
long-lost grandson.
And you must be another
stinking hedgehog.
So you're the one
behind all this.
- The Shadow breakout.
- The attack on Walters.
That musty old-man smell.
How dare you insult me
with your unsolicited
exposition!
Shadow, get the key.
Yep, we're that stupid.
GUN took everything from us.
And now we are going to
take everything from them.
With this.
My masterpiece of malevolence...
The Eclipse Cannon.
In exchange for my freedom,
I gave GUN the most
powerful weapon
mankind has ever seen,
capable of delivering
a precision strike
anywhere on Earth.
Our first target:
GUN Headquarters.
But firing a weapon
that powerful
could threaten millions
of innocent lives!
Yeah, tera-bite me.
This is one of two keys required
to launch the Eclipse Cannon.
The other is locked
inside GUN headquarters.
Once we have both,
I will take rightful
control of my weapon.
I'm in.
Holy crab!
Spacious
and crustaceous.
Thank you so much
for inspiring this
little adventure.
It really worked out for me.
Shadow, wait! Don't do this.
I've spent 50 years reliving
what they did to her.
Yeah! Yes!
Yikes.
I've spent years trying
to cleanse the cosmos
of that spiny, blue speed freak.
And you did it...
in one afternoon.
There's nothing we can't
destroy together, my boy.
Charting route to GUN
Headquarters in London, sirs.
ETA four hours.
As the crab flies.
By all accounts, we're
ahead of schedule.
We should take this time
to get to know
each other better.
Wow. What?
You mean...
spend some qua-qua-quality time?
You've waited for
this your whole life.
How would you choose to spend one
perfect day with your new grand pal?
Ooh!
London, baby!
GUN Headquarters is right there.
Let me go in, get the key
and destroy anyone in my way!
I want revenge.
Patience, Shadow.
Just let us handle this...
and I promise
you'll have revenge
on a scale you couldn't
possibly imagine.
Come on, Granddaddy-O,
we've got...
dirt to do!
Suits.
Right here, sir.
Stone, babysit the hedgehog.
Keep the crab on a low boil.
It's time for more
family bonding.
Tom, Maddie, are you
in position and ready?
- We were born ready.
- Let's do this.
Knuckles,
how about you?
I have taken my perch
atop the giant clock.
All right, everyone
knows what to do.
Tom and Maddie, you guys
plant the USB drive.
I'll disable the traps. Sonic
will snag the launch key.
And Knuckles, you stand by to...
Break glass in
case of emergency.
Then we're all set.
Hologram time.
You go first.
Okay, Tails, what
are we looking for?
The security server is in
the 7th row, 23rd cabinet.
All right, hang tight, guys.
Maddie's about to insert the drive.
Ready?
Three...
two...
one...
Go.
I'm shutting down the
outside sensors now.
Yes! Uh...
Hold on. Is...
there supposed to be
another USB drive here?
One with a
giant mustache on it?
Oh, no. I've got two heat
signatures en route to the vault.
Which can only mean...
The Robotniks have
entered the chat.
Hello! What's this?
I knew I saw an outside signal!
Cheerio!
I guess someone forgot to flush.
What now, my cunning cohort?
Just a little teamwork!
Hey...
The lasers...
don't seem to be
penetrating my suit.
They're conforming to the
shape of my bodacious bod.
Of course.
I designed these suits
to create a field
of laser-bending
thermal distortion.
Wasn't sure it
would work till now.
You're heartless, son.
- Hmm!
- Rotten to the core.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm...
so proud.
So now we can just
dance right through.
That sounds like a challenge.
The Robotniks are
almost at the vault!
We're out of time. I'm going.
No, Sonic!
I haven't disabled
the traps yet!
You're not gonna make it!
I can make it.
I'm gonna make it.
Our destiny awaits.
Stop right there, Roboscum!
- Let's do this!
- Copy!
Too slow, Eggmen.
Now if you don't mind,
I've got to get that key.
Whoa!
this vault is armed
with variable gravity.
No kidding.
Green goes up...
and red takes you down... hard.
Rockwell, listen to me.
The Robotniks are
planning to...
Oh, they're planning on stealing
a second key, just like you are?
Yes, I'm aware.
I called it the second
Commander Walters was attacked.
So...
thank you for taking the bait
and falling right into my trap.
I don't believe this.
I know, grandson.
A woman in the military!
Let's go.
Go, positions!
Full perimeter.
Robotnik.
Going full spandex,
huh? Who's the fossil?
That's my grandfather, you
dough-eating dimbecile.
- Who are they?
- A couple of bleeding hearts,
here to rescue their
emotional-support animals.
Enough! It's over.
The only way you're leaving
here is in handcuffs.
There is no other way out.
Hey, big guy,
I think it's time to...
Break glass in
case of emergency!
Ha! Nothing can
stop Team Knuckles!
Open fire!
Knuckles,
turn this stuff off!
- Hurry!
- On it.
Uh-oh.
- Can you move?
- No, not at all.
- Tails, can you?
- No, I'm stuck.
We might be here a while.
Whoa! Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Where's the key?
Whoa!
- What was that?
- We might have a problem.
No, no, no, no!
I'm moving.
I'm moving!
You go get it, grandson!
Oh, whoa, whoa...
No. No, no!
I'm almost there!
Whoa!
That was so not worth it!
- You okay?
- Yeah. You good?
Sonic!
Hey.
Thanks for the save.
Cutting it a little
close, don't you think?
Secure the room!
She's got the key.
I got an idea.
Commander Walters.
Sir.
You're... Still alive?
I'll die before I let that
key fall into the wrong hands.
Thanks for keeping it safe.
I'll take it from here.
That's an order,
Director Rockwell.
Now, organize the
reinforcements.
Yes, sir.
Guys, guys, I got the key.
I repeat, I got the key.
Now let's get out of here.
Commander Walters.
No, no. No. Wait!
What?
Tom! Everyone's clear!
Come on, let's go!
You. What are you...
Tom!
Tom. Tom, what happened?
Please, please, please get up.
Hey, come on, please wake up.
Wake up, wake up, wake up!
Maria.
What did you do?
What I had to.
Oh, my God. Tom!
Help me up, kid.
Freeze! Don't move!
Any tricks up your sleeve,
Captain Grandtastic?
We got what we came for.
Great job, Shadow.
We have both keys.
So where's your little
science project?
It's closer than
you think, my boy.
Welcome...
to my masterpiece!
I must hand it to GUN.
They built her to my
exact specifications.
It's...
remarkable!
Mm-hmm.
- Astounding!
- Yes.
That's my genius grand-genome!
And I have one more surprise.
It's a new suit!
♪ I'm a chip off
The old block! ♪
What do you want,
Stone? I'm busy.
Doctor, I have a bad
feeling about this.
I don't think your grandfather's
been completely honest with us.
There's more to their plan.
How dare you!
You have been jealous of
my long-lost grand-Pop-Tart
since the very beginning!
I no longer require your
obsequious groveling.
Consider this your
notice of termination.
Your letter of reference
will be L for Loser.
Of course, I'll
expect you to stay on
until you've been
successfully cloned.
But you and I are done!
Like a blackened catfish dinner!
Sir, it's too dangerous and
I'm not there to protect you.
I already lost you once! I...
Unsubscribe. Blocked
and reported.
I
can't lose you again.
Do the honors...
grandson.
Here we go.
Sonic!
This is an urgent
national emergency broadcast.
A spacecraft designed
by the agency GUN
has been hijacked and launched
out of the River Thames.
All residents are urged
to seek immediate shelter.
It's time, Shadow.
Professor, is this really
what Maria would have wanted?
The question isn't what
Maria would have wanted.
It's what do they deserve.
Remember what she meant to us.
Remember what they took from us.
Kids!
We have to go, now!
They want to take
Shadow away from us, Maria!
Hey! Hey! What are you
doing? Those are children.
- We've got our orders, Walters!
- Stand down!
Huh?
Maria!
Excuse me, Grand Paso Doble.
What is that thermonuclear
gerbil doing?
Infusing the core...
with chaos energy.
That's my little secret.
The Eclipse Cannon is
about to turn this planet
into a flaming pile of rubble,
wiping out everything
in a 25,000-mile radius.
Including us.
What?
We can't annihilate the Earth!
- Hmm?
- By combining our genius, we can rule humanity.
Together!
Humanity is a failed experiment.
If anyone should
know that, it's you.
All your life, you've been
rejected by this world.
You have nothing down there.
No one who cares about you.
But I have you now.
We're family.
We have each other.
Oh, Ivo...
you're no Maria.
The moment I lost her, my
family was gone forever!
The only way to give
Maria's life meaning
is to destroy the world
that took her from me.
So I'm burning it all down!
It's done.
Good work, Shadow.
I'm prepping the
firing sequence.
The weapon will be fully
charged in ten minutes.
It's almost finished, Maria.
You will have justice.
What is that?
Is GUN launching missiles at us?
Impossible. It's
moving too fast.
It's him.
You hurt my family.
This ends now!
Now you know my anger.
The pain I've felt for 50 years.
And you've made the
same choice I did.
I'm nothing like you!
We'll see.
Show yourself, coward!
You were right about one thing.
This ends now.
What's happening?
Where are they?
- Up there.
- Where?
- Higher.
- Hmm?
Left yourself open.
Ivo! What are you doing?
Thwarting your evil plan!
- Not the mustache!
- Agreed.
Let go on three.
One, two, three!
Oh... a nano-fist.
I haven't seen that since I
hate-watched Green Lantern in 2011.
I was saving it for Comic-Con.
But now there won't
be a Comic-Con!
Why are you alone?
Where are your friends?
They tried to stop
you, didn't they?
But you came anyway.
Your anger was too much.
What kind of hero
abandons his friends
to pursue revenge?
Go ahead. Finish it!
You didn't let your pain
change who you are...
What are you doing?
You won. Take your revenge.
There are no winners
with revenge.
This whole mess is my fault.
I've been so blinded
by rage, I thought...
I had no choice.
You always have a choice.
But making the right
one is never easy.
One more thing I learned
is that when you really
screw something up,
you can't fix it on your own.
I... will... not...
try...
to stop... my...
elders... from...
destroying... the... world!
Playtime is over.
There's no going back now.
Set up defense.
Damn you, autocorrect!
Mantis!
Oh!
Whee!
I'm right here, arach-nerd.
That's what I call
mantis-scaping.
That's elder abuse!
Alert! Alert! Alert!
Shadow...
I see you've chosen betrayal.
And you were once
so useful to me.
Please, Grampsy,
don't do this!
Sorry, kiddo.
Bring Your Grandkid
to Work Day is over.
Any last words?
Just one thing...
that I never thought I'd say.
What is it?
"I love you"?
No.
It was something even better.
But I'm not gonna say it if
that's the way you're gonna be.
Okay. Bye.
Grandchildren.
All the fun and none
of the responsibility.
Who said life was pointless?
- Huh?
- Oh, right. You did.
Victory!
Say what you want
about my granddad,
he made one hell
of a bug zapper.
We got to stop that laser!
I knew there was something
I was forgetting.
We can't stop the
cannon from firing...
But we can steer it
away from the Earth.
- Coming around to starboard.
- Aye-aye, Doc.
Here we go.
It's a little tight.
Definitely not power steering.
Keep... turning.
Jump in anytime here, guys!
Yes!
I did it! I did it!
- Oh!
- Ooh!
Look what you did!
- Hey, look down there!
- Sonic!
Oh, Knuckles, please
tell me you have a...
Last one.
Let's make it count.
Ready for a little base of ball?
Deep breath.
One... two... three!
- Really!
- What's happening?
The reactor core is overloading.
It's only a matter of
time before it blows.
So what does that
mean for Earth?
A radioactive atmosphere.
Rain that kills the crops
and melts your flesh.
Other than that...
We're not done here!
You try to stabilize
the reactor.
Buy me some time.
I'll push the station
away from Earth
before it explodes.
This is our last chance
to do the right thing.
Go with God
stinking hedgehog.
Core integrity failing.
I've got you, Sonic!
Initializing
reactor core stabilizers.
This is Doctor Ivo Robotnik,
dedicating my final livestream
to one very special henchman:
Agent Stone.
No, no. Doctor, wait!
If I can't rule the world...
I might as well save it...
for the one and only person
who ever cared about me.
Don't do this, Doctor, please!
Stone, you were more
than a sycophant to me.
You were...
a syco-friend.
I'll miss your lattes with
steamed Austrian goat milk.
I love the way you make 'em!
So... I guess there's only
one thing left to say.
It's been a real drag.
Thanks for nothing.
Sonic, look.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Let's do this!
Yeah!
All right,
boys, try and keep up.
Sonic the Hedgehog is
Family Champion once again!
Tails?
Knuckles?
Okay. Yeah, I overshot
the finish line.
Okay, so
how do I get back?
Pro Tip
you'd better not miss.
That's a neat trick.
What? Who are you?