Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
<i>So, I know
what you're thinking.</i>
<i>Why is that incredibly
handsome hedgehog</i>
<i>being chased by a madman</i>
<i>with a mustache
from the Civil War?</i>
<i>Well, to be honest, it feels like
I've been running my whole life.</i>
<i>Is this too much?
Am I going too fast?</i>
<i>It's kind of what I do...
You know what? Let's back up.</i>
<i>This is the island
where I'm from.</i>
<i>It had everything.</i>
<i>Sandy beaches,
cascading waterfalls,</i>
<i>public access to loop-de-loops.</i>
<i>And, I never had
to catch a school bus</i>
<i>because I could run across
the entire island</i>
<i>in less than two seconds.</i>
<i>Also, there was no school.</i>
<i>I know,
pretty sweet island, right?</i>
Yeah!
<i>I was born
with extraordinary powers</i>
<i>and was told
to keep them secret.</i>
<i>And like any kid,
I did the exact opposite.</i>
Whoo-hoo!
<i>That's Longclaw.
She took care of me.</i>
<i>She was basically
Obi-Wan Kenobi...</i>
<i>if Obi-Wan Kenobi
had a beak and ate mice.</i>
Sonic, someone
could have seen you.
No one saw me. I'm too fast!
And I wanted to bring you this.
Get down!
<i>Turns out,
with great power</i>
<i>comes great
power-hungry bad guys.</i>
<i>And I led them right to us.</i>
Listen carefully, Sonic.
You have a power unlike
anything I have ever seen.
And that means someone
will always want it.
The only way to stay safe
is to stay hidden.
This world is on the far side
of the universe.
You should be safe there.
- I don't want to go without you.
- You must.
These rings will be your most
important possession.
If you're ever discovered,
use one.
Never stop running.
Now go!
Longclaw!
Goodbye, Sonic.
No!
Come on, one car?
I'm bored.
<i>Tom, do you read me?
Are you there?</i>
No, Wade, I'm actually
on a yacht in Barbados.
With Rihanna.
OMG.
That's amazing.
Please send pics.
No, Wade.
I'm at the speed trap.
Already? How did you get back so fast?
Barbados is in the ocean!
Hang on, I think
I got something.
Hey, buddy! Where's the fire?
Got kids living around here.
I thought that was
kind of funny.
Sorry.
What?
<i>Tom,
we need you down on Main Street.</i>
<i>There's been a violent
gang shoot-out.</i>
<i>Just kidding.
A duck stole a bagel.</i>
<i>But they do need it back.</i>
Whoa, buddy, you almost
got yourself killed out there.
What are you,
some kind of adrenaline junkie?
It must be rough
being slow all the time.
Tell you what.
Today is your lucky day.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Have you ever felt so alive?
This is great.
You're doing amazing.
Oh, geez!
Good recovery.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Let's keep this our little secret, okay?
You never saw me.
I was never here.
<i>So what
were you expecting?</i>
<i>A dirty little hedgehog
eating berries</i>
<i>and struggling to survive?</i>
<i>Think again. Because I am
living my best life on Earth.</i>
<i>I've got a library...</i>
<i>a home gym,</i>
<i>and a state-of-the-art
security system.</i>
Oh, no.
<i>And, if I'm ever discovered,</i>
<i>I'll follow
Longclaw's instructions</i>
<i>and use my rings
to escape to a new planet.</i>
<i>A nice, safe little world
filled only with mushrooms.</i>
<i>Gross, smelly mushrooms.</i>
I hate mushrooms.
<i>But let's not worry
about all that.</i>
<i>This is Green Hills.</i>
<i>The greatest place on Earth.</i>
<i>These are my people and,
dare I say,</i>
<i>I am their
lovable space creature.</i>
<i>So what if they
don't know I exist?</i>
<i>My favorite person
is the Donut Lord.</i>
<i>Protector of this town</i>
<i>and defender of all creatures,
big and small.</i>
Morning.
Donald. Daisy. Daffy.
<i>Donut Lord lives
with Pretzel Lady.</i>
<i>She is super nice to animals</i>
<i>and strangely was born
without bones.</i>
Ouch, ouch, ouch.
<i>There is one person in town</i>
<i>who's actually onto me.</i>
<i>He calls me the blue devil.</i>
I almost caught him last night.
<i>Say hello to Crazy Carl.</i>
<i>We have fun together.</i>
I know you're out there!
And I know you're real!
No, I'm not!
<i>Movie night is my favorite.</i>
Please, please,
please, please, please.
Yes! Keanu!
You are a national treasure.
- <i>When I find you...</i>
- <i>Pop quiz, hotshot.</i>
<i>There's a bomb on a bus.</i>
"Pop quiz, hotshot."
It's a classic line.
<i>Basically,
we're like a family.</i>
<i>Even though we haven't met yet.</i>
You don't zink your
prolonged isolation is making
you a bit crazy perhaps?
Crazy? Me?
No way, Doc.
You got me all wrong.
And despite all these so-called
friends of yours, deep down...
...you're still rather lonely?
<i>Perhaps afraid
you'll be alone forever?</i>
Uh-uh. Hey!
No, no, no, no.
Get out of there. Come on.
Oh, come on! Get out of there!
Get out of there,
you trash pandas.
Maddie, as Green Hills'
most respected veterinarian,
what is the fastest way
to exterminate a raccoon?
Hi, Ozzy. Hello!
You're glad to see me.
You don't eat garbage, do you?
What's that?
- Is that what I think it is?
- Uh-huh. Open it.
Oh, it's kind of small.
Is that bad?
Just open it.
"Dear Thomas:
We have reviewed
your application
to the San Francisco
Police Department,
and pending
interdepartmental review
and background check,
we are happy to inform you
that you have been selected
to join our team."
- Oh, my God!
- Wow.
Oh, my God.
Ta-da!
"San Francisco Sucks."
Oh!
Wrong one!
Ta-da!
- You never had a doubt, huh?
- No! Mm-mmm.
- I can't believe this.
- Oh, I know! You did it.
Hey, what are those?
Apartments for rent
I found on Zillow.
I thought Ozzy and I
could fly there tomorrow
and check out
some neighborhoods.
I mean,
this is all happening so fast.
Oh, man...
It's the craziest thing.
You apply for the job,
you get the job.
Well, pending
a background check.
Oh, man.
Hope they don't find out about
that time you used
the neighbor's Wi-Fi.
Correction: I'm still using
But, Maddie,
are you sure
you're okay with this?
Thomas Michael Wachowski,
what did you do the entire time
I was in veterinary school?
I worked a second job
to pay the rent and...
A third job to pay tuition.
You sacrificed for me.
I'm happy to sacrifice for you.
Babe, are you sure
you're okay with this?
I mean, there's been
a Wachowski protecting this town
for more than 50 years.
This is a big change.
I'm positive.
It's time for this guy to
get out there and prove himself.
I love Green Hills, but,
you know, I want to help
people in real trouble.
I want someone to turn to me
in a life-and-death situation
and I'll be there for 'em.
I get it.
- I'm so proud of you.
- Thank you.
Mmm!
And so it is with a heavy heart,
that I tell you all
that I've accepted a position
at the San Francisco
Police Department,
effective immediately.
It's gonna be tough
to leave my hometown
and all my friendships.
But this is something
I feel like I need to do...
to grow...
as both an officer and a man.
What do you think,
Sergeant Sprinkles?
That wasn't so bad, right?
Now all I got to do is...
tell everyone
who isn't a donut.
Whoa, the playoffs!
Oh! So cool.
Bottom of the ninth,
tie score.
And exactly who you want
at the plate
with the game
on the line: Sonic!
But staring him down
from the pitcher's mound
is the most fearsome southpaw
in Green Hills:
Also Sonic.
Okay. Focus, Sonic.
If you win this game,
you'll be the most beloved kid
in Green Hills.
Hit it to the guy in left!
He's a real space case.
I can't with that guy.
Hey, batter Sonic.
"Suh-wing," batter Sonic.
I got it, I got it, I got it!
I don't got it.
Go home! Go home!
Come on!
Safe!
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes! I did it!
Did you see that?
I did it. I did it.
I really am alone.
All alone. Forever.
I'm sure no one noticed that
giant blue explosion, right?
- Hey, Wade.
- Hi, Tom.
Uh, Wade here.
What is going on?
Well, gosh,
I think the power's out.
Yeah, no dur!
The lights are out.
The whole town is freaking out.
- What should I do?
- <i>Okay, relax.</i>
Take a deep breath, call Gil,
see if they can locate
the downed line, then...
call Zim and see if he can get
his generator over to the Super Q
so the food stays... fresh.
<i>Call Zim before Gil?</i>
- <i>Call Gil... Hello?</i>
- I'll call you back.
Wait! Hello? Was that
the end of the instructions?
Okay, all right.
Uh, you can do this.
What was the first thing
he said to do?
Right. Relax.
Twenty minutes ago,
an energy surge
knocked out power across
the entire Pacific Northwest.
What do we know?
Well, our first instinct
was it was an EMP.
But electromagnetic pulses
don't have that kind of power.
NASA has ruled out
meteor strikes or solar flares.
The Department of Energy says it's
not a power plant malfunction.
Well, sounds like
we're really good
at figuring out
what it wasn't.
This could be a prelude
to a larger attack.
I'm suggesting we scramble
the Fifth and Sixth Regiment.
No, no, no, no.
This needs a much more
sophisticated mind.
Someone who
understands technology.
- You want to send in a lab rat?
- Not just any lab rat.
A lab rat with teeth.
You're not suggesting
who I think you're suggesting.
- I know, he's a little weird.
- Weird?
- No. No way.
- He's a psychological tire fire!
But he's also brilliant.
Five PhDs, IQ off the charts.
And his drone tech
is revolutionary!
You're sure he can handle this?
He has a perfect
operations record.
- Remember the coup in Pakistan?
- No.
Or the uprising
in Azerbaijanistan?
- That's not even a country.
- Exactly.
And you can thank
Robotnik for that.
I can't believe you're
bringing that freak into this.
Neither can I, but...
we have no choice.
What the...
Are you in charge here?
- Yes, I am...
- Nope!
- My...
- Wrong!
- name...
- I'm in charge!
- is Major...
- Me!
- Ben...
- I'm in charge.
You've never seen
anything like this before.
It says
I'm the top banana
in a world full of
hungry little monkeys.
Allow me to clarify.
In a sequentially
ranked hierarchy
based on level
of critical importance,
the disparity between us
is too vast to quantify.
- Agent Stone?
- The Doctor thinks you're basic.
I'm initiating a sweep sequence.
Ten miles in every direction
should suffice.
- Is he still looking at me funny?
- Yes, he is.
Tell him to stop or I'll
pull up his search history.
If you don't stop looking
at the Doctor,
- he'll take a closer look...
- I'm not deaf.
And tell him his men
report to me now.
Blah-blah-blah.
Excuse me? Listen, pal,
I don't know if you realize...
I'm sorry, Major.
What was your name?
- Benning...
- Nobody cares!
Nobody cares. Listen,
Major Nobody Cares.
You know why
nobody cares who you are?
Because nobody cares about
your feeble accomplishments.
And nobody cares
how proud your mommy is
that you're now reading
at a third-grade level.
- Mmm.
- Have you finished <i>Charlotte's Web</i> yet?
Spoiler alert:
She dies in the end.
But she leaves
a big creepy egg sac.
Ah... my babies.
Whoo! Look what came out
of my egg sac.
You know what I love
about machines?
They do what they're told.
They follow their programming.
They don't need time off
to get drunk
and put the boat in the water.
Now you do what you're told.
Stand over there on the edge
of your personal abyss...
and watch my machines
do your job.
- Can you feel it, Stone?
- I can feel it, Doctor.
It's evolution, Stone.
It's evolution!
- Agent Stone?
- Doctor.
Do you see anything useful
in this image?
- Nothing at all, Doctor.
- Of course you don't.
Your eyes weren't
expertly trained to spot tracks
by the Native-American
Shadow Wolves.
That's extraordinary.
No. What's extraordinary is,
I've determined
the exact height, weight
and spinal curvature
of this creature,
and my computer
can't find a single match for it
anywhere in Earth's
animal kingdom.
This blackout
was not a terrorist attack,
and that's no baby bigfoot.
This guy is something else...
entirely.
Divert all search units
to the site of the footprint.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for me.
Okay, okay, everything is fine.
You played some baseball,
got a little upset,
lightning shot out of your butt,
and now they're coming for you.
All right, all right.
Earth isn't safe anymore.
Time for plan B.
Mushroomville.
But I gotta take my stuff.
Okay, essential items only.
Okay, toothbrush, toothpaste,
hair gel, night-light.
Funny hat.
This half-eaten cantaloupe.
Oh, and my scented candle.
My entire comic book collection.
Bean bag chair.
Can a bean bag chair
fit in a backpack?
No, no, no. Of course not.
That's stupid.
Okay, what else? The rings!
The rings, yes, of course.
Here we go. Ring time.
Mushroom planet, here I come.
Oh, no.
They're right outside.
I gotta go somewhere else.
Goodbye, cave.
- Hey.
- <i>Hey.</i>
Whatcha doing?
Just coloring
with Jojo and Rachel.
Ah, that sounds...
half-fun.
Hey, exciting stuff here.
We had a power outage.
The whole town went dark.
It was like a sign telling me
to get out of Dodge.
- Wade must have lost his mind.
- <i>Yeah.</i>
And he does not
have much to lose.
How's your sister?
Did she convince you to leave me yet?
No, but she did tell me to check
your phone for dating apps.
<i>The only apps on my phone
are the ones that came with it.</i>
- And the Olive Garden.
- <i>Ah.</i>
- Because when you're there...
- You're family.
No way.
The raccoons are back.
And they are in for a surprise.
Your surprise better not be
my tranquilizer gun.
They're just hungry.
<i>And also, that's for bears.</i>
- Good. Now I know it'll work.
- <i>Tom!</i>
I'm kidding. I'm just gonna
use it to scare 'em.
Possibly to death.
- <i>Love you, honey, bye!</i>
- Tom...
D-I-V-O-R-C-E.
Okay, I'm in.
With minimal damage
to Donut Lord's property.
Here we go.
It didn't work out on Earth,
but that's okay.
You're going to a safe world.
A nice, safe world
full of mushrooms.
Mushrooms that'll be
your only friends.
That sounds awful.
I can't do this.
You have to do it.
There's no other option.
All right.
SFPD...
pending background check.
Paws in the air!
Uh, meow?
Ow!
"San... Francisco?"
No.
What?
The blue devil.
- Donut Lord?
- It can talk.
You're not...
You're not here
to abduct me, are you?
You abducted me.
Okay, that's a fair point.
What are you?
Why are you hiding out
in my garage?
I needed somewhere safe.
And you're the only person
I could think of, Donut Lord.
Why do you keep
calling me Donut Lord?
'Cause you talk to donuts.
And then eat them
if they get out of line.
Again, fair.
Wait, wait, wait.
Where are all the mushrooms?
Why am I still on Earth?
What is...
Oh, no!
I lost my rings.
What?
What's happening?
Is this your mother ship?
I'm not in the mood
to get probed.
You think you're worried?
I'm not even wearing pants.
What the...
- They're coming for me!
- Who's coming for you?
- What's that got to do with me?
- I don't have time to explain,
but you have to help me.
No, I don't. Why?
Well, my legs,
which normally would be classified
as lethal weapons,
feel like spaghetti.
I need your help. Please.
It's life or death.
Fine. Come with me.
Uh, little help?
All right, stay here.
And be quiet.
Good plan. Great plan!
We're already working
so well together.
Practically finishing
each other's sentences.
Okay, bye.
Hello there!
Can I help you?
Good morning,
my rural chum.
I'm... from the power company,
investigating the blackout.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to take a few readings
inside your house?
No kidding?
You're from the power company?
- Mmm.
- Oh, you must know my buddy Spencer.
- We play softball together.
- Ah! Spence.
He's a good man.
- Yeah. Come on in!
- Great.
Take all the readings you need.
Except, uh...
Doesn't the power company usually take
their readings from outside the house?
That way they can check them
even if you're not home.
Also, my buddy Spencer
works for the gas company,
and he's more of
an Ultimate Frisbee guy.
So you want to tell me
why you think I'm dumb enough
to just let you
walk inside my house?
- I'm sorry, Mister...
- Wachowski.
Except my dentist,
he calls me Tim.
But it's gone on
for so long now
that it would just be weird
if I corrected him.
Well, Tom, whose-dentist-
calls-him-Tim.
You may have noticed
that this entire town
has been experiencing
a power outage.
Yep, no lights.
Picked up on that.
Twenty minutes ago, I tracked an
energy pulse with a similar signature
to the one that caused
that disruption.
Listen, uh, Mister...
Doctor.
Dr. Robotnik.
But my dentist calls me Rob.
Hmm.
Look, uh, Dr. Robotskeez.
Um, I'm sure what you're
here for is very serious,
but it's got nothing
to do with me.
You can ask anyone in town.
- Everyone knows me.
- I bet they do.
I'm sure you're hella popular
with the Jebs and Merles
and Billy Bobs,
in this glorified
gas-station rest stop.
Betcha go way back
to the days of tippin' cows
and playin' in a jug band!
And maybe someday
you'll achieve your goal
of getting a Costco card
or adopting a Labradoodle.
But the reality is,
I surpassed
everything you're
ever going to do...
before I was a toddler.
I was spitting out formulas while
you were still spitting up formula.
I was breastfed,
actually.
Nice.
Rub that in my orphan face.
Mr. Wachowski,
are you familiar with
US Code 904,
Title 10, Article 104?
- Yeah, who isn't...
- "Anyone...
who attempts to aid an enemy of the
United States shall suffer death."
And if I'm the one
that catches you,
it'll be even worse.
Worse than death?
Okay, I'm a ball,
a normal ball.
I'm blending in like a ball.
Shh. Stop talking.
No, <i>you</i> stop talking.
Be quiet, Sonic.
<i>You</i> be quiet, Sonic.
Oh, I hope they aren't
scanning me with X-rays.
I had kind of
an embarrassing lunch.
Don't freak out. Don't freak out.
Don't freak out.
I'm freaking out!
Why don't you have
your staircase carpeted?
Compared to what I...
- Old pipes.
- Yeah.
Probably just
the house settling.
Nothing to see here!
Hey!
Here's the thing.
I'm never wrong.
Well, first time
for everything, I guess.
Would you like some cake?
I hear raccoons have
the cleanest mouths
of any animal that
routinely eats garbage.
Look at that.
I was right.
Note the lack of surprise.
Shall we try this again?
I'm going to give you five
seconds to tell me where it is.
Five...
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- Four.
- Hey, tough guy. I'm a cop,
and you're
threatening an officer.
How can you threaten somebody
who never existed?
Three...
Come on!
Rack your brain.
You might be able to come up
with some lame excuse
to go on living
in two...
one.
Wait! Don't hurt him!
This feels excessive.
Stay behind me.
Hiya!
Don't worry. I got it
right where I want it!
Can you believe Amazon is gonna
deliver packages with these things?
This was a horrible plan!
What was I thinking?
I'm gonna puke!
Come on!
We gotta get out of here.
Oh, don't tell me
that's all you got!
I'm just getting started!
Let me know if you want to go
round two with the blue.
Doctor! Are you okay?
I saw a guy race out of here
and thought...
That you should
stop them?
Open your mouth...
and say you thought that you
should stop them.
No, I thought that maybe
I should check
to see if you were okay...
You know what's hard about being
the smartest person in the world?
You got that one.
Whatever this creature is,
it's our job to secure it,
neutralize it,
uncover the source of its power.
And if it resists,
we take it apart...
piece by piece.
See what makes it tick.
- Stone?
- Doctor?
Call Optical Illusions.
Tell them I need new frames.
They know what kind I like.
Oh, and bring that quill.
Yes, Doctor.
All right, pal,
you need to start talking
right now.
Who are you? What are you?
I'm a hedgehog!
I feel like that's obvious.
- And I'm in big trouble.
- Oh, <i>you're</i> in big trouble?
You're not the one who punched some
sort of government weirdo back there.
You think <i>you</i> have problems?
I lost my rings.
Rings?
What are you talking about?
Okay. Rings are how
all advanced cultures
travel between worlds.
And now mine are
on top of a pointy building
- I've only ever seen on your skintight T-shirt.
- Hey.
So, I'd like you to take me
to San Francisco,
so I can get back my rings
and use them
to go to the mushroom planet.
- Mushroom planet.
- Yes!
Right.
- Okay, pal, out you go.
- I'm sorry, what?
for me to get myself
into trouble, okay?
You asked me to save your life,
I saved your life.
Now, please, go find your rings.
And your mushroom land.
Hopefully I'm gonna wake up
in a hospital bed
and the doctor's gonna tell me
that my colonoscopy
was a big success, okay?
So goodbye.
- Okay. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Why aren't you leaving?
- I don't know where San Francisco is.
- It's west.
- West?
Straight shot, can't miss it.
Fine. That's cool.
I'm totally cool
saying goodbye now.
So, as I crashed into the cold,
dark water of the Pacific,
I realized a few things.
A, I have no idea
where I'm going.
B, saltwater stings.
C, I shouldn't even be on
this planet right now, but I am.
Why? Because you shot me!
- I know.
- You shot me!
All right, I heard you
the first time.
You don't have to pile it on.
Good grief.
I'm wet. I'm cold.
There's a fish on my head!
And clearly, I'm not gonna
be able to do this on my own.
All right,
get in the truck.
Really? You're gonna help me?
I guess it is a little bit my fault
that all this is happening to you.
Not a little bit. Entirely.
It is entirely your fault.
Okay, it's entirely my fault.
Are you coming?
Yes.
Road trip! Whoop-whoop!
What am I doing?
All right, there's
gonna be rules on this trip.
Number one, do exactly
as I say all the time.
- Got it?
- Got it, Donut Lord.
Would you stop
with the "Donut Lord"?
I have a name. It's Tom.
I'm Sonic.
Sonic. Sonic.
So you've been
spying on us all for years.
I wouldn't call it "spying."
We were all just hanging out,
only I wasn't invited
and no one knew I was there.
I can't believe Crazy Carl
was right all this time.
Yeah. You should call him
Super Observant Carl instead.
- Oh, my God, stop the car right now!
- What? What?
The World's Largest
Rubberband Ball?
- We gotta see it!
- No. No.
No, this is not some
fun family road trip, okay?
The government wants
to dissect you.
And arrest me. This is serious.
Eh, you're right, it was lame.
Gift shop was cool, though.
I got you a mouse pad.
When are we gonna get there?
We will get there
when we get there.
I'm gonna go check in with Wade,
see if he knows what's going on.
You're gonna see Wade
in that glass thing?
What is it, a teleportation box?
It's a pay phone.
It's mostly for drug dealers
and fugitives from the law,
which is us.
Stay in the car.
I don't want anybody seeing you.
Fine.
Huh?
Okay, okay.
That is the coolest place on Earth,
but you have to stay in the car.
Be strong. Be strong.
Hmm.
Hello.
Green Hills Police Department.
- Wade, it's me.
- <i>Hi.</i>
I'm so glad that you called.
Uh, so, some guys came in
asking some questions.
Uh, they're a little creepy.
Kind of reminded me of
the guys from <i>Men in Black,</i>
but not as likable
or charming as Will Smith.
Wait, what kind of questions?
Um, questions about terrorism?
I told them that I've gone
ice fishing with Tom.
He doesn't know how
to make a bomb.
<i>He can't even
make bait in the cold.</i>
All right, Wade, listen to me.
This is really important.
Don't tell them
that we talked, okay?
You know, I think
they already know.
Mr. Wachowski.
Tom.
I want you to know
that the only other person
who ever punched me in the face
was the school bully.
He hit me in the cafeteria,
causing a blunt-force contusion
to the soft tissue
surrounding my orbital bone.
Humiliated me in front of
the entire school!
And do you know
what I did in response?
Uh, I'm assuming that you reported
him to the principal's office
'cause that kind of behavior
is really unacceptable.
No. I examined the inefficiency of
a world where brawn trumped brain
and I used technology
to resolve that inefficiency.
The boy ate his meals
through a straw for a year.
And I have never
lost a fight again.
Until today.
Hey, hooray for me then, huh?
No, because you're about to
become the bully with the straw!
I'm coming for you,
Mr. Wachowski.
And when I catch you, I'll...
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, hello, hello?
I think he actually hung up,
because I notice
that the light isn't on.
Thank you, Officer Brainfart.
If you give me a second,
I can get an outside line.
No. Don't be bothered.
You just sit there and be "u"...
...'seless.
No one's gonna
erase my memory here?
I will tell people about this!
Okay, not exactly
the healthiest meal, but...
Sonic?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no!
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
Howdy, pardner!
I'm not your partner.
Come on. We're leaving.
But there's a ZZ Top cover band.
You gotta see their beards.
You're gonna have to catch 'em
some other time. Let's go. Get up!
If we stay, I won't say another
word for the rest of the trip,
starting... now.
Welcome to the Piston Pit.
What can I get you fellas?
I want nachos and buffalo wings,
oh, and guac.
Funny word, isn't it?
Guac, guac! Guac.
Hey, no kids
allowed in here.
What's he got on,
some kind of mask?
Oh, he's actually
43 years old and, um,
suffers from
a very rare skin disease
that stunts his growth and makes him
look, uh, like that.
The face,
I was born with.
The confidence,
I picked up along the way.
- Make his a Mello Yello, please.
- Okay.
- You owe me one.
- I never sat on a barstool before.
So squishy!
Oh, look at this.
It spins.
- Yes.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- That's nice.
- I feel sick.
Are you having fun?
Gonna check this off
the ol' bucket list, huh?
- Big night for you.
- What's a bucket list?
A bucket list is, uh...
It's a list of things
you want to do in your life
before you, well,
kick the bucket.
I've never
kicked a bucket, either!
Oh, I gotta make my list.
Uh-huh. Mm-hmm.
Oh, Sonic!
Uh-huh.
What? What's the matter?
There's so much stuff
I've never done.
And now that I'm
leaving Earth forever,
I guess I missed my chance.
Well, I guess
this is the kind of place
you could get a lot of living
done in a short period of time.
I suppose we can spare an hour.
What? You're gonna
bucket-list with me?
- Sure, why not?
- You won't regret this.
Oh, I'm pretty sure I will.
New high score!
Yippee-ki-yay!
Ah-ha!
Wait a second,
is this bull missing a head
or does it have two butts?
This is easy.
- Okay.
- Ha-ha! Yeehaw!
I'm a cowboy, baby!
I'm okay.
Whoo!
Whoo! Yeah!
Ha-ha-ha!
Yeah, yeah, laugh it up.
Nice work, Romeo.
Glad you're having a good time.
I am having a good time!
I'm having the best time.
I mean, what could go wrong?
Uh...
Can we help you?
We don't like
your kind around here.
Our kind?
What kind is that?
Hipsters.
- How dare you.
- Oh, hey. You know what?
We were leaving anyway.
Weren't we?
- There's not a problem here.
- No, no, no, it's okay.
No, no, no,
we're leaving.
I know exactly
how to handle this situation.
Pop quiz, hotshot.
You just picked a fight with
a poorly disguised hedgehog
who's seen way too many
action movies.
What do you do? What do you do?
Huh. Am I crazy?
It's supposed to break, right?
Dink! Dink-dink!
Break, please. Break, please.
Break this bottle, please.
- Please, please, please.
- Uh, Sonic?
Uh-oh!
- Oh-ho-ho-ho!
- Nice going!
Thanks! It's awesome right?
All right, who's next?
Who wants some?
Who do I get to beat up?
Hey! Has anybody
seen my waitress?
Still waiting on
those buffalo wings.
Why, you!
Ha-ha-ha!
Uh-oh!
Really?
<i>Ol!</i>
- So, should we get out of here?
- Yeah, time to go.
That was amazing!
Wait a second.
Did we even pay our tab?
It doesn't matter!
Watch this, watch this.
I always wanted to do this.
- Get 'em!
- See ya, suckers!
I can't say for sure,
but I think they liked me.
Come on!
Don't let 'em get away!
- Oh, yes!
- Yeah!
- Yes!
- Ouch!
He got you pretty good.
I'm all right.
I've been hit harder.
Did you see how much
toilet paper I used?
The next person that goes into that
bathroom will have nothing to wipe with!
The floors were sticky.
The crowd was rough.
And the odds
were against us.
But there was no stopping
Donut Lord and the Blue Blur.
Scratch another one
off my list.
You are a weird little dude.
Mmm.
Okay.
So what are we gonna do now?
I'm gonna pass out watching TV.
I think you should too.
But this is my
last night on Earth.
I want to soak up
every last second.
All right, well, anything you
can find to do in this room,
you knock yourself out.
Good times.
Oh, come on.
That's awful.
What did you eat?
I think it's called a chili dog?
You might want to check
your fur on that one, buddy.
Hey. So, what's this next planet
you're supposed to go to like?
It's no Earth,
I can tell you that.
There's no people,
just breathable air
and giant mushrooms and stuff.
Well, look at it this way.
At least you won't be
the only "fun-guy."
No. Don't ever do that again.
I liked it.
I'm really gonna
miss this place.
I know I have to
leave Earth to be safe,
but what if
Longclaw was wrong?
Maybe I could have a life here.
All right.
We should get some sleep.
You sleep.
Don't worry about me.
I'm gonna stay up all night
enjoying Earth while I can.
Sure, kid.
As long as we're
on the road by 8:00.
I ate a chili dog.
That's why my farts smell.
<i>Thomas Wachowski, accused of committing
an act of domestic terrorism.</i>
<i>Wachowski is considered
armed and dangerous.</i>
<i>Any information
regarding his whereabouts</i>
<i>should be reported to
local authorities immediately.</i>
Did he say where he was going?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Like I'd ever tell you.
Stand down, Agent Stone.
This well-meaning citizen obviously doesn't
understand the urgency of the matter.
Really?
Now that's
what I call good cop, bad cop.
Hoy!
Left yourself open.
Judging by the quickest route
to San Francisco,
the approximate
speed of their vehicle,
and local weather conditions...
They should be...
right about...
here.
- That's brilliant, sir.
- Thanks...
for nothing.
- So, what's on your bucket list?
- Who, me?
Yeah. Everyone has
a bucket list, right?
Sure, but...
I mean, you're the one
leaving Earth, and...
I'm not planning
on dying anytime soon.
Don't be so sure.
Are you anointing yourself
as the bestie?
Mm-hmm.
A little presumptuous, but...
I mean... What, no...
I like you, of course, but,
you know,
we're not best friends.
You tucked me in last night.
Fine, fine, fine.
Best animal friend.
- That would be my dog, Ozzy.
- Okay...
let's drop this increasingly
humiliating topic of conversation.
Bucket list.
Give it to me!
Okay, there is one thing.
In Green Hills,
I've always felt,
I don't know, more like a babysitter
than a real cop, you know?
So I want a chance to prove
myself, under real pressure.
I'm gonna move to San Francisco,
become a street cop.
And, I don't know,
see if I have what it takes.
What?
Why...
Why is your face doing that?
You're leaving Green Hills?
Okay.
B-B-But why?
Why would you leave Green Hills?
This may be hard for you to understand,
but Green Hills is a small town.
It's a very small town.
Uh, it's not small.
There are hundreds of people.
That's a small town, dude!
It's a perfect town,
and the people need you.
Please.
I clean out their gutters.
I jump-start their cars
in the winter.
They could call anybody
to do that.
Sure, they can call anybody,
but they don't.
They call you.
Eeny, meeny, miny...
mayhem.
- You're not making any sense.
- Would you calm down?
You come from a great town with
great people and by my count,
zero bad guys
trying to kill you!
Besides, what could possibly
be more important
than protecting
the people you care about?
- Look, I get your poi...
- Whoa!
Yeah!
You know what?
I was wrong about you.
You're not
the Donut Lord at all.
You're more like the Jerk Lord.
Have you noticed the harpoon
stuck in our dash?
Sonic!
I was forced from my home.
Your home is perfect,
and you're leaving it.
Why would you do that?
- Your body!
- Oh, no, not again!
Hey! Hold on!
- Why?
- Because I'm gonna do this.
Sonic!
Guess I had a bonus life.
Oh, yeah, baby!
Sonic, one. Big Tank, zero.
I'm sorry.
- Did we get that on camera?
- How are you not dead?
I have no idea.
- Do you see me dancing?
- Yes, I saw you dance.
Is that all you got?
No, but thank you for asking.
- Uh-oh.
- Sonic! Get back in the truck!
You go. I'll catch up.
Ha!
I think that tank
just had a baby.
Incoming!
- It's my turn!
- You just had one. It's mine!
Hey, stop fighting
or I'm taking that thing away!
Yeah, right, Dad.
Where are you going?
Just drive the car.
I'll take care of this.
And if I don't make it,
just ditch me.
You seem good at that.
<i>Hey, everyone!
Welcome back to my livestream.</i>
<i>Today we're destroying robots.</i>
Step one.
Yes, we did it!
We did not do it.
Who <i>is</i> this guy?
Ever wonder where
your tax dollars are going?
My turn.
Here, just keep us
going straight.
I put it in cruise control.
I feel just like Vin Diesel.
"It's all about family, Tom."
Quick suggestion.
Roll up into a ball
and smash him with your body.
Whoa! Where'd you
learn how to drive?
Here. In this truck.
It's happening as we speak.
I can't reach it.
Bring him in closer.
- What?
- Bring it in closer!
- Hit the brakes.
- Oh, you mean this one?
The other brakes!
Ha-ha! Whoo!
Oh!
Give me a big, fat break!
Aw, this one is cute.
Let's keep him.
Aah!
Oh, come on!
How could something
so adorable be so terrible?
You've got car insurance, right?
Buzz off.
That doesn't sound good.
- No, beeping is bad. Get rid of it!
- I'm trying.
Throw it out the win...
Throw it anywhere!
- I can't get it off.
- All right, I'm pulling over.
- Did I get it?
- Nope.
Here. Hold still.
It's going,
it's going...
It's still here.
Get off me.
Ha-ha! Nailed it!
Sonic!
No, no, no, no, no.
Hey. Come on. You're all right.
Wake up. Wake up.
Did we get 'em?
Oh. No, there they are.
They are real survivors,
those two.
Can we have a moment?
Pin yourself
to the wall.
You know, I won't miss you
when you're gone.
Human beings are
unreliable and stupid,
and I care very little
about them.
But my machines are diligent,
relentless.
They're everything to me!
Huh?
Mmm?
Come on, buddy.
You're gonna be all right.
You'll be all right.
- Is Maddie here?
- No, no.
- Not today. Goodbye.
- It's an emergency!
- Bye-bye.
- Rachel, stop! Maddie!
Don't do this.
This is important.
- Oh, my God! Rachel, let him in.
- I am calling the police.
No, I am calling the FBI.
I am calling the CIA.
- Stop. Don't do that.
- I am calling your mother.
- Okay, got it.
- Maddie, can we talk?
Tom, what's going on? You're all over
the news. I've been trying to call you.
I had to ditch my phone
so they couldn't track me.
- Ditch his phone?
- Track you?
- Uncle Tommy!
- Jojo! Hey!
Now your niece is
an accessory to treason.
- No, she's not.
- Calm down.
Calm down?
I will not calm down!
- Enough.
- Yes, calm down. Stop talking.
No. Ozzy, please.
Good to see you too.
Oh, little Lord Baby Jesus.
What is that, Tom?
Is that plutonium?
Is it e-mails?
Yes, it's plutonium.
Can we please go in
the other room and talk...
Stop it, Ozzy. Quit it!
This is why I told you
he was no good.
- I'm not engaging.
- No, Ozzy, quit it.
Ozzy, no! Ozzy, no!
Oh, catch me, Jojo.
Oh, thank God.
Can I get a glass of water?
I just thought
you might like a latte
with steamed Austrian goat milk.
Who do I look like,
an imbecile?
Of course I want a latte.
I love the way you make them!
Ready the prototype.
With this kind of power,
my machines can finally reach
their full potential.
He's gonna be okay, Jojo.
Oh, thank God.
He's gonna be okay, right?
I'm a vet, Tom. I don't even
know what I'm looking at here.
He's a hedgehog.
Or so he says.
- It talks?
- Almost constantly.
Okay.
- Holy...
- What?
His pulse is super-fast.
That actually
might be normal for him.
I don't know.
You gotta help him, Maddie.
I don't know his physiology.
He doesn't seem
to have any broken bones.
He's just really banged up.
Oh, look at
his poor little feet.
Hang in there, buddy.
You're gonna be all right.
Jojo?
Untie your mother. Jojo!
Untie Mommy.
Sweetie. Jojo!
I have to go to the bathroom.
- He's gonna be okay, right?
- Uh...
He'll snap out of this.
He'll wake up soon?
Oh, smelling salts!
Don't you have, like,
vet smelling salts,
like for cats or parakeets
or something?
No. They don't make
cat smelling salts.
- They should.
- I have human smelling salts
in my human first aid kit.
Okay.
- Here we go.
- Come on, buddy.
Gotta go fast!
- Whoa.
- Where am I? What year is it?
Is The Rock president?
Whoa, buddy, you're okay.
Calm down.
Oh, hi, Pretzel Lady!
Hi.
- Tom?
- Yeah.
Can I talk to you, please?
Space hedgehog, stay there.
Try to rest.
You got it.
I am great at resting.
I rest faster than anybody.
Still talking.
Uh, first of all,
can we take a moment
to acknowledge how
under control I've been?
- Amazing.
- Didn't freak out.
- No.
- Totally calm.
- Thank you.
- Ahh.
Second of all...
What the heck is going on?
Is that thing an alien?
Okay, so, remember how Crazy
Carl is always going on
- about the blue devil?
- The blue devil!
- That's him? He's real?
- Yeah.
What is he doing here?
What are you doing here?
I... kinda sorta...
shot our little blue friend
with your tranq gun.
- No, you did not.
- I didn't mean to.
This is kinda hard
for me to explain.
And it's gonna sound
a little bit crazy.
He has to get to
the Transamerica building,
and I promised
I'd take him.
Uh-uh! Aliens?
Maddie, your husband's
lost his mind.
Use this as an opportunity
to leave him.
No one would judge you.
So you won't
hurt your feet anymore.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
No one's ever
given me a gift before.
I gotta check that
off my bucket list.
All right! Looking good!
Okay.
You said you wanted to help
people in real trouble, right?
Well, that's what you're doing.
Blue alien hedgehogs still
count as people. Right?
- I think so too.
- Yeah.
- I think.
- Okay.
I love you.
Did I tell you that already?
I don't deserve you.
You know that?
I know that.
So, you're supposed to be
Tom's best friend
that he won't shut up about.
Well, I don't see the appeal.
Stop!
That is very gross.
- Hey.
So, my truck still runs,
but it's pretty much totaled.
You think your sister would
mind if we borrowed her car?
You have got to be kidding me!
- She'll be fine.
- Yeah, let's do that.
Mm-hmm.
This is my house!
Coming through!
Whoa, whoa! Now this is my turn,
and I go around you.
Sorry! And...
- perfect park.
- What are you, crazy?
Is there anything
you didn't hit?
Why did we let the alien drive?
Hey, I got us here.
And please, five stars.
- So, this is it?
- That's it. That's your pyramid.
Wow, look at that thing!
What happens now?
- Oh. He's... gone.
- Yep.
No good. You need a special
key to get to the roof.
What now?
Time for me to abuse
the power entrusted to me.
We got a jumper on the roof.
Gotta get up there fast
or we're gonna have
a human pancake on our hands.
You came all the way
from Montana.
Yeah. That's how serious it is.
Okay.
You just saved a life.
How much longer?
I can't breathe in here.
Hello?
Anybody there?
Do you have your child
in that bag?
No.
I mean, yes, it's a child,
but it's not mine.
It's not your child.
Relax.
I'm a cop, okay?
Plus, he likes it in there,
don't you, buddy?
Why would I
like it in here?
This is worse than the dog cage
you had me in earlier.
Such a kidder.
- Okay.
- No, I'm scared of the dark!
Is anybody there?
What were you
keeping in this bag?
A jar of pickled farts?
All right.
What are we looking for?
This.
Okay.
What happens now?
Now all I have to do
is think of where I want
the other end of the ring
to appear, and I throw it.
So that's it?
We did it?
Yeah. We did it!
Hey. Sorry we didn't get to do
everything on your bucket list, pal.
It's okay.
I did the ones I needed the most.
You two are so cute.
- Oh, please. What?
- We are not.
No.
We're not cute.
We are a couple of loose cannons
just living by our own rules.
Exactly.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And our rules include
expressing heartfelt emotions.
If you say so.
- Okay, then.
- All right.
- Um, you gotta go, right?
- Yeah, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
We gotta go too.
See... All right, bye-bye.
Just one more thing.
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
I know it's a tough decision
for you to leave Green Hills.
Walking away from
something you care about
has to be painful.
You're not sure
you really want to go, huh?
I don't want to go,
but I can't stay.
As long as I'm here,
I put everyone in danger.
I just want you to know that
these last two days have been
the best two days of my life.
You know, I never
thought I'd say this,
but I'm actually gonna miss
you, you little blue devil.
I'll miss you too,
Donut Lord.
Thank you.
For what?
For saving my life.
Okay. Did someone leave
their "Find My Phone" on?
Welcome to San Francisco,
Mr. Wachowski.
Are you enjoying
the clam chowder?
It's the government wack job
who keeps trying to kill us.
Unsuccessfully!
Nice of you to swing by
on your way to Comic-Con.
Yeah,
what are you wearing?
It's a flight suit,
designed to modulate my body
temperature and reduce drag.
Yeah, and yet
you still are one.
Ooh-hoo! Good one.
You are catching fire,
Thomas.
Oh, and speaking of heat,
I see you've taken a lover.
Does she have a name
or should we just call her
"collateral damage"?
Hey, watch your mouth.
Unless you want a little more
of what I gave you earlier?
I punched him
in the face.
Oh! He punched him right in the face!
It was awesome!
The time for talking is over!
It's time to push buttons.
Your flying eggs are pretty
impressive, Mr. Eggman,
but let's face it,
you'll never catch me.
Confidence!
A fool's substitute
for intelligence.
- That's not good.
- Uh...
Sonic, I know you got the
super-speed and everything,
- but Maddie and I...
- Totally defenseless? Probably gonna get blown up?
Pretty much, yeah.
Don't worry.
I know exactly what to do.
I was not expecting that.
But I was expecting not to expect
something, so it doesn't count.
Pew, pew-pew-pew,
pew-pew-pew-pew!
Oh!
Come on!
Come on, come on, come on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
No, no, no!
Oh! Hi, Tom.
Glad you're here.
Could use some help.
Old Bessie's about to give birth.
Give me a minute.
Aah.
Can I give you one
genius piece of advice?
Don't run.
It'll only hurt more if you do.
And it's bad for your joints.
They've proved it.
All right, Eggman.
You wanna get fast?
Let's get fast.
The hard way it is.
That was an illegal left,
by the way.
<i>So, here we are again.</i>
<i>We've been through
so much together.</i>
<i>Now you understand why there's
a psychotic robot doctor</i>
<i>chasing a supersonic
blue hedgehog.</i>
<i>Want to know how it ends?
Yeah, me too.</i>
How is this possible?
No one's ever
caught up to me before.
Coming through!
<i>Sacrebleu!</i>
<i>Excusez-moi, monsieur!</i>
Here we go.
Room to open it up.
I can't lose him!
If you can't beat 'em,
blind 'em.
Lost visual contact.
You're not allowed up there!
It's one of the Seven Wonders!
Get out of here!
You're an astonishing
little creature.
It'll be fun to take you
back to the lab
for a litany of invasive
exploratory procedures.
Any last words?
Guac. I like that word.
I don't have to tell you how
many scientific breakthroughs
have been made possible
by animal testing.
You're being very selfish.
Going my way?
What the...
Who the hell
do you think you are?
I'm the Donut Lord,
you son of a...
Autopilot, adjust.
Why?
Why would you throw
your life away for this thing?
That's why I don't have friends.
Next thing you know,
you're somebody's best man.
They want to have
the wedding out of town.
Like nobody has anything
better to do!
Anyway, where were we?
Oh, yes.
You were about to die.
That's our sheriff
you're messing with.
And our blue devil...
who as everyone can see
is a very real creature,
and not at all invented by me.
- Oh, careful.
- Just... Just put it away.
Tom?
I don't mean
to be indelicate here,
but someone should get some ice,
keep the body fresh.
He's just a silly little alien.
He didn't belong here!
That little alien
knew more about being human
than you ever will.
His name was Sonic.
This was his home.
And he was my friend.
He's all yours.
Everyone, get back!
I think you have something
that belongs to me.
Whoa.
This is my power.
And I'm not using it
to run away anymore.
I'm using it
to protect my friends.
Ooh! Now you've done it!
Guess what, Eggman?
I'm not leaving Earth. You are.
Donut Lord?
- I told you, you got this.
- Hey, <i>we</i> got this.
- I think these belong to you.
- Thank you very much.
No more pushing people
off of buildings.
You know
I can't promise that.
- You did pretty good, space hog.
- Thanks, Donut Lord.
You're gonna have to explain
this "Donut Lord" thing.
Nope, sorry. That's for me
and the little guy. Right?
- We got our thing, you got your thing with your... sister.
- Oh, my God, my sister.
Gotta go fast. Gotta go fast.
Jojo, put on my Fitbit...
so I can at least
get some steps.
We can never go back there.
I mean, are we?
'Cause it kind of feels like
we're home right now.
Really?
I kind of feel like
I checked the "save a life" box
off my bucket list.
Now all I want to do
is spend my life
with the people
I care about.
I want to check that box.
Okay, I like that.
All right, everybody.
Nothing to see here.
Let's disperse.
Just another ordinary day
in Green Hills.
Carl,
I'll take that chain saw.
Come on. Let's go!
You act like
you've never seen a fight
between an intergalactic space
rodent and a robot with a doctorate.
You got enough there?
- Yes, Mr. Manager.
- Need any more?
You get that away.
Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski?
Yes?
A token of appreciation
from your government,
for keeping quiet about recent
incidents, which never occurred.
Wow!
- Wonder what it is.
- Money to fix the house?
- Letter from the President?
- You'll see.
Okay.
- Olive Garden.
- Hmm, yeah.
The way you said
"You'll see" made me think
it was something better
than the things we said.
Have you tried their
Never Ending Pasta Bowl?
It never ends.
- That sounds... fancy.
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Well, thank you.
We appreciate the gesture.
Oh, hey. I guess we can close the
file on that Robotnik guy, huh?
Just disappeared.
I'm sorry,
but no such person exists
or ever has existed.
I wish that were true.
You haven't by any chance
been in contact
with a certain alien creature
since the incident, have you?
Uncle Sam would love
to have a chat with him.
Very casual.
Brunch, perhaps.
Oh, you mean
the little blue guy.
- Mmm.
- No.
- No, nothing. No.
- Mm-mmm.
- Doubt we'll ever hear from him again.
Very well.
Okay.
- Thank you.
- Great.
Mmm.
Yep.
To be honest, I'm pretty
pumped about the pasta bowl.
So, do you guys wanna
watch a movie or what?
Sorry, buddy,
it's a school night.
It's time for you
to go back to your cave.
What?
It's 3:00 in the afternoon!
You know how you get
when you're tired. Come on.
Me? I'm not like anything.
- You guys are so uncool.
- Yeah, yeah, we know.
Hey, buddy, where you going?
You said I have to
go back to my cave.
We did.
Oh, my... Are you kidding me?
I can't believe it.
How did you...
It's... It's all here.
Look at this! Are you kidding?
And the beanbag?
No way!
How did you even get this?
And you got it all the way over...
Oh!
I love it, I love it,
I love it, I love it!
Well, welcome home.
Thank you, so much.
<i>Oh, no, you don't.</i>
<i>No second-best animal friends
allowed in my room.</i>
<i>Wait. What are you doing?</i>
<i>Stay away from me.
Stop it!</i>
<i>I'm warning you.
I've got nunchucks!</i>
<i>Hey, stop.
Okay, you can stay.</i>
My grasp on sanity remains...
absolute.
Isn't that right,
Agent Stone?
Why don't you get a head start?
Do some rock-connaissance.
Rock-connaissance!
Come on! That's hilarious!
What's the matter with you?
Here's the "sitch." Uninhabited planet.
No resources, no supplies,
no apparent way home.
A lesser man would die here.
I'll be home by Christmas.
Rock-connaissance!
Come on! Cheer up!
If these readings are accurate,
he's here.
I found him.
I just hope I'm not too late.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[Robotnik] Doctor's log.
It's day 243 in this...
portobello purgatory.
My only companion
is a rock I named Stone.
The question is,
for whom am I narrating this?
[shudders]
<i>It seems I've become a featured
player in the theater of the absurd.</i>
<i>Marooned in deep space
by that wretched blue rodent.</i>
<i>But it's all good,</i>
<i>thanks to a breathable atmosphere
and my supreme intellect,</i>
<i>sharpened against the only
competitor savvy enough to bring it.</i>
Chanterelle to d4. Mmm.
<i>I've been striving to make fungi
into a functional drink of choice...</i>
[sniffs] Mushroom coffee.
[slurps]
[sputters, gags]
<i>With limited...</i>
<i>limited...</i>
[gags, coughs]
<i>success.</i>
[gasps]
<i>But today, day 243,</i>
<i>has brought a new optimism
to my most pressing endeavor...</i>
<i>Planet us exodus to returnicus
and kick blue butticus.</i>
If my calculations are correct,
and there's no reason to say
"if" because they always are...
this quill is going to power
my masterpiece.
Let's light this candle...
and see who comes
a-knockin'. [Electricity crackling]
[shrieks]
Greetings! [Gasps]
[screaming]
<i>Klaatu barada nikto.</i>
[screams]
[weapons humming]
Agent Stone? Now!
[yells, grunts]
[Robotnik] Thank you, Stone.
It's time to say goodbye to
this piece-of-shiitake planet!
[grunts]
[panting]
Huh?
Where did you get that?
From a little blue menace
on the planet called Earth.
I'd be happy
to show you the way.
[chuckles] Oh.
[engine racing]
[sirens wailing]
They're still on us.
This'll slow 'em down. [Grunts]
[tires screeching]
["It's Tricky" playing]
<i> This speech is my recital
I think it's very vital </i>
<i> To rock a rhyme
That's right on time </i>
<i> "It's Tricky" is the title
Here we go </i>
<i> It's tricky to rock a rhyme
To rock a rhyme </i>
<i> That's right on time
It's tricky </i>
Watch out. Excuse me.
Pardon me. Coming through.
[song continues playing]
Good evening, gentlemen.
Mind if I drive?
[tires squealing] [screaming]
Better buckle up.
[robbers screaming]
How we doing back there?
And now this way.
[grunting]
[Sonic laughing]
Whoo-hoo!
[muffled shouting]
Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't speak duct tape.
[grunts]
What the heck are you?
Fear not, citizen.
I am the hero you need
and the hero you deserve.
The blue dawn
that banishes the darkest...
Holy crap!
[both screaming]
[tires squealing]
[screaming] Don't worry.
Nobody's gonna get hurt.
Huh. What are
those? Bombs. Bombs.
They're bombs! Those are bombs!
Relax. They're not even lit.
So I'll say again,
nobody's gonna get...
[screams] I was wrong! We're
all gonna die! [Whimpering]
Why aren't you slowing down?
That would require brakes.
Oh, it's hot. Hot, hot, hot!
Why don't you just let
the police handle this?
Thank you very much.
Please hold your applause.
[horns honking]
[fuse sizzling]
Do you hear that?
There's one bomb left.
Uh... Uh-oh.
Did you check under the seat?
Of course I checked
under the seat!
[horn honking]
You are terrible at this!
You know what? Your negative
attitude is not helping anyone.
It's in your spiky things!
Ha! I can never find
anything in here. [Grunts]
Drained it from downtown!
[mimics fanfare]
See? I told you
nobody would get hurt.
[people chattering]
Holy sherbet!
Oh, hello.
Don't panic.
This is only a drill.
[drill whirring]
[people exclaiming]
[guard screaming]
[breathing shakily]
[fuse sizzling]
[gasps]
[sirens wailing] [tires screech]
Come here!
No need to thank me, citizens.
All in a night's work for...
Blue Justice!
You're a terrible hero!
[Sonic laughing]
["Stars In The Sky" playing]
<i> The feelings running deep </i>
<i> Ain't no time for sleep </i>
<i> A second to unwind
Head up in the sky </i>
[Sonic] Morning, Wade!
Morning, Sonic!
[song continues playing]
[Sonic] Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Good morning, Green Hills!
[grunting]
Ah! Oop! Oh.
[sighs]
[floor creaking] [groaning]
[floor creaks louder]
Oh, come on.
Uh-oh. Uh...
[gasps]
[inaudible]
Oh, Sonic.
I miss you, Longclaw.
I'm trying to make you proud.
[yawning] And now
for a little shut-eye.
[lapping]
Oh! Blech!
Ozzy, morning breath!
Sonic. Are you still in bed?
You're supposed
to meet Tom, remember?
[grunts]
All right, all right,
I'm up! I'm up.
[Tom sighs] What a day.
Whoo!
Thanks for coming out, bud.
You know,
I feel like you and me,
we haven't had
much time together lately.
How's it going over there?
You getting any bites?
[snoring]
[screams] I can't swim! Help!
If I die,
don't look in my closet!
Hey, hey, you're good.
You're all right. Come on.
[shivering] It's freezing.
All right, okay. Take it easy.
[shivering]
All right. You're good. Okay.
But now that you've had
a nap and a bath...
<i>I went up to your room last night to
bring you some new comics and, um...</i>
<i>[Sonic on tape] Whoa, whoa,
whoa. Stop right there.</i>
<i>I wouldn't come any closer,</i>
<i>because this little hedgehog
had way too many chili dogs.</i>
<i>Oh, no. Oh, no. [Farts]</i>
<i>I'm so embarrassed.
Get out of here quick!</i>
<i>Oh, no, here comes another one!
[farts]</i>
<i>Go. Now. Save yourself.</i>
<i>[tape rewinds] Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop
right there. I wouldn't come any closer,</i>
<i>[distorting] because this little
hedgehog had way too many chili dogs.</i>
<i>Oh, no. Oh, no. [Farts]</i>
<i>I'm so embarrassed.
Get out of here...</i>
Ugh! I knew I should've
used real farts.
How many times
are we gonna do this?
What? Cast your line and not
catch anything? Seems like a billion.
I think you know
what I'm talking about.
The lying. The sneaking out.
The pretending to be Batman.
Blue Justice, trademark pending.
Whatever. You're being reckless.
Ugh!
Not this conversation again.
Hey. It's no fun for me, either.
But if you keep
being irresponsible,
we're gonna keep
having this conversation.
How is it irresponsible
to use my powers?
Sonic, you destroyed
an entire city block!
That block
was already messed up.
Who cares?
Look, I stopped a robbery.
I was a hero.
No, you put people in danger
and that's not what a hero does.
[sighs] You're supposed
to be my friend.
Stop trying to be my dad.
[sighs]
I can take care of myself.
Sonic, taking care of yourself
is not what being
a hero's all about.
It's about taking
responsibility for other people.
And right now,
whether you want to hear this or not,
you are still just a kid.
You got some more
growing up to do
before you're ready
to be the big hero.
But trust me when I tell you,
there will come a time when
your powers will be needed.
But you don't choose
that moment.
That moment chooses you.
Whoa. Look at you. [Chuckles]
Look at that.
I just got goose bumps.
Wait a second.
Did you steal that from Oprah?
No, sir. That is
a Wachowski family special.
Came from my dad,
in this very boat,
on this very lake.
He would always try and steer me
in the right direction.
And that's what Maddie and I
have always tried to do with you.
So, until your moment arrives,
I want you to work on
being a little more responsible.
<i>Comprende?</i>
<i>Comprende.</i>
High five on it.
Yeah! Donut Lord and the
Blue Blur are back at it again!
Hang on.
Speedboat!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
[Sonic laughing] [Tom] Sonic!
[Sonic] Whoo-hoo!
How excited are you,
going to Hawaii with me? Oh, Hawaii.
Oh, yeah! [Chuckles]
Wow. [Laughs]
Welcome to Sonic Air,
the fastest way to travel.
Now boarding groups one and two.
[laughs] Oh!
Sonic, this is so fun!
I'm sorry, ma'am,
you're group three. Please wait your turn.
Anyone from groups one and two?
Just let him get it out
of his system. Nobody?
Okay, then everybody else
right this way.
Thank you.
[imitating
electronic scanner noises]
[laughs]
And you, sir?
[imitating scanner]
Terrible shirt detected.
There we go.
Okay, you're free to go.
Enjoy your trip.
Bye-bye now.
[sighs] Okay.
Bring it in.
Tom, I'm about to be hedgehog
of the house for the first time.
I think I'm a little mature
to hug you goodbye.
Okay,
what about a power bump? Power bump?
Yes, power bump.
That's more like it.
[all] Wachowski!
Okay, use this one
to get back home.
Oh!
All right, we're off. Be good.
Yes. You have our number.
Sorry! Can't hear you! You're traveling
through a cross-dimensional portal!
Miss you already! Okay?
Have fun at Rachel's wedding!
Okay, it's 48 hours
until they come back.
We've got TV channels,
streaming channels,
a house full of food
and no supervision.
[barks]
Let's do this.
["Here Comes The Hot step per"
playing]
<i> Na-na-na-na </i>
<i> Here comes the hot step per
Murderer </i>
<i> I'm the lyrical gangster
<i> Pick up the crew in-a de area
Murderer </i>
<i> Still love you like that
<i> Extraordinary
Juice like a strawberry </i>
<i> Money to burn, baby
All of the time </i>
<i> Cut to fit is me </i>
<i> Fit to cut is she </i>
<i> Come juggle with me
I say every time </i>
<i> Here comes the hot step per
Murderer </i>
<i> I'm the lyrical gangster
<i> Dial emergency number
Murderer </i>
<i> Still love you like that
<i> Nah, na-na-na-nah </i>
<i> Na-na-na-na, na-na-na
Na-na-na </i>
<i> Na-na-na-nah </i>
[siren noise playing]
<i> It's how we do it, man </i>
Whoo-hoo!
<i> Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na </i>
<i> Na-na-na-nah </i>
<i> Yeah, man </i>
<i> It's how we do it </i>
<i> Na-na-na-na
Na-na-na, na-na-na </i>
<i> Na-na-na-nah </i>
[device beeping]
If these readings
are accurate, he's here.
I found him!
I just hope I'm not too late.
[grunts]
[device beeps]
Hmm. He's close.
I just need a way to reach
him without being spotted.
Standard human transport.
Perfect.
<i> This is how we do it </i>
[phone buzzing]
<i> It's Friday night </i>
Uh-oh.
Oh, boy.
[clears throat]
<i>Aloha! [Laughs]</i>
<i>How's it going, bud?
[Sonic] Oh, you know.</i>
Just a quiet night at home,
settling in with a good book.
<i>And you? What's up with you?</i>
I was just calling
to say we're here.
<i>But now every word out of your
mouth is making me suspicious.</i>
What? You got to relax,
buddy. You're at the Four Seasons Oahu.
Have a Mai Tai.
Enjoy some time with your wife.
Get sunburned
somewhere embarrassing.
<i>This weekend is about you.</i>
You know what? You're right.
We power-bumped on it.
So whatever it is you're doing,
I'm sure you can undo it
by the time we get home, yeah?
<i>Exactly! I mean,
I am deeply offended by such accusations!</i>
<i>So, how's Rachel's fianc?</i>
<i>Is he as good-looking in
person as he is in pictures?</i>
Hey, baby.
[sighs] Somehow better-looking.
<i>[Sonic] Wow! You're about to be the
third best-looking dude in the family.</i>
<i>But, hey, still on the podium.</i>
Ha-ha-ha.
All right,
I better go and introduce myself.
<i>Stay out of trouble.</i>
Trouble? Don't worry.
Everything here
is completely normal.
Uh-huh. Night, bud.
Hey! I was just
coming over to say hi.
You've got a lot
of nerve coming up in here
after what you did
to my fiance.
Wait. What? Totaling her car?
Leaving her tied to a chair?
I should rip you limb from limb.
[stammering]
[laughs]
Oh, my God, look at your face!
Tommy, breathe, baby.
Breathe. I was kidding.
Hey, man,
I was totally kidding. Okay.
You were kidding. Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Rachel put me up to it.
It was totally her idea.
That rascal.
Listen, I don't know
if you're aware.
Rachel does not care
for you at all.
Oh, I'm aware. Yeah.
Seriously, bro,
you got work to do.
Hey! Hey.
Good to see you!
Thanks for coming, Tom.
Really glad you came. Really?
Uh...
Great to see you, too.
Congratulations.
I mean, you guys seem
really happy together.
You know, you're all right,
Thomas Wachowski.
Ah.
Can we Bury the hatchet?
I'd love that.
Yeah? Yeah.
All right,
bring it in! All right! Great.
Oh. And if you screw up my wedding,
I will end you.
[people chattering on TV]
All right, Ozzy,
it's movie night at Casa de Sonic,
and it's your turn to pick.
<i>But I am not watching
Snow Dogs again.</i>
That movie is the worst!
[electricity powering down]
[laughs] Blackout!
[spooky wailing] Ozzy!
[Ozzy whines]
Oh, sorry, buddy.
Everything's okay.
Whoa!
[static on TV]
Uh, excuse me.
We did not order a poltergeist.
[thunder rumbling]
[electricity buzzing]
[heavy footsteps thudding]
Um, if this is the pizza guy,
this is really unprofessional.
Eggman?
[crackling]
Hello, hedgehog.
Did you miss me?
I don't know how you got back,
but you made
a big mistake coming here.
<i>Au contraire, mon frre.</i>
The mistake
was thinking you'd won.
But that was just a prelude,
an hors d'oeuvre,
an aperitif, an amuse-bouche.
I get it.
[laughs]
I don't think you do.
But you're about to.
And so will that idiot
sheriff and his wife.
And your little dog too!
[yells]
[Sonic grunts]
[groans]
Pitiful.
What? Who are you?
Where are my manners?
Sonic, meet Knuckles.
My new BFFAE.
Bestest friend forever and ever!
Look, Robotnik, I don't care
who you brought to help you.
You're never going
to get my power.
Do I look like
I need your power?
[both yelling]
[grunts]
So nice when diabolical evil
lives up to the hype.
[groaning]
[grunts]
Where is it?
Oh, you want it? Here it comes.
I was expecting more of you.
You're unskilled.
Untrained.
And unworthy!
You forgot one. Unstoppable.
[energy crackling]
[yelling]
[groaning]
It is my destiny to do
what my ancestors could not...
To restore the ultimate power
to the home of my people.
[Sonic] Ultimate power?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You've got the wrong guy.
Ultimate power?
Now you're speaking my language.
Don't play dumb with me,
apprentice of Longclaw.
You knew Longclaw?
Longclaw and her people were the
sworn enemy of my tribe, the Echidna.
We fought and died
at their hands,
and now you will die at mine.
[siren wailing]
[grunts]
[imitating
electric servo motors]
Come on. Get in!
I'm on your side.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
[groaning]
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
[grunts]
[both scream]
[Sonic] Get us out of here!
Go, go, go!
[tires squealing]
[grunting, snarling]
Ah! He's gone rabid!
[growling] [whimpering]
Gross! Is he licking it?
See ya!
[Sonic] Make sure
to get your shots, Eggman!
[panting]
[Sonic] Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
[yelling]
Wow. Okay. Let me just say
it is an honor to finally meet you,
Sonic.
Is it okay if I call you Sonic?
Everyone calls me Tails.
You're probably wondering why.
Let me guess. Because of
the extra tail? That's right!
I should've known
you'd get that. Cool.
Also, what is going on?
Robotnik's back?
[Tails] That's Knuckles,
the last of the Echidnas
and the most dangerous warrior
in the galaxy.
He's obsessed with finding
the Master Emerald.
[Sonic] Are you serious?
The Master Emerald?
That's just a bedtime story.
Well, he believes it's real.
And he must think
you're the key to finding it.
Red light! Give me the wheel!
Hey, what are you...
Move your foot.
[horn honking]
[Sonic yelling]
[sighs] I think we lost him.
[grunts]
[screams] We did not lose him.
We definitely did not lose him!
[whimpers]
I've got an idea.
Do you trust me?
Of course not!
I literally just met you!
Just let me... Come on!
What are you doing?
[Sonic screaming]
[screaming continues]
[grunts]
[whimpering]
We're flying.
Uh, did your butt just
turn into a helicopter?
[laughs] A butt-copter!
Oh, only Sonic the Hedgehog could
come up with something like that.
[tractor engine sputters, dies]
[grunts] [tractor hissing]
[chuckles] Foxy move.
You want something done right...
[electronic beeping]
You have to hire someone
you can push around.
All caps.
["Don't Know Why" playing]
[whirring]
<i> I waited till I saw the sun </i>
<i> I don't know why
I didn't come </i>
Doctor,
where are you?
[song continues playing]
[slams utensil on counter]
Freak.
[sighs]
[watch chimes]
Oh, I, uh... I'm sorry, folks.
Uh, I have to close early.
Everybody out!
Everybody out. Thank you
for visiting the Mean Bean.
All right, good night.
Good night.
[electronic whirring]
[scanner trilling]
He's back.
He's back!
[drones humming]
[inhales, exhales]
That's more like it.
I've been re-hatched!
[grunting]
[gasps]
[growls]
So, my massively
metacarpaled friend,
you mentioned... [howling]
Ultimate power.
Back at the house?
The Master Emerald?
It does not concern you.
I got you off that planet and
you brought me to the hedgehog.
We have no more use
for each other.
Well, I hate to be
a contrarian, but...
[gloves beep]
I think we might.
You think these machines
are a match for me?
I will shatter them
like the bones from a fallen...
Oh, they are stairs.
You see, Earth is my turf, G.
If you don't know how to floss,
you'll be lost without me.
I understand nothing
of what you just said.
I help you retrieve the Emerald,
and you use it to...
destroy the hedgehog!
You're suggesting an alliance.
Around here we simply
grip each other's hands tightly.
[bones cracking]
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
[gasping]
You truculent space bumpkin!
You've crushed my favorite hand!
Really? My hand is uninjured.
Ugh.
But I'm now convinced
of your commitment.
"Oh, goody,"
he exclaimed,
while he reset two of his knuckles.
[bones crack] I'm...
delighted to be
on the same team.
Road trip!
I'll let you stick your
nose out the window.
[Tails] Uh, Sonic, where are we?
Welcome to the Wade Cave.
Which is something I hope
to someday say to a woman.
A woman who's not my mom.
[chuckles]
Wade, focus.
We need to figure out
why Knuckles thinks
I'm the key to finding
the Master Emerald.
And why did he mention Longclaw?
There must be a connection.
Wait a minute. There is.
Look. There's an emerald symbol
on the map Longclaw gave me.
I never knew
what it meant before.
[Tails] Something's happening.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Longclaw?
Hello, Sonic.
If you're watching this,
then something has happened to me.
And I pray you've made it
to Earth unharmed.
This world has been chosen
for a very important reason.
It's the secret location
of the Master Emerald.
Whoa.
The Emerald has the power
to turn thoughts into reality.
<i>Like the Stay Puft Marshmallow
Man from Ghostbusters.</i>
Shh!
In the wrong hands,
it could threaten
all life in the universe.
Protecting the Emerald
was my sacred duty.
And now I must pass
that responsibility to you.
This is my moment.
Follow the map, find the Emerald,
and keep it safe.
My dear Sonic,
you have a heart like no
creature I've ever known.
I love you so much.
Goodbye.
No, no, wait. [Sighs]
I won't let you down, Longclaw.
So is that y-your dad?
What?
No?
According to this map,
the first clue is in Siberia.
It's a compass that
will lead to the Emerald.
And with Knuckles already here,
it's a race.
Knuckles?
I knew a kid in middle
school named Knuckles.
Could fit his whole fist
in his mouth.
If this is the same Knuckles...
[exhales] ...we are screwed.
This Knuckles,
that Knuckles. It doesn't matter.
We're gonna get there first.
[chuckles]
What do you mean, "we"?
You're coming with me.
Oh, no, no, no.
I just came here to warn you.
I'm not a field guy.
Don't worry. I got your back.
I won't let anything
happen to you.
It's a power bump.
On Earth, it means
an unbreakable promise.
Okay, I'm in.
["Me and You" playing]
<i> Me and you
Maybe sunshine, maybe rain </i>
Doctor. It's really you.
You look different.
Papa's got a brand new 'stache.
Ha!
I knew it. I knew it!
I knew you'd come back, sir.
I never stopped steaming
your Austrian goat's milk.
[Robotnik smacks lips]
Could use some mushroom.
You brought something.
Some kind of, uh,
space porcupine.
Porcupine? I am an Echidna!
Trained since birth in
all forms of lethal combat,
destined to restore honor
to my tribe,
and willing to destroy
anything that gets in my way.
Welcome to the team.
[bones cracking] [groaning]
[gasping] [laughing]
That means he trusts you, Stone.
Now let's renovate this dump!
Latte with steamed
Austrian goat milk!
[machinery whirring]
[grunts] [players cheering]
Good one. Solid.
[grunting]
[players laughing, cheering]
Sorry, fellas.
[player] That's game!
Ha! That's how we do!
That's how we do!
But are they good at math?
[player]
Teamwork makes the dream work!
Sorry about that, Big Tom.
Are you good? All good. Fine.
Thanks for inviting me out to
hang with you and your groomsmen.
Good quality bonding.
You know, bro,
those guys right there,
they're way more than my groomsmen.
That's my squad.
Never would've made it
through life without 'em.
Get over here!
Yeah, I'm coming! I'm coming!
I'll catch you later.
Hey. Yeah!
Let me know if you're ready
for some power yoga, huh?
You bet. Come on,
Tommy boy. Let's go.
Don't make me. [Laughs]
What am I doing?
Hey, Uncle Tommy!
Hey, girls!
How you do... Oh!
Are those the
wedding rings? Uh-huh.
May I?
This little ring bearer has been
taking her job very seriously.
She's been practicing
all morning.
I can see that.
How very responsible of you.
Except aren't there supposed
to be two wedding rings?
Uh-oh.
Uncle Tommy?
Hang on. What's going on here?
You're gonna do great, kiddo.
Bye.
Hey, baby. Hi.
[groomsmen cheering] [cork pops]
That's right!
Groom in the building!
Look at those guys.
I wish Sonic had that.
Muscles? Control yourself.
Mm-hmm.
No. Buddies. Wingmen. A squad.
Sonic doesn't have anything
like that. He's flying solo.
Baby, you got to relax.
You're at the Four Seasons.
Have a Mai Tai. Spend
some time with your wife.
That's what he said.
Seriously, his exact words.
See? He's a
smart kid. All right.
Hmm. He'll find his way.
I absolutely cannot find
my way. [Wind howling]
We are completely, totally,
unequivocally lost.
[device beeping]
Sonic, in this weather,
there's no way we're gonna get
any readings on this thing!
Should we go back?
No, no, no.
There's a light up ahead.
Maybe we can take shelter
in there.
Ah. Perfect.
Are you sure about this?
We don't know who's inside.
Don't worry. On Earth,
people are very welcoming,
and love taking complete
strangers into their homes.
[people chattering in Russian]
[up-tempo music playing]
[door creaks open]
[music and chatter stops]
[both gasp]
[both sigh]
[both scream]
[grunts]
Run.
[groans]
Table for two, please!
[speaking Russian]
Two beef stews, please.
[translating into Russian]
Where'd you get
all these cool gadgets?
I invented 'em.
That's kinda my thing.
In fact, my inventions
are how I discovered you.
<i>Remember that night
at the baseball field?</i>
<i>Your energy blast reached
all the way to my home planet.</i>
I saw you save your whole village
from that crazy mustache guy.
Wait, so you've been
watching me this whole time?
Even in the shower?
That's a trick question.
Sonic the Hedgehog
prefers bubble baths.
Man, you're good!
When I learned Knuckles
was on your trail,
I knew I couldn't just sit
back and watch anymore.
I had to come warn you.
[phone chimes]
Oh, what? Hang on one sec.
Donut Lord is checking in.
[Knuckles]
"Just chilling. Watching TV."
Dot, dot, dot.
Doctor,
why are we working
with this imbecile?
Because that simpleminded space trash
is the key to something extraordinary.
Something to help you
get revenge on the hedgehog.
Think bigger, Stone.
The emerald he seeks
could power my wildest designs.
My genius wouldn't
just be recognized on Earth.
It would spread virally
to every corner of the galaxy,
allowing me to harness all the
negative forces of the universe
and commune
with Darkness itself.
Wow. That sounds big.
It's been on my vision board for
years. It's the Law of Attraction.
<i>Didn't you see The Secret?
[chuckles]</i>
Kaplooey!
Kaplooey.
"Another boring night at home."
The hedgehog has returned home!
<i>Falsa.
Which is Latin for "wrong-o."</i>
According to my worldwide network
cell tower triangulation, he's lying,
all the way
from the majestic hinterlands
of Eastern Siberia.
He's a long-distance liar!
Kuh! Kuh! Kuh!
Nga-nga-nga-nga-nga!
Yeah, there's more
where that came from.
[Knuckles grunts]
Tiny magic hedgehog destroyed.
Now let's begin our quest.
Wait.
What about your Minion?
The goat milker.
There's no room
on the ship for Stone.
I say we ditch him,
ghost him, blow him off.
Dishonor!
"Dis" is how I roll.
Ugh!
Uh, I'm sorry,
but I asked for the beef stew.
[device speaking Russian]
[speaking Russian]
Uh...
Uh, what's going on?
Maybe they think
it's my birthday?
Don't worry,
I'll take care of this.
Okay, everybody, take it easy.
I'm sure there's
a perfectly good explanation
for whatever my friend said
or did.
[device speaking Russian]
[all muttering]
[whimpers] [yelps]
[all gasp]
Uh... meow?
[speaking Russian]
[crowd cheering]
Oh, no, no. Come on, guys.
Take it easy.
Let's talk this through.
Let's talk this through!
[whimpering]
Come on, come on.
Scanning Siberian customs.
There's got to be
something in here.
[Sonic] Tails,
whatever you're doing, do it fast.
Ooh! I think I got it!
<i>Pivonka! Pivonka!</i>
<i>Pivonka!</i>
<i>Oh? Pivonka?</i>
<i>[crowd murmuring] Pivonka.</i>
<i>Da.</i>
<i>Pivonka!</i>
[all cheering]
<i>Tails, what's a "pivonka"?</i>
It's a Siberian custom
to resolve disputes.
If we win, they let us go.
If we lose...
[both scream]
[shouting]
[shouts in Russian]
Okay, we have to grab the map
and get out of here. Where's the map?
Oh, no. I left it
on the table! Look!
[cheering, applause]
What?
[up-tempo music playing]
[music increases tempo]
[crowd cheering,
clapping rhythmically]
Oh, my God, it's a dance fight.
Sonic, what do we do?
We dance and get that map.
Here we go.
[grunts] Ow!
[crowd jeering]
Okay, now let's do... No,
we're gonna go... [grunts]
[grunts] Ah, okay. [Grunts]
Okay, this is not going well.
Channing Tatum
makes it look so easy.
Wait, Sonic. Look!
<i>[crowd] Opa! Opa! Opa!</i>
The map! Come on, let's grab it!
You want?
Come get.
Freaks! [Crowd jeering]
Freaks!
[all chanting]
Freaks! Freaks! Freaks!
[whimpering]
[gasps] What's wrong,
Tails? Come on. I need you!
I can't do this, Sonic.
I'm not brave like you.
My gadget got us in this mess,
and I lost your map,
and we're gonna get
tossed into a fire!
Ah...
New deejay coming in.
[feedback squawking]
["Uptown Funk" playing]
Come on, pal. I got an idea.
They called us freaks,
so let's get freaky.
Just follow my moves.
You'll be fine.
<i> Doh-doh-doh, doh-doh Aw, ow </i>
<i> This hit, that ice cold </i>
<i> Michelle Pfeiffer
That white gold </i>
<i> This one for them hood girls </i>
<i> Them good girls
Straight masterpieces </i>
<i> Stylin', wilin'
Livin' it up in the city </i>
<i> Got Chucks on
With Saint Laurent </i>
<i> Gotta kiss myself
I'm so pretty </i>
<i> Break it down
Girls hit your hallelujah </i>
<i> Whoo
<i> Whoo </i>
All right! Backup dancers!
<i> 'Cause uptown funk
Gon' give it to you </i>
<i> Saturday night
And we in the spot </i>
Here we go!
Oh! Ha!
[crowd exclaims]
Boom! Ah! Oh!
<i> Don't believe me Just watch </i>
Whoa! [Laughs]
Whoo-hoo! [Tails laughs] Yeah!
[Tails laughing]
[Tails] Whoo-hoo!
[Sonic] There's a lot
of me up here!
[Tails laughs]
[both laughing]
<i>[Sonic] I love pivonka!</i>
<i> Uptown funk you up
Uptown funk you up </i>
[Tails laughs] And big dismount!
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
[music stops]
[laughs]
I'll take that.
[crowd cheering]
Whoo-hoo! We did it!
That was amazing!
Way to go, Tails.
[laughs] Wow.
Only Sonic the Hedgehog
could win a dance battle that epic.
Well, stick with me, pal.
Earth can be a scary place,
but I know everything
about this old pale blue dot.
Do you really mean that?
I mean, not everything. But I watch
a lot of Discovery Channel and...
I meant about me being your pal.
Of course, buddy.
[laughs] Comin' in hot.
Growing up,
I didn't have any friends.
Everyone in my village
thought my two tails were weird.
Hey, I know that feeling.
But then I saw you,
the fastest creature in the galaxy.
You were weird too.
But you were a legend.
That made me think,
maybe being weird isn't so bad.
You inspired me
to leave my village,
to find you and help you
in your mission.
I'm really glad
you're here, Tails.
I'm glad I'm here too, Sonic.
[both yawn]
Well, might as well
get some sleep.
This feels like a good
place to spend the night.
You'll be able to get clear
readings on your gizmo thing
once the storm is over,
so I... [sighs]
[snoring]
Night, Tails.
[yawning]
[gasps]
Tails. Tails. We have
a situation. [Snoring]
[Sonic] Hoo-hoo!
Today's forecast calls for
clear, sunny skies
and a 100% chance of
adventure. [Device beeping]
I pinpointed the coordinates.
It's right up ahead.
[Sonic] Wow.
Hey, Tails. Wait up.
Whoa.
Okay,
we got a giant owl door. Seems encouraging.
[grunts]
Whoa.
[gasps]
Check this out.
Can you translate that?
Uh, yeah.
<i>[Tails] Ages ago,
a fearsome group of warriors,</i>
<i>known as the Echidnas,</i>
<i>forged the Seven Chaos Emeralds</i>
<i>into the most unstoppable
weapon ever created.</i>
The Master Emerald.
<i>With it, a single warrior</i>
<i>could defeat entire armies.</i>
[screams]
<i>[Tails] Believing no one should
have such power,</i>
<i>an order of heroes
recovered the Emerald</i>
<i>and swore to protect it
from evil.</i>
Sounds like
the Owls and the Echidnas
have been fighting
each other for centuries.
Like Vin Diesel and The Rock.
[gasps] Whoa! Wait for me.
Okay, giant owl door,
giant owl. Makes sense.
Whoa.
Wait a second.
I've seen these symbols before.
Here we go.
[rumbling]
Well, that did something.
Whoa! The compass!
This will lead us
to the Emerald!
Hey, you got
a little something on your...
Oh, no. Tails, get back.
Run! [Tails yelps]
[both gasp]
[Robotnik yodeling]
[sighs] That guy again?
Heads up, my little stalagmites.
Someone call an Uber?
Hey, thanks for doing
all the hard stuff.
[grunts]
But we'll take it from here.
Okay, we really gotta talk
about your new look.
It's like Professor X
meets the Monopoly man.
And what kind of genius shows
up to Siberia in a convertible?
The kind of genius
that can turn up the heat...
with a flick of a switch.
[grunts]
Oh! Whoo! [Laughs]
Good one!
I'm sure that wasn't important.
Tails, that's our exit. Come on.
[growls]
[yelps]
Uh-huh. Let's split up.
You go high, I go low.
Right.
Quick little stretch
and here we go.
[laughs]
[Sonic] Oh, so you want to play?
That's new.
Whoa. [Screams]
[exclaiming]
Sonic!
[yells]
[yelping]
Snowball fight!
[Sonic laughs]
It's too easy.
Come on, challenge me!
[gasps]
["A Summer Place" playing]
<i> There's a summer place </i>
[Sonic] We are talking style
and pizzazz.
<i> Where it may rain or storm </i>
Pew-pew-pew!
Pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew.
<i> Yet I'm safe and warm </i>
Yeah! I make this look good.
[grunts]
Oh, great. The Winter Soldier.
For a guy named Knuckles,
you are really bad at punching.
Surrender the compass!
You are no match for me.
I've been training for this
my entire life.
And I had no training at all,
yet here I am ahead of you.
That's gotta be embarrassing.
[yelps]
[gasps] My rings!
Has anyone ever told you
you've got serious anger issues?
You mock me
with your weak jokes,
but you know nothing
about me, hedgehog.
Well, I know you Echidnas have a habit of
showing up uninvited and ruining my life.
Ruining your life?
Another bad joke.
I lost everything
because of you.
<i>My tribe was on the verge
of its greatest victory.</i>
<i>The last of the Owl warriors
had been located.</i>
<i>Soon Longclaw's Emerald secrets
would be ours.</i>
<i>But my father stopped me
from joining the fight.</i>
<i>He said my moment
to honor our tribe would come,</i>
<i>but it was not this moment.</i>
<i>Those were the last words
he spoke to me.</i>
I never saw him again.
We both lost everything
that day.
[Echidnas yelling]
Goodbye, Sonic. No!
<i>Longclaw!</i>
[groaning]
Sonic! Are you okay?
Deceiver!
No, it wasn't a trick.
Tails, take the compass
and get out of here!
Yeah!
Later, haters!
Tails!
Tails, come on. Wake up.
He chose helping the fox
over pursuing the compass.
Of course he did.
New friend,
same pathetic weakness.
Hmm.
[rumbling]
[gasps]
Oh, no. No, no, no.
We're in real trouble here.
Come on, Tails. I need you to fly
us out of here. Time to wake up.
See ya, kids.
Enjoy the fresh powder.
[grunting]
[ukulele music playing]
[guests murmuring]
[airplane passing overhead]
[guests applauding]
Did you...
These rings signify the...
[phone ringtone]
[laughs] Sorry.
Thought it was on silent.
[ringtone stops]
These rings... [phone ringtone]
So help me, Thomas!
[stammering]
Okay, sorry. Sorry.
Excuse me, this is an emergency.
Sorry.
[phone ringing]
What? This better
be important. I just...
<i>Are you skiing?</i>
<i>Snowboarding, actually.
But I need your help now.</i>
Life or death situation
this very second.
I need you to use the ring I gave
you to save me. Like right now.
<i>Okay,
slow down. I don't even know where you are.</i>
You just gotta picture
where you want the ring to go.
So picture this.
Oh, my God. Okay, okay. Hang on.
What?
<i>[Sonic] Did you throw it?</i>
<i>Oh, God. [Sonic] What? Tell me what "Oh,
God."</i>
I mixed up the rings
when I was teasing Jojo.
<i>What? Where is it then?</i>
You don't want to know.
<i>But I do, Tom.</i>
<i>[sighs]
I very much want to know,</i>
before I become
a hedgehog-flavored snow cone.
Hang tight, buddy. I got this.
With this ring, Rachel...
Hey! Hi. [Guests gasp]
Uh... Everything okay, bud?
Not really. What are you doing?
This is gonna sound crazy,
but I need to see that ring
for just one second.
Have you lost your mind?
I'm gonna give it
right back, I promise.
Please, Randall, it's really important. No,
bro. Go sit down.
Give me the ring, please? Randall,
don't look at him, look at me.
One second.
Put the ring on my finger.
No, Randall, listen to me.
Randall! Look at me.
Ring on my finger.
Give me the ring! Just
one second. Put a ring on it!
Please, love? Okay?
With this ring... Yes, baby.
I'm so sorry about this.
[grunts] [guests exclaiming]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Snow, my God. Oh, boy.
Incoming!
[guests screaming]
[Sonic] Oh.
[guests groaning, chattering]
Anybody hurt?
Sonic! Hawaii.
Are you okay?
What's happening?
Are you hurt? [Groaning]
No, no, I'm fine. Okay, good.
Because you're in
so much trouble!
Okay, you calm down.
You talk.
Okay, quick version.
Robotnik is back on Earth
and he's after a magic emerald.
[grunts, sighs]
We need to get it back
or the world is doomed.
Tails!
Wait! All this happened
since yesterday?
Wait. Who's Tails?
Tails, can you hear me?
Oh, Lord,
there are two of them now.
Okay, let me think.
Tails, come on, buddy.
[Sonic groaning]
[weapons powering up]
Hey!
Randall,
why do all of your friends have weapons?
You really should have taken me up
on that brunch, Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski.
Olive Garden guy?
It's okay, everyone.
We're federal agents.
You, too, Agent. Go ahead.
You mean to tell me
that this entire wedding was a
setup? Rachel, wait a minute.
What?
That's correct, ma'am.
Every single aspect
of Operation Catfish
was a complete fabrication.
Operation Catfish?
So is everyone here an agent?
Are you an agent?
Son of a...
Was the florist an agent?
How about the photographer?
The woman who waxed my...
at the spa?
Is Jojo an agent?
What?
Rachel, listen to me.
I'm done listening!
I am done listening!
I am so sorry. I am
so sorry. [Sobbing]
I really am. I am so sorry.
No. Hey, no!
Let him go! Hey!
[grunts]
Sonic, hang on.
Take it easy. It's not worth it.
Tom! Ah-ah-ah.
Sonic is not a threat.
He's on our side.
He's an uncontrolled
extraterrestrial.
And your days of aiding
and abetting him are over.
Secure them in the hotel
until the chopper arrives.
You're making a mistake.
[Rachel] Hold on, Major A-hole!
This is still my day,
and someone is gonna explain to
me what the hell is going on here!
After the events
in San Francisco,
a global task force was created,
devoted to protecting
our planet from alien threats.
That day,
Guardian Units of Nations was born.
G-U-N. Seriously? GUN, yeah.
Look, what about protecting
our planet from Dr. Robotnik?
Robotnik is dead.
You're wrong. He's back.
And you just hauled away the
only ones who could stop him.
Sounds like Robotnik
might be back in play.
If he is,
I want him found immediately.
And cancel my five o'clock
at the Olive Garden.
Aunt Maddie? Yeah.
Sonic and his friend
dropped this.
[gadgets beeping]
I have an idea.
And I want to have
a word with my fianc.
And that word is "murder."
[Sonic] Hey, come on.
You can't just leave us in here.
My friend is hurt! He needs a doctor,
a vet, anyone!
Tails,
you got to wake up, buddy.
Please wake up.
[children chattering, laughing]
[police radio chatter]
All clear.
All right. Game plan.
I get inside the hotel and find
where they're hiding Tom and Sonic.
Okay.
Then I find Randall, right?
And then I squeeze the breath
from his lying, deceitful,
perfectly manscaped body!
[cackles]
I'm going through
a lot right now.
So let me process this
my own way, okay?
Sure, sure.
No judgment. Should've
brought a journal.
Okay...
Okay. Is this meant to be a
weapon? This is adorable.
Pew, pew! Take that, Randall!
[imitates explosion]
Run, Randall!
All right.
We're about to
find out. All right!
Let's go kick some Booty.
[laughs]
[Maddie] Shh! Shh!
Rachel! No. Rachel!
In a minute.
Mm-mmm! Mm.
Stop right there!
Get the bag.
[device beeping]
[screaming]
He's gonna
come back down, right?
I don't know. [Groans]
Good luck!
Look. Tom and Sonic
have to be inside.
I got a fianc to
vaporize. Uh-huh.
Watch your back, sis. Okay.
[both grunting, growls]
Randall!
[grunts]
We got her.
Move in.
Okay.
[grunts]
I did not mean to do that!
Whoo!
Something bothering you, Agent?
I just feel a little guilty
about what I did to Rachel, sir.
Ah, don't worry about it.
We'll send her a gift card.
Now, I propose a toast.
To a perfectly
executed operation.
[agent screaming]
Sir, we're under attack.
["Barracuda" playing]
[crashing] [glass shattering]
[crashing continues]
Randall, wifey's home! [Cackles]
Oh, my God. Rachel.
<i> You lying so low
In the weeds </i>
[tires screeching]
<i> I bet you gonna ambush me </i>
<i> You'd have me down, down
Down, down on my knees </i>
<i> Now wouldn't you, barracuda? </i>
<i> Oh </i>
What a woman.
You no-good,
lowdown, dirty, lying...
Rachel, just listen to me.
What kind of twisted sicko
tricks someone
into a fake wedding?
[weapon clicks, powers up]
Party's over, Bridezilla.
Stop right there.
You son of a...
Have it your way. No!
No! [Electrodes buzzing]
[groaning]
Oh. Ugh. Oh!
Very disappointing,
Agent Handel.
Ha! Is that supposed
to be a weapon?
I don't know,
but we gonna find out.
Haven't you caused
enough trouble for one day?
I haven't even begun
causing trouble.
Hell hath no fury like
a bride scorned.
Looks like it's real, huh?
[laughs]
Whoa! Uh! Ah! Huh?
No. Right.
Be honest. How bad is it?
Not bad at all.
You got Tased. You'll be fine.
I'm so cold.
You landed on our ice sculpture.
Get up.
Just...
Just tell me the truth,
for once.
Is there anything about you
or about us that was real?
Rachel, look at me.
Before I met you,
I didn't think that I was even
capable of real happiness.
But that all changed when
you walked into my life.
And I ended up breaking the
first rule of undercover work.
Which is?
Never fall in love.
[door lock beeps, clicks]
[Tom] Maddie! [Sonic] Maddie!
We're busting out of here.
How'd you get past the guards?
Because that little fox
is into some crazy stuff.
Come on. [Laughing]
Let's go. You're amazing.
The Owls were fools to think
they could hide this.
Ah.
[chiming]
[rumbling]
What's happening?
Wait for it.
[exclaims]
[cackling]
Yes. Eureka!
I've found it!
[explosion]
Sonic.
What is that? A big problem.
The compass led Robotnik
to the Emerald.
That's got to be
hundreds of miles away.
All right.
Huddle up.
Let's figure out a plan.
Together.
There's no time for that.
I'm the only one
that can get there fast enough.
Sonic, this is way too big
for you to do by yourself.
You see that little fox
over there?
He came all the way across
the universe to meet his hero.
And what did his hero do?
I practically got him killed.
You know what? You were right.
My moment came and I blew it.
I'm no hero.
Wait. [Sonic] No.
I'm not letting
anyone else get hurt
because of me.
I'm gonna fix this
while I still can.
Sonic! [Gasps]
Sonic, wait! [Grunts]
[groaning]
Hold on. Wait. Don't move.
Take it easy, little guy.
You're hurt.
But we have to help him. You
don't know what he's up against.
You believe us now?
Mm-hmm.
[siren wailing]
["You Know How We Do It"
playing]
Hey, Bob!
Hey, Maria, how you doing? Hey!
Ah.
Working on my moves.
Just keepin' it green.
No need to burn the fuel.
Speaking of fuel... [groans]
Closed? [Sighs]
That doesn't seem right.
[electronic beeping]
Close.
Yes.
Makeover, makeover. Look at you.
Freeze! Police!
Oh, my God, you got robot hands.
No, they're gloves.
Get 'em up.
Now spread your fingers!
Now wiggle 'em!
Wiggle your digits!
Yes! Like you just finished
a big musical number.
Good.
Why is there
a light on your head?
'Cause I'm the sheriff
for the weekend, pal.
[Sonic] Ugh. Water.
Why did it have to be water?
[exhales]
Okay, you can do this.
Gotta go fast.
[grunting]
[Sonic yells]
[yelling]
[panting]
[straining]
[coughing]
[gasps]
Oh!
[grunts]
I don't want to die
like this! It's derivative!
Make room for Daddy!
[grunting]
Two and two. Great!
We're still bipedals,
more or less. [Sighs]
Fire in the hole!
I've solved it. There is a
booby trap every seven seco...
That was a little early. Mmm.
Oh! So glad it didn't
cut off my mustache.
Hey, Little Red Wrecking Ball.
I know you're dying
to get your Emerald on,
but can we be a little bit more
mindful of our surroundings?
May I?
[glove beeping]
<i>[electronic voice]
In 30 feet, turn left.</i>
Work smarter, not harder.
[Sonic yelling]
[grunting, groans]
My pelvis.
Okay, Secret Temple,
let's see what you've got.
Whoa!
No, no, no! No!
[yells]
[exclaiming]
No.
Yes! [Screams]
<i>[electronic voice] You have
arrived at your destination.</i>
Wow. That really
opened up the space.
I can't even picture it
with an impenetrable wall now.
And the rubble
is always a nice touch.
At last. The Master Emerald.
Ultimate power.
Soon order will be restored.
All because of what
we have done together.
Such a lovely sentiment,
Knuckles.
I think I feel
a single tear forming.
Sadly...
[crackling]
You're as useful to me now
as a backstage pass
to Limp Bizkit.
[thudding] [Sonic yelling] Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
[Sonic yelling]
[yelling continues]
[metal clanking]
[Sonic grunting]
[yells, grunts]
[coughing]
Nailed it.
[gasps]
This guy is always trying
to spoil a bad thing!
Ah! You guys are here, too?
Took the long way, huh?
Is everything a joke to you?
Why must you constantly
interfere with my destiny?
Because my destiny is to
protect my friends and family.
I think I just threw up
in my mouth.
And if you want that emerald,
you're gonna have to go through me.
[gulps]
Whoa!
[both yelling]
[both grunting]
The Echidna's
taking no prisoners today!
Sonic has heart,
but will he lose the quill to live?
I don't want to fight you,
but you're not giving me much choice.
[grunting]
[grunts]
Too easy. Let's do this.
Huh?
[grunts]
[both grunting]
[yelling]
[grunting]
Why don't you stand still
and die with honor?
Okay, I thought about it
and I pass.
[yelling]
Hi there, beautiful.
You're the real deal,
aren't you?
[speaking Italian]
[groaning]
Say goodbye, hedgehog.
[gasps]
Knuckles, stop.
Robotnik's stealing the Emerald!
What kind of fool
do you take me for?
Just look.
Mine.
Wait! That wasn't the deal.
[Boulder thuds]
Oh, you poor, naive creature.
It's not your fault.
A more advanced intellect would
have seen this move coming a mile away.
Or 1.6 kilometers.
But I trusted you!
You were my friend!
[cackling]
I'm sorry.
That just hit me funny.
Let this be
my final lesson to you,
you dim-witted
celestial skin tag.
Friends...
Which means X squared times
the hypotenuse of Y squared,
divided by the absolute value
of friendship, equals...
dookie!
Oh, no.
[Sonic, Knuckles scream]
Chaos is power!
[yelling]
Let's get out of here!
[gasps]
Knuckles!
Water again? Come on!
[straining]
Mmm? [Grunts]
[muffled exclaiming] Mmm?
Mmm. Mmm.
Mmm?
[muffled yelling]
[Sonic grunting]
[muffled grunting]
[groaning]
[coughing]
You saved me.
Don't talk to me.
I'm not in the mood.
[grunts]
How dare you attack me
in my hour of sorrow!
[grunts]
Why did you save me?
Because you saved me first,
which clearly gave you a tactical
advantage I do not understand.
It wasn't a tactic.
I couldn't just let you die.
Why?
I've been trying to destroy
you since the moment we met.
Because being a hero isn't
about taking care of yourself.
It's about taking responsibility
for other people.
Hmm. Wise words.
An ancient Earth proverb?
No, sir, that's
a Wachowski family special.
I got it from a guy
in a rowboat.
Someone who means a lot to me.
[biplane approaching]
Wait a second.
What's that sound?
Only Sonic the Hedgehog
needs rescuing this much.
[laughs] That sly little fox!
Come on, Knucklehead.
We're not beat yet.
On the mountain,
you told me you'd lost everything.
The way I did.
But you seem
so hopeful and free.
How did you move forward
despite failing again?
And again. And again.
Okay, I didn't fail that much.
But I didn't do this all alone.
I found a new family.
New friends.
And you can too.
You don't have to be
alone anymore.
[bones cracking]
[Sonic] Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Are you kidding me
with that handshake?
[Wade] I'm done
playing games, pal.
You're gonna tell me
what I want to know.
And I am asking you
for the last time...
what would you like
on your bagel?
I'm not telling you anything.
And that is a display bagel.
I don't get it with you!
I mean, I've tried everything.
I was good cop. I was bad cop.
I was cop
who offers you a bagel.
And nothing. It's like...
That is a display bagel. Wow.
[rumbling]
[electronic warbling]
[yells]
Doctor, you're here.
[in electronic voice] Yes,
I'm here, and yet I'm...
not all there.
Sir, are you feeling okay?
I'm more than okay.
I'm upgraded.
[singsongy] Sinister 3.0.
My game is next level.
[warped vocalizing]
Hi. [Screams]
I can smell the electricity
in your brain.
[sniffs]
You smell like a snack plate.
Yeah, no, that's fair.
I had a couple today.
Sit down.
In the chair.
I didn't know.
'Cause he was in the chair,
so I didn't... Okay.
Sir? We have a problem.
[soldier 1] All teams in position!
[soldier] Set up a perimeter!
[soldier] Move! Move! Move!
<i>In correct us, my trusty barnacle.</i>
After all these years,
what I finally got...
is a solution.
Commander. Status report.
Robotnik is in there with Stone
and a hostage. Possibly local PD.
I'm not saying he's dumb,
but if he is local PD,
this town's in a lot of trouble.
[both] Wade.
Um...
Okay.
Rockin' that new
spring collection, I see.
Well, if it isn't
the Pastry King.
The Donut Lord.
A real genius would remember
the name of the guy
who helped kick your butt
off this planet.
And I'll do it again
if you mess with Green Hills.
Congratulations on your
oh-so-temporary sense of superiority.
You're finished, Robotnik!
We've taken everything.
Your lab, your drones,
your funding!
Let's see how big of a man you
are without your silly little robots.
Would you like to see how...
big a man I can be?
Welcome to the new norm.
My God!
Doctor! Take me with you!
[screaming]
[train horn blowing]
He's taking everything apart.
He's building something.
[Tails]
That can only be one thing.
The fearsome power
of the Emerald.
If that thing really
turns thoughts into power,
we are in big trouble.
Robotnik has a lot
of bad thoughts.
Hey, Sonic, are you sure
it was a good idea
bringing you-know-who aboard?
Knuckles isn't really a bad guy.
He's just a little mixed up.
I am not mixed up!
I have steely focus.
And I'm complex.
And that's a lot
for some people.
[chuckles] Hope you're not
still mad I hit you with that car.
Pfft!
I was completely uninjured.
And my revenge will come
when you least expect it, fox.
Whoa.
Sir, you're magnificent!
Thank you, sycophant.
Your admiration is inevitable.
I knew it!
Just like the Stay Puft
Marshmallow Man.
World Domination play list.
[heavy metal playing]
Fall back.
Fall back! Quick! Retreat!
How are we supposed
to beat this thing?
We need a plan.
Knuckles, use your strength to...
Jump off the plane. Wow.
Okay, this is what we're
gonna do. Step 1: Light taunting.
Step 2: I have no idea.
Sonic!
[Sonic]
Nice action figure, Eggman.
Does it do anything or just
stand there looking ugly?
Like a blister,
he keeps coming back!
He's on the okay-to-kill list. Shoot
the missiles. Make a decision.
I need a moment, sir. I'm
trying to figure out how to do this.
Did you even glance at a manual?
No! I'll do it.
Pardon my lightning.
You might want to
ground yourself. [Groaning]
Uh-oh.
I'm gonna pop that thing open
like a can of chili... [screams]
[Sonic] Whoa!
[Tails] Hang on!
Whoa!
[grunting]
Whoa! [Laughs]
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
Oh,
yeah! Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo! Close one.
Robotnik!
Deceiver!
Die, mosquito.
[panting]
[grunting]
[yells]
Ooh! I felt that.
[growling]
Oh! Whoa!
What just happened?
It's the Stache Masher.
Right here in the manual.
Return to sender.
[Robotnik, Stone grunt]
Stone?
Oh, great.
Next thing you know, there'll be a
report about a hostile work environment.
Those were our best attacks,
and they did nothing!
We can't beat Robotnik as
long as he's got that Emerald.
He's too powerful.
Look, we aren't strong enough
to beat Robotnik on our own.
But there's three of us.
Your strength, your smarts
and my speed.
Together. That's how we win.
So we make our stand here
on the field of battle.
As a team.
This is it.
This is our moment.
Time to fight.
Bad time to say this,
but I don't actually have a plan.
Tails, any ideas?
We have to find his weak spot.
I suggest the groin.
What? No. No!
Traditionally, yes,
the groin is the weakest spot.
Stop saying "groin."
[Robotnik] Hedgehog!
Look out!
I know what his
weak spot is. It's me.
I'm the groin!
[Knuckles grunts]
Think about it. Whoa!
I live rent-free
in this dude's head.
So if I go out there
and rile him up...
He'll focus on only you,
leaving himself open
to a flanking maneuver
from me and the fox!
Hedgehog,
you are a brave and noble warrior.
Go to your certain death
with honor.
We're gonna have to work
on your pep talks, pal.
[laughs] Yeah. Let's go.
All right, mustache.
You want me? Come and get me.
You don't tell me
about coming and getting.
I am on the cutting edge
of coming and getting!
Coming, getting.
Coming, getting. Coming,
getting. Coming, getting.
Oh, you're really heavy.
That's because I am one million
percent muscle. Faster, fox!
Go! Move, guys! Move back! Let's go,
that's it! Go, go, go!
Keep going! Go! Go!
No, no! Stop! Stop the truck!
Tom, what happened here?
You thinking what I'm
thinking? Let's get our kid.
[both] We need your truck!
[voice slowing] Coming,
getting. Whew!
[Sonic] Yoo-hoo!
So what's the
plan here? [Panting]
Huh?
You gonna build
a big robot house?
Get yourself a big robot wife?
I'm going to enslave humanity and
force them to service my machines.
First, Green Hills.
Then the universe.
Then the multiverse.
Then who knows?
Maybe that'll be enough.
Full disclosure?
You won't be there.
[grunts] Eye lasers? Really?
[panting]
Snot rocket!
No, no, no!
[screaming]
[grunts]
[laughing] Giving up already?
Not so tough when you're fighting
someone 700 times your size, are ya?
You can't beat me!
I'm all-powerful! All-knowing!
All-seeing.
Looks like your fancy robot
has a glitch.
[voice multiplying] Is it me?
What about me? I'm over here.
Up top! Down below!
Behind you! [Laughs]
[voices overlapping] I'm
over here. Sorry! Over here.
Too slow! Try again.
You can't outsmart me.
Missed me again.
I'm the out smarter-er!
[grunts]
[yelping]
I didn't outsmart you.
I'm just the distraction.
[Knuckles] Robotnik!
I am also a hologram.
Disloyal.
"Dis" is how I roll.
[yells]
[Robotnik groaning]
[both screaming]
[both grunting]
[gasping]
Where's my Emerald?
No, no, no, no!
Computer, auxiliary power.
[groans]
[gasps] Oh.
The Emerald. It's right there.
Move, you hunk of junk!
I have to... [groans] reach it.
[groaning]
[grunts]
Come on.
There he is! Go! Go, go, go!
[Maddie yelling]
No!
We got you, Sonic.
Hold on!
[all panting]
You guys okay?
[Tom grunts] Yeah.
Okay.
I got the Emerald.
We could still defeat him.
Come on, come on. How does
this thing work? What do I do?
[cracking]
What?
No. No, no, no!
Look at the happy little family.
You have to get away from
me. I'm the one he wants.
Hey.
We're not going anywhere.
We're family.
And families stick together...
no matter what.
I love you guys.
We love you too, Sonic.
[chaos emeralds chiming]
No!
I got him!
I finally got him! [Cackles]
[thudding]
What was that?
[gasps]
[yelps]
[panting]
It's over, Eggman.
[chuckles] I like the
new look. It works for you.
What do you say
we just let bygones be bygones?
I did some things,
you did some things.
There are good people
on both sides.
Surely two intelligent beings
can work these things out!
[grunts]
Come on, buddy.
Get him, Sonic! Come on.
Yeah. Come on.
[gasping]
It's like that?
Okay, we're not friends.
Later, hater!
Sonic! Buddy! [Laughs]
Wait! You cannot touch him!
The hedgehog holds
the power of the Emerald.
I am sorry. He is no longer
the Sonic you once knew.
What?
[sniffs]
Mmm.
Oh, you got to try this.
Okay. He is exactly
the Sonic you once knew.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Sonic! Whoa!
Bring it in, bud.
It's good to be back in blue.
The golden god thing was fun,
but blue has always been more my color.
Looks good on you.
Sonic, you were
the most powerful hero
in the universe,
and you let it go.
Why?
Because I still have
some growing up to do.
And I kind of like being a kid.
And you're not just any kid.
You're our kid.
That's right.
Bring it in! [Tails] Yay. Hugs.
It's a good thing we didn't do
this before. You would've blown up.
[Sonic] Whoa! You fixed it.
I've spent my whole life
questing for this.
Now I have it.
Now we have it.
What do we do with it?
What next?
There were once
two orders of heroes
who protected the galaxy from those
who would use the Emerald for evil.
But they have all passed on to
the great battleground in the sky.
So we start a new order.
The three of us.
This is no light task.
We must make a vow to use our
powers to keep the universe safe,
to watch out for each other.
Our new tribe.
Oh, I know!
A power bump!
Good idea.
It's an Earth custom.
An unbreakable promise.
Very well.
A power bump it is.
Power bump!
[Sonic over PA]
It's truly a beautiful day
for baseball here
in Green Hills.
An exciting lineup today
with the debut appearance
of two new players!
On the mound,
rookie sensation from across the galaxy,
Miles "Tails" Prower,
facing off against the powerhouse,
Knuckles the Echidna.
Um, I don't understand.
Why am I angry
at the enemy ball?
You're not angry.
You just want to hit it
as hard as you can
and then run around the bases.
But if my quest ends
where I am standing,
why run at all?
Ugh. I can't with this guy.
Why do I even try?
This is just a game.
We're out here having fun.
Just having some fun.
Fun. Huh.
All right!
Give him the heat, Tails!
Hope you're ready
for my fastball.
Your fastball
will be dishonored.
And so will you, fox. [Grunts]
Easy, guys!
Don't think about it too much.
Just keep your elbow up,
eye on the ball
and give it a ride.
A ride? To where?
[grunts]
[growls]
Power bump!
[screams]
Ha! Victory is mine!
First base is also mine!
I think that was our
only ball. [Laughs]
I have conquered
the second of the bases!
Who wants ice cream?
Knocked the cover off that.
Ice cream! Ice cream, yeah!
[laughing] I am having
the fun! What is ice cream?
It's a dessert. If you like fun,
you're gonna love it.
Oh, yum. Dessert.
Does it have grapes in it?
No, not usually.
I'm proud of our little guy.
I really like his new friends,
especially the red one.
He cracks me up.
Heck of a swing too.
Come on, fox.
Our dessert adventure
awaits. Whoo!
Good job, guys. Yeah.
You too, baby.
Let's go get some ice cream.
Come on, come on.
I'm happy for you, pal.
Got your wing men.
Perfect friends to grow up with.
Come on,
Knuckles. Ah! My victory chariot!
I've got a lot more
than that... Dad.
Race you to the truck.
One, two, three, go!
No, don't go easy on me.
I want your best.
Sonic, I have just been told
they have sprinkles.
Ice cream and sprinkles?
This is your new destiny.
What a perfect meal to celebrate
my victory over you in base of ball.
What? I mean,
you barely beat me.
Ha! You've never been
beaten so hard.
[Sonic laughs]
Can't forget this.
["Stars In The Sky" playing]
<i> Say I might And sail tonight </i>
<i> I'm home </i>
<i> Say right now, I'll get it </i>
<i> Take my hand, come zone </i>
<i> Come on, catch a ride </i>
<i> And we take it to places
That we only dreamed </i>
<i> I think I'm home </i>
<i> This is my heaven, baby </i>
<i> Day and night in my zone </i>
<i> The feeling Flows through me </i>
<i> Heaven's where we meet </i>
<i> Happy we lovin'
We lovin' our lives </i>
<i> Things I wished to see
Seem to come to be </i>
<i> I seek the truth, I'm honest
Hey </i>
<i> The moon is singin' our song </i>
<i> Say we find
What we're searchin' for </i>
<i> The love that we holdin' </i>
<i> Another adventure unfolds </i>
<i> I been dreamin' about it
Yeah </i>
<i> Dreamin' about it </i>
<i> Goin' for it </i>
<i> I'm out, I'm rollin'
Till the stars in the sky </i>
<i> Babe, I'm home </i>
<i> In the city </i>
<i> I'm out, I'm rollin'
Till the stars in the sky </i>
<i> Babe, I'm home </i>
<i> Say I might And sail tonight </i>
<i> I'm home </i>
<i> Say right now, I'll get it </i>
<i> Take my hand, come zone </i>
<i> Come on, catch a ride </i>
<i> And we take it to places
That we only dreamed </i>
<i> I think I'm home </i>
<i> This is my heaven, baby </i>
<i> Day and night in my zone </i>
<i> We are free of worries </i>
<i> Stressin' aside </i>
<i> Take me home </i>
<i> Free, no worries at all </i>
Agent, I want an update.
Still searching,
sir. We haven't found any sign of Robotnik.
No one could've
survived that crash.
He's toast. Good riddance.
What a mess that lunatic made.
Sir, there's something else.
When we were wiping Robotnik off
our database, we found something.
A file buried deep in our system
and dating back over 50 years.
What was it?
Coordinates, sir.
Coordinates? To what?
<i>[agent]
A secret research facility.</i>
<i>It was a black site, sir.</i>
<i>Someone worked very hard
to keep this hidden.</i>
<i>[commander] My God.</i>
<i>Project Shadow.</i>
Oh, yes! You got donuts.
I already ate all
the Boston Cream.
Kyle!
This place gives me the creeps.
Relax. That Popsicle
hasn't moved in 50 years.
Is that normal?
No.
- Someone's hacking the system.
- What?
The containment tank
is destabilizing.
He's waking up.
We need more guys.
That is all the guys.
Wait a second.
I thought we were going tubing.
Hold on, hold on.
Is this a race?
You're going down!
It is my destiny
to claim the throne
of Family Champion, hedgehog.
Cute.
Are you sure you
want to challenge
the fastest creature
in the universe?
I mean, that's kind
of my whole brand.
Okay, Tom and Maddie,
- count us down.
- Right!
Don't worry, a little
sibling rivalry is healthy.
Me and my brothers used to do
this kind of thing all the time.
Tom, your brothers are lunatics and
neither of them were born with the power
to trigger a global
cataclysmic event.
That's a fair point.
Did you hear that, boys?
No cataclysmic events, okay?
Let's keep this
cataclysmic-less.
- Ten-four!
- Understood, Lord of the Donuts.
Then on your marks, get set...
go!
And way out in front,
to the surprise of
absolutely no one,
it's the Blue Blur,
the Red-Shoed Rocket,
the one, the only...
Come on, Sonic!
Catch up! Yeah!
What in the what, now?
I am also defeating
you, hedgehog!
Seriously? All
right, you know what?
Time to light the afterburners.
Look! It's a bird! It's a plane!
It's Air Hedgehog!
Yes! I did it! I...
lost?
How is that even
possible? I do not lose.
I am also defeating
you, hedgehog.
Okay, okay, I get it,
man. No need to rub it in.
Come on, Sonic!
Catch up! Yeah!
Wait, what's going on?
Why are you
guys acting like...
holograms!
Which means...
I remain the undefeated
speed champion of all time!
Yes! And the crowd goes wild!
But also, what's going on?
Surprise!
But wait a sec, you guys...
what is all this?
"Happy Bea Arthur Day"?
Oh, it's "Happy B-Earth-Day."
Today's the anniversary of the
day you came to Earth, bud.
It's your "Earth Day Birthday."
So the race was
just a distraction,
which I totally didn't
fall for, by the way...
Good try, though...
so you could throw
a party for me?
Today, we honor you, hedgehog.
If it wasn't for you, none of
us would be here right now.
The boys are right, bud.
You know, the day you
came to this planet
is the day all our
lives changed forever.
And we became a family.
You stole my hoomans.
You guys, I don't... I
don't know what to say.
Except... let's party!
All right! Yeah!
It's now on till the
break of dawn! Toga! Toga!
Thanks for the surprise party.
It really means a lot to me.
Ah, you deserve it, pal.
No way. Is that...
What? Dude...
Could you just for
once walk at my speed?
Whoa.
Sonic!
This is your...
Yep. My old cave.
Oh, man. I can't believe this is
where you lived all those years.
Hey! My state-of-the-art
security system!
Still works.
Hey, bud.
What's this?
Wow. You know, I drew that
on my first night on Earth.
I wanted to remember
where I came from.
I still miss her.
You think Longclaw
would be proud of me?
I know she would, pal.
Because even though you lost
her at such a young age,
you didn't let your pain
change who you are...
in here.
Yeah. In my lungs.
- Or your heart.
- Heart, right.
Yeah, makes more sense.
Not lungs, heart.
That's the thing
about life, Sonic,
it's all about the
choices we make.
You're gonna make
some good ones and,
knowing you, you're
gonna make some bad ones.
But...
as long as you remember
to listen to your heart,
you're gonna make the right
choice when it matters the most.
Thanks.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
<i>I'd probably be a totally
different hedgehog.</i>
2024?
I've been trapped for 50 years?
- Move, move!
- Take positions!
Get on the ground now!
We've got you surrounded!
Why won't you leave me alone?
Take him down!
I have dishonored
my marshmallow.
It's really just a question
of temperature and distance.
It's not a competition.
This is so nice.
- Peace.
- Quiet.
Finally.
Finally!
Hey! We're trying to have
a family moment down here!
- What did we do?
- Or what did they do?
What did you do?
I don't know. I
do a lot of stuff.
Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski.
Aliens.
"Aliens"? Excuse me?
It's not like we're
from different planet...
Oh, yeah, we are. I
guess we are aliens.
Please continue.
I'm Director Rockwell.
There is a very
dangerous situation
unfolding right now in Tokyo.
Commander Walters is requesting
Team Sonic's immediate assistance.
"Team Sonic"? Who
picked that name?
Love it! Ten out
of ten, no notes.
Tom and Maddie, put
the s'mores on ice
because Team Sonic is
off to save the day!
Remember,
make good choices!
Good evening and welcome
to Tails Air flight 1012.
We're looking at an
on-time arrival into Tokyo.
Okay, Captain, we got a
rogue alien on the loose.
How do we find
him?
I love it! Let's start
with the giant fireball.
Finally,
some action!
Okay, time to gear up.
Titanium handcuffs,
completely indestructible.
I don't need your
silly gizmos, fox.
And you know why?
Because I am...
...one million
percent muscle.
Yes, good. You've
been listening.
We're
over the drop zone.
All right, here
we go. Showtime!
Now, look, we don't
know if it's Godzilla
or Hello Kitty down there,
but as long as we
stick together,
there is nothing
we can't handle.
"Team Sonic" on three.
One, two, three.
Team...
- Sonic!
- Knuckles!
Talk about low-budget
flights. No food or movies?
We're out of here!
What happened here?
Looks like GUN
got their butts kicked.
Keep your eyes open.
Tails, anything?
Whoa! These energy readings
are off the charts!
Look
out!
One... million... percent.
Whoa! Are you guys seeing this?
- He looks just like you.
- Impossible!
You're a colorful bunch.
Um, excuse me. Why
do you look like me?
I don't look like you.
You look like me! Why
do you look like me?
Hey, you know what? I'll ask
the questions, new hedgehog!
Who are you? Why do
you look like me?
This is a waste of time.
Walk away, before you get hurt.
Whoa, whoa, easy, buddy.
We don't want to fight you.
Actually, Sonic, I
would like to fight.
Not now.
Why don't you stop throwing
cars at us for a second
and come down here to talk?
You jumped out of
a GUN helicopter.
There's nothing to talk about.
All right, then. Enough!
Knuckles, no!
Let us talk with our fists!
Knuckles!
Knuckles! Knuckles,
are you okay?
No, not really. Ow!
Who is this guy?
He is much more impressive
than the hedgehog I
fought previously.
Dude, I'm standing right here.
Now, come on! He can't
take us all at once.
Ow!
Okay, he
took us all at once.
Weakling.
Don't try to follow me.
Sonic, I know that look.
Going after him is a bad idea.
When has that ever stopped me?
I got to ask, one
hedgehog to another,
who does your highlights?
Hey! Dangerously weaving
through traffic is my thing!
Coming through!
Why are you running away? We
were just getting started.
The more you talk,
the harder I want to hit you.
Watch out!
Ugh, I'm gonna throw up!
Yeah, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Yah!
1.21 gigawatts.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
Sonic!
Are you okay?
I'm fine, guys.
And before you ask,
I handcuffed myself
for tactical reasons
that I do not have
time to explain.
You shouldn't have
gone off on your own.
We're supposed to be a team.
Sorry, buddy. I'm still
working on this teamwork thing.
So now what?
Well, I'm not jumping out
of any more helicopters
until we get some
answers from GUN.
We need somewhere to regroup.
I know just the place.
<i>Hai, chiizu.</i>
It's an ambush!
You'll never take us
alive, foul beasts!
Calm down, Knuckles.
This is a Chao Garden.
One of the top ten must-see
spots in all of Tokyo!
It's a perfect place
for us to blend in.
Are you Detective Pikachu?
Yes, he is!
He does
look like a Pokmon.
"Pika, pika!"
Commander Walters!
Sonic.
Thank God you're all okay.
I'm sure you have questions.
Just a big ticked-off
red and black one.
Who was that guy?
Shadow's story began a
lot like yours, Sonic.
But where you found family
and friends on this planet,
Shadow found only pain and loss.
<i>It begins over 50 years ago,</i>
<i>with a meteor crash in a
quiet corner of Oklahoma.</i>
<i>The meteorite
contained a life-form.</i>
<i>The ultimate life-form.</i>
<i>Shadow's power...
his "chaos energy"...</i>
<i>went far beyond any
living creature.</i>
<i>The scientist who discovered
him believed this power</i>
<i>would usher in a new
era for humanity.</i>
<i>But Shadow's power
proved too dangerous.</i>
<i>A terrible accident
destroyed the lab,</i>
<i>taking human lives
with it.</i>
<i>The project leader was blamed
for the incident and imprisoned.</i>
<i>With the program
canceled...</i>
<i>Shadow was a loose end no
one knew how to deal with.</i>
<i>Too dangerous to
be walking free,</i>
<i>too valuable to destroy.</i>
<i>So I had him placed
into stasis...</i>
<i>indefinitely.</i>
Wait a second. If Shadow's
been on ice for 50 years,
- someone had to help him escape.
- True.
But there's only a few
people in the world
who even know of
Shadow's existence.
A live show? Yeah!
Get down!
Egg drones?
But Robotnik is
supposed to be dead!
Konnichi-what?
I'm sorry, we already had our big
motorcycle chase for the evening.
Commander Walters!
Commander
Walters, are you okay?
Sonic...
take this.
What is
it? A key...
to the most powerful
weapon GUN has ever built.
You're the only one I
trust to keep it safe.
Commander Walters...
Alpha team, fan out!
Do we have eyes?
Secure the perimeter!
Medevac is en route.
His launch key is missing.
I knew they couldn't be trusted.
Why are we
running from GUN?
Aren't we on the same team?
Until we get
more information,
we're not trusting anyone.
- Follow me.
- Get it... off!
Hold it right
there, Tokyo Drift!
Who are you?
It's the Goat Milker!
"It's the Goat Milker!"
Relax. I'm not here to fight.
- Then why are you here?
- And why did you free Shadow?
Are you kidding?
The last thing we want is more
super-powered hedgehogs running around.
The doctor had
nothing to do with it.
And I can prove
it.
Please,
join me in the crab.
<i>And now back
to... "La Ultima Pasin."</i>
I have fallen in
love with another.
But who, Gabriella?
Tell me who!
My twin brother, Pablo?
<i>Pablo!</i>
!Bastardo!
Buenos das, !hermano!
<i>No!</i>
Let that be a
lesson to you, Juan.
Family
is a field of
emotional claymores
that leave you
abandoned, betrayed
and weeping while you eat cake,
which creates copious
amounts of adipose tissue,
and what some calloused
individuals refer to as...
man boobs.
Ha.
Doctor, we have visitors.
Really?
I thought I was having an
anthropomorphic nightmare.
Where the only person I
could trust in the world
showed up with all
my worst enemies,
while I was in a bathrobe,
playing congas on
my big, fat belly!
Sorry, sir.
I don't believe
it. Eggman's alive?
And he's never looked worse.
Well, maybe,
this is what not giving a damn what
you think I look like looks like.
Sir, right now we have
an even bigger problem.
Oh, come on.
There's an imposter out
there using your technology.
Imposter. That's
impossi... What?
No.
My sweet mechanized spawn!
Whomever this party-pooping
posse is looking for
has stolen my persona
and the precious
babies from my egg sac.
Well...
I'll soon egg-xact my revenge.
You see what I did
there?
It's time for the
dramatic soap-opera twist,
where this Pablo
reveals his Juan!
By cross-referencing
the precise coordinates
of each drone's energy spikes,
I can track my babies
to the imposter's
base of operations,
right about...
there!
Sonic, I hate to say it,
but I think we're both
after the same person.
Hold on, hold on. You're
not suggesting we team up
with Doctor
Ro-Butt-Stink, are you?
Perhaps the fox is right.
It could be our only chance
to find this mysterious,
more impressive hedgehog.
All right, Egghead.
I hate to say it,
but it looks like
we're partners.
On one condition.
Dude, you have serious issues.
Ow!
Let's...
do this!
Suck it in!
Tinker-tailor?
I need room.
Think Elvis, circa 1976.
But sir, I don't have
the proper materials.
Found some.
Resourceful.
Hey! This is a restricted area.
Oh, it's okay. She's the
professor's granddaughter.
He takes her everywhere.
Welcome to the lab, Maria.
I'm Captain Walters.
Oh, do you know
where my room is?
Yeah, down the hall
and to the right.
Make yourself at home.
But, um,
let's lose the
skates, okay, kiddo?
Okay.
Look out!
Wow.
Look at all those stars.
They're like diamonds.
My grandfather says
it can take hundreds of years
for the light of a
star to reach Earth.
And by the time you see it,
the star might not
even exist anymore.
Isn't that crazy?
A light shines,
even though the star is gone.
Yeah, it does.
I wonder which one
you came from, Shadow.
I don't know.
I don't know anything
about my home.
This is your home, Shadow.
Earth.
Maria,
do you think I'm...
dangerous?
What are you talking about?
The way the
scientists look at me,
I can tell they're afraid.
Like I'm the horrible thing
from that movie we watched.
I don't know...
what I am.
You're my friend.
And you can do or be
anything you want.
Not because of your powers,
but because of who
you are... in here.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Professor?
It's good to see you, Shadow.
I knew you'd come home.
I can't get her out of my head.
The pain...
It's too much.
And that is why we
have to punish them.
Okay, I don't like you
and you don't like me.
Let's get this
over with quickly.
Out of my way, dorkupine.
"Dorkupine"? Really clever.
This door is
six-inch-thick solid steel
on a pressurized latch.
I'll need a moment to
calculate the molecular density
and invert the
venting mechanics.
I unlocked it.
Subtle as
always, fist-for-brains.
Easy, Shadow.
Those are the guests
I've been expecting.
Let's give them a warm welcome.
Whoa.
What is this place?
It looks
like a military base,
but nobody's been
here for years.
I wonder if it's haunted.
Haunted? Nobody said
anything about being haunted.
What's the matter? You
afraid of g-g-g-ghosts?
Nothing scares an
Echidna warrior.
Uh, yeah. Do you remember what
happened last movie night?
Let go, let go, let go!
There is no such thing
as a friendly ghost.
So which way do we go?
I know! We should split up.
Everyone with hideous, brightly-colored
fur take the left and the middle.
Stone and I will go right.
No, no, no, no, no. I'm not
letting you out of my sight.
Tails, you and Stone go left.
Knuckles, you take the middle.
Eggman, you and me go right.
By all means.
We could use some time together.
To work on your trust issues.
You know what? You're right.
I should be more trusting.
I mean, you've only
tried to kill me twice!
Just a dark, creepy hallway.
Nothing to be afraid of.
You hear that, ghost?
You don't frighten me!
Get... a... grip.
Boo.
I'm just gonna come
right out and say this:
You're adorable.
Oh, um, thanks.
So, what's it like
being Sonic's assistant?
You have a daily routine?
Paid time off? Benefits?
Oh, I'm not Sonic's
assistant. We're teammates.
He's the leader,
Knuckles is the muscle,
and I'm the gadget guy.
We all have a role to play.
That's what makes
the team so special!
That and the fact
we're best friends.
You are?
Well, yeah. Just like
you and Eggman, right?
Uh... Yeah, eh...
Of course! Yes.
Me and the doctor,
best of friends.
That's definitely what we are.
Hmm.
Whoa. Look at all this stuff.
This was more than just
a military base or a lab.
It was a home.
People lived here.
He had a family.
Is that what I smell?
The stench of domestic harmony?
You ever wonder what your life would
have been like if you had a family?
Hmm... No!
Maybe you wouldn't have
gone full supervillain.
I have no parents,
no aunts, no uncles.
And something about my
attitude renders me...
undesirable to all
possible genders.
My future is a cul-de-sac!
The Robotnik name ends...
<i>avec moi.</i>
Yes, I know French.
Whoa.
Is this where you
grew up, Shadow?
No wonder you're so mad.
This place could really
use a beanbag chair
and some comic books.
What happened here?
I'm tired of giving
you warnings!
Where'd you go, hedgehog?
I wasn't finished
trauma dumping.
My darlings!
My eggy weggies!
<i> Memories </i>
<i> Light the corners </i>
<i> Of my mind </i>
<i> Misty watercolor </i>
<i> Memories </i>
<i> Of the way </i>
<i> We weren't </i>
I...
- don't believe it.
- Don't you?
- It's impossible.
- Is it?
- It couldn't be.
- Couldn't it?
I'm... Are you?
Imposter!
You stole my babies!
But they know who
their real daddy is...
drone-napper!
Magnificent creations, my boy.
I borrowed them to lure you here
and reunite our family.
You see, Ivo...
I'm your grandfather:
Gerald Robotnik.
My... grandfather?
But how? And why?
And who did what with whom?
You hail from an
ancestry of excellence...
tied directly <i> moi.</i>
Yes, I know French.
You do look like me.
But fatter. And older.
And there's that funny smell.
But the resemblance is uncanny.
It's as if...
we're two
characters in a movie
being played by the same actor.
- But I need real proof!
- Ivo!
We have very little time.
But I could field a
couple of queries.
Name the most elegant
formula in mathematics.
Euler's Identity.
E to the I times pi
plus one equals zilch.
European capitals
arranged alphabetically
by the fourth letter.
Riga, Monaco, Sarajevo, Tirana.
The speed of light divided
by the speed of sound,
divided by the speed of
the bus in the movie <i>Speed.</i>
17,893.33333...
Rounding up? 17,894 MPH.
And, for all the marbles...
Good. I lost mine.
A rare lung disease,
and the longest word in
the English dictionary.
Um...
Pneumonoultramicroscopic-
silicovolcanoconiosis!
- Pap-pap!
- In the saggy flesh.
But looking pretty good
for a hundred and ten.
Oh, Grampy-poo!
Where have you been
my entire life?
Wait.
Where have you been...
my entire life?
Locked in a top-secret
prison for the last 50 years.
Made it kind of hard to
send Christmas cards.
Now...
you're probably wondering
why I brought you here.
You didn't bring me here!
I used my unparalleled
intellect to track you down.
Per the plan I concocted with
my unparalleled intellect.
You'll see.
I have the answer to everything.
Come on, kiddo.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no.
Someone tell me
this is some kind of
concussion-induced nightmare.
There's two Eggmen now?
Double your villains,
double your fun!
Two Robotniks are
way worse than one.
Chest bump?
No.
Stone, why are you tied up?
You must be the
long-lost grandson.
And you must be another
stinking hedgehog.
So you're the one
behind all this.
- The Shadow breakout.
- The attack on Walters.
That musty old-man smell.
How dare you insult me
with your unsolicited
exposition!
Shadow, get the key.
Where is it?
Ha! Good one, Hot Topic.
Do you really think
we'd be that stupid
to bring the key right to you?
Yep, we're that stupid.
GUN took everything from us.
And now we are going to
take everything from them.
With this.
My masterpiece of malevolence...
The Eclipse Cannon.
<i>In exchange for my freedom,</i>
<i>I gave GUN the most
powerful weapon</i>
<i>mankind has ever seen,</i>
<i>capable of delivering
a precision strike</i>
<i>anywhere on Earth.</i>
<i>Our first target:</i>
<i>GUN Headquarters.</i>
But firing a weapon
that powerful
could threaten millions
of innocent lives!
Yeah, tera-bite me.
This is one of two keys required
to launch the Eclipse Cannon.
The other is locked
inside GUN headquarters.
Once we have both,
I will take rightful
control of my weapon.
I'm in.
Holy crab!
Spacious
and crustaceous.
Thank you so much
for inspiring this
little adventure.
It really worked out for me.
And you wonder why
I have trust issues!
Shadow, wait! Don't do this.
I know you're hurting,
but don't let that change
who you are inside.
I've spent 50 years reliving
what they did to her.
This is who I am inside.
Uh, nice magic
marble. Real scary.
That actually
is real scary!
It's a mini black hole!
It's going to suck in all
the matter in this base!
Fear not, friends.
Even my teeth are muscles!
Sonic, try to reach
one of my rings!
Got one.
Check this out. Trick shot!
Come on.
Come on!
Yeah! Yes!
Yikes.
Somebody better
call Google Maps.
I've spent years trying
to cleanse the cosmos
of that spiny, blue speed freak.
And you did it...
in one afternoon.
There's nothing we can't
destroy together, my boy.
Charting route to GUN
Headquarters in London, sirs.
ETA four hours.
As the crab flies.
By all accounts, we're
ahead of schedule.
We should take this time
to get to know
each other better.
Wow. What?
You mean...
spend some qua-qua-quality time?
You've waited for
this your whole life.
How would you choose to spend one
perfect day with your new grand pal?
Ooh!
And done!
- Masterpiece.
- Look at that. - Yay!
It's really been great
having time to ourselves.
Right. Absolutely.
I just feel so...
relaxed, you
know? Clearheaded.
Mmm, look at all these
new interests we found.
- I know, so many hobbies.
- So many!
After the action and adventure
of the last few years,
- well, I could get used to this.
- Same.
Tom! Maddie! We
need your help on a super...
- Knuckles, do you mind?
- Oh! Excuse me.
Tom! Maddie! We need your help
on a super-dangerous
top-secret mission!
Hmm.
- Thank God. Yeah, we're in.
- Let's go.
Really? You're in?
Just like that?
Yes. It was getting so boring - without you guys here.
- Yeah. So...
No offense... boring.
No, none taken.
I mean, whatever crazy
plan you're cooking up,
- the answer's yes.
- Yes.
Great. But first things
first: What is that?
Oh! This is...
Li'l Tom!
Isn't he great?
I told you to get rid of
that. It's very creepy.
I told
him to get rid of you.
Okay, that's, mmm...
- crossing a line there.
- You are in so much trouble.
Okay, this is it. The
belly of the beast.
GUN Headquarters in London.
Tom, we're finally gonna
get to see London together.
Hey, I told you we'd
get there someday, baby.
Okay. So here's the plan.
<i>I run in superfast,</i>
<i>fly over that water, no problem,</i>
<i>and right when I get to the...</i>
What just happened?
Congratulations.
You just got incinerated
by their energy shield.
We'll need to shut it down by planting
a USB drive in their server room
<i>that will give me
full control over it.</i>
That's what we need you two for.
Couple of badass spies,
that's what we are.
Mr. and Mrs. Smith.
<i>Once we
disable the shield,</i>
<i>you'll face the laser hall.</i>
<i>These high-density bad boys
will cut you into tiny pieces.</i>
<i>And cut those pieces
into even tinier pieces!</i>
Once again...
Can't we just get Tom Cruise
to do this? Nope.
<i>Because not even he could
break into... the vault.</i>
<i>Why is it
empty in there?</i>
<i>Because
we have no idea</i>
<i>what's on the other
side of that door.</i>
<i>To prevent the vault from
ever being accessed by a ring,</i>
<i>all images and schematics have
been wiped from GUN's database.</i>
So for the last leg
of this heist...
we're going in blind.
Sorry.
Okay, I'm
just gonna say it.
It sounds like this plan would
work a heck of a lot better
if Sonic used the Master
Emerald to go Golden God mode
to get the key.
No way, Maddie.
The Master Emerald is too
powerful to ever use again.
We made a promise to each
other to keep it hidden.
In a location only
Knuckles knows.
As guardian of the
Master Emerald,
anyone who tries to take
it away for any reason...
will become a sworn enemy.
Okay, okay! Sheesh!
No need to get all
growly on me, buddy.
You guys are always telling
us to make good choices.
Well, this is the right choice.
Okay.
I guess we're going to...
London, baby!
GUN Headquarters is right there.
Let me go in, get the key
and destroy anyone in my way!
I want revenge.
Patience, Shadow.
Just let us handle this...
and I promise
you'll have revenge
on a scale you couldn't
possibly imagine.
Come on, Granddaddy-O,
we've got...
dirt to do!
Suits.
Right here, sir.
Stone, babysit the hedgehog.
Keep the crab on a low boil.
It's time for more
family bonding.
Come on, Shadow.
Got fresh avocados in the
crab. We'll make guac.
Revenge guac!
Guys, are you ready for me yet?
I've been waiting here all day.
Sonic, we literally
just started.
Tom, Maddie, are you
in position and ready?
- We were born ready.
- Let's do this.
<i>Knuckles,
how about you?</i>
I have taken my perch
atop the giant clock.
Now, where is this glass
I'm supposed to break?
Actually, Knucks, your job
is to "Break Glass in
Case of Emergency."
Understood.
I will shatter this glass
like the jaw of a vile foe.
In case of emergency.
<i>I will pulverize it like the
skull of a loathsome rival!</i>
Just to be clear, the "emergency"
is the important part.
The glass will beg for mercy
under the shadow
of my mighty fist!
Guys, remember, we're a team.
- Let's focus.
- Please.
<i>You know
what? Let's move on.</i>
All right, everyone
knows what to do.
Tom and Maddie, you guys
plant the USB drive.
I'll disable the traps. Sonic
will snag the launch key.
And Knuckles, you stand by to...
Break glass in
case of emergency.
See? He gets it.
Then we're all set.
Hologram time.
You go first.
Tom, it's me, Rachel!
Can you believe it? We're
both in London together.
Have you met your
sister? Try again.
Unless...
you're not up for this mission.
Yeah, maybe you want to be back
in Green Hills, baking sourdough.
- Thomas Michael Wachowski!
- Gah!
You brought aliens
to my wedding,
punched out my husband and
buried me in an avalanche.
Your day of
reckoning is at hand!
Yeah, that's perfect.
Okay, now for her better half.
Ho-ho, my name is Randall,
and I am too much to handle!
Welcome to the gun show!
Baby, would you describe
me as jacked, juiced,
or shredded?
I would describe
your head as swollen.
Let's get to work.
Agent Randall Handel.
I'm here to have lunch with
my lovely wife, Rachel.
I'm
sorry, Agent Handel,
this facility's
currently locked down.
Command-level clearance only.
One minute.
Tails... we have a problem here.
Wow, they must have tightened
security after Shadow's escape.
I got this.
You must be new here.
Allow me to introduce
myself. My name is Rachel.
Rachel Gonnagetyoufired.
Do you know what GUN stands for?
Well, 'course. Guardian
Units...
Getting. Ultra. Nasty.
Do you want me...
to get ultra nasty?
Nasty nasty?
- No, ma'am.
- Okay, then.
Then go ahead and take
those little sad fingers
and start tippity
type-type-typing!
Mm-hmm. That's right, go on.
Sorry for the
inconvenience, ma'am.
Mm-hmm.
That's what I thought!
My God, I love being Rachel!
- Did it work?
- Oh, yeah.
Oh! Ouch!
Director Rockwell seeking
access to the server room.
<i>Just one moment, ma'am.</i>
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
It's her. It's the real her!
- The incident in Colorado?
- We're still assessing.
What do you mean,
we're still assessing?
- What do we do?
- Quick, change faces!
Okay. Did it work?
Who am I? What's going on?
Why are you looking at me like
that? What am I doing wrong?
Ow!
Aye-aye, Captain!
"Aye-aye, Captain"?
Who are you, Popeye?
- I panicked! I was panicking!
- Jeez!
Get it together!
Okay, Tails, what
are we looking for?
<i>The security server is in
the 7th row, 23rd cabinet.</i>
Are you guys finished yet?
This is taking forever.
Uh-oh.
Has the time come
to break the glass?
Or at least break something?
All right, hang tight, guys.
Maddie's about to insert the drive.
Ready?
<i>Three...</i>
<i>two...</i>
<i>one...</i>
Go.
It didn't work.
Did you put it in the right way?
- Try punching it.
- Do not try punching it.
Oh!
Take it out - and blow on it.
- Yes!
Oh, come on, Tom.
<i>There's absolutely no scientific
evidence to support...</i>
Never mind. It worked!
Little trick from the '90s.
I mean, best
decade ever. Right?
I'm shutting down the
outside sensors now.
Yes! Uh...
Hold on. Is...
there supposed to be
another USB drive here?
One with a
giant mustache on it?
Oh, no. I've got two heat
signatures en route to the vault.
Which can only mean...
The Robotniks have
entered the chat.
Wait.
Poppyseed?
Grand-geezer?
<i>Dnde est?</i>
I'm right here.
If you weren't family,
I could have gut
you like a pheasant.
I mean, try to keep up.
<i>And now back
to "La Ultima Pasin."</i>
<i>Ultima Pasin...</i>
can only belong to one.
No.
It can only belong... to Juan!
Gabriella should kill them both.
She's not a prize to be won.
"Kill this. Murder that."
You need to lighten up, Shadow.
We're about to rule the world.
When we're done...
there won't be
anything left to rule.
That is dark. Even for you.
What are you and
the professor up to?
Hello! What's this?
I knew I saw an outside signal!
<i>Cheerio!</i>
<i>I guess someone forgot to flush.</i>
What now, my cunning cohort?
Just a little teamwork!
Hey...
The lasers...
don't seem to be
penetrating my suit.
They're conforming to the
shape of my bodacious bod.
Of course.
I designed these suits
to create a field
of laser-bending
thermal distortion.
Wasn't sure it
would work till now.
You're heartless, son.
- Hmm!
- Rotten to the core.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm...
so proud.
So now we can just
dance right through.
That sounds like a challenge.
<i> My
finger is on the button </i>
<i> Push the button </i>
The Robotniks are
almost at the vault!
We're out of time. I'm going.
No, Sonic!
I haven't disabled
the traps yet!
Too late!
Look at me! I'm running on
the wrong side of the road!
Well, I got to
take in the sights.
Paul, John, George,
the other one!
Loud American coming through!
Excuse me. Pardon me.
'Ello, guv'nor! Which
way to Hogwarts?
Hear ye, hear ye!
Sonic the Hedgehog
wants a cuppa tea!
Hold this for me, please.
You're not gonna make it!
I can make it.
I'm gonna make it.
I'm not gonna make it.
I'm not gonna make it!
- Made it!
- Whoo!
Excuse me. Coming through.
No time for autographs.
Got to go, bye!
Our destiny awaits.
Stop right there, Roboscum!
- Let's do this!
- Copy!
Too slow, Eggmen.
Now if you don't mind,
I've got to get that key.
Whoa!
My feet. Why can't I
use my beautiful feet?
Heh-heh! Because...
this vault is armed
with variable gravity.
No kidding.
Green goes up...
and red takes you down... hard.
Rockwell, listen to me.
The Robotniks are
planning to...
Oh, they're planning on stealing
a second key, just like you are?
Yes, I'm aware.
I called it the second
Commander Walters was attacked.
So...
thank you for taking the bait
and falling right into my trap.
I don't believe this.
I know, grandson.
A woman in the military!
Let's go.
Go, positions!
Full perimeter.
Robotnik.
Going full spandex,
huh? Who's the fossil?
That's my grandfather, you
dough-eating dimbecile.
- Who are they?
- A couple of bleeding hearts,
here to rescue their
emotional-support animals.
Enough! It's over.
The only way you're leaving
here is in handcuffs.
There is no other way out.
You know, there might
be one other way out.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Hey, big guy,
I think it's time to...
Break glass in
case of emergency!
Ha! Nothing can
stop Team Knuckles!
Open fire!
Knuckles,
turn this stuff off!
- Hurry!
- On it.
Uh-oh.
Ha! See how you
like it...
- Can you move?
- No, not at all.
- Tails, can you?
- No, I'm stuck.
We might be here a while.
Whoa! Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Where's the key?
Whoa!
- What was that?
- We might have a problem.
No, no, no, no!
I'm moving.
I'm moving!
You go get it, grandson!
Hey!
Oh, whoa, whoa...
No. No, no!
I'm almost there!
Whoa!
Sonic!
That was so not worth it!
Ooh!
- You okay?
- Yeah. You good?
Sonic!
Hey.
Sonic, one, concrete
boulder, zero.
Thanks for the save.
Cutting it a little
close, don't you think?
Secure the room!
She's got the key.
I got an idea.
Commander Walters.
Sir.
You're... Still alive?
I'll die before I let that
key fall into the wrong hands.
Thanks for keeping it safe.
I'll take it from here.
That's an order,
Director Rockwell.
Now, organize the
reinforcements.
Yes, sir.
Guys, guys, I got the key.
I repeat, I got the key.
Now let's get out of here.
Commander Walters.
No, no. No. Wait!
What?
Tom! Everyone's clear!
Come on, let's go!
You. What are you...
Tom!
Tom. Tom, what happened?
Speak to me. Come on.
Come on, it's gonna be okay.
Please, please, please get up.
Hey, come on, please wake up.
Wake up, wake up, come on.
Wake up, wake up, wake up!
Maria.
What did you do?
What I had to.
Oh, my God. Tom!
Help me up, kid.
Freeze! Don't move!
Any tricks up your sleeve,
Captain Grandtastic?
We got what we came for.
Great job, Shadow.
We have both keys.
So where's your little
science project?
It's closer than
you think, my boy.
Welcome...
to my masterpiece!
I must hand it to GUN.
They built her to my
exact specifications.
It's...
remarkable!
Mm-hmm.
- Astounding!
- Yes.
That's my genius grand-genome!
And I have one more surprise.
It's a new suit!
Gee.
<i> I'm a chip Off
the old block </i>
<i> I'm a chip off
The old block! </i>
What do you want,
Stone? I'm busy.
Doctor, I have a bad
feeling about this.
I don't think your grandfather's
been completely honest with us.
It was something Shadow said.
<i>There's more to their plan.</i>
How dare you!
You have been jealous of
my long-lost grand-Pop-Tart
since the very beginning!
I no longer require your
obsequious groveling.
<i>Consider this your
notice of termination.</i>
Your letter of reference
will be L for Loser.
Of course, I'll
expect you to stay on
until you've been
successfully cloned.
But you and I are done!
Like a blackened catfish dinner!
Sir, it's too dangerous and
I'm not there to protect you.
I already lost you once! I...
Unsubscribe. Blocked
and reported.
I
can't lose you again.
Do the honors...
grandson.
Here we go.
It'll be okay, Sonic.
It'll be okay?
Tom is fighting for his life
and you think it'll be okay?
The fox is simply
trying to comfort you.
Comfort's not what
I need right now.
I need to stop them.
By any means necessary.
Wait, you don't mean...
The Master Emerald.
The Emerald must never
be wielded for vengeance.
Not ever!
We swore a sacred oath.
Don't talk to me
about oaths. Not now!
But you told Tom
using the Emerald
wasn't the right choice.
Well, now it's the only choice.
And if neither of you
have the guts to help me,
then I'll do it alone.
But I thought the three
of us were a team.
I thought that's
what made us special.
I'm not asking you
twice, Knuckles.
Where is the Master Emerald?
Your heart is being
consumed by anger, hedgehog.
You are in no condition to
make decisions right now.
I know you're upset
about Tom. We all are.
Last chance.
Where... is it?
Don't do this.
Part of our oath is
to trust each other.
And I must abide
by that promise,
even if you have
chosen to break it.
But heed this warning:
The Master Emerald is guarded
by a fearsome warrior.
And to seize this
ultimate power,
you will have to go...
through him.
Okay, Wade... all
comes down to this.
Last few seconds.
Whipple down the ice.
He shoots... he scores!
Wade Whipple is
a champion again!
Oh, hey, Sonic. See my
goal? Pretty sick, right?
I'm here for the Emerald.
Look, Sonic, I'm sorry.
I promised to guard this
emerald with my life.
I will do whatever it takes...
Well, I tried.
Sonic!
Too bright!
<i>This is an urgent
national emergency broadcast.</i>
<i>A spacecraft designed
by the agency GUN</i>
<i>has been hijacked and launched
out of the River Thames.</i>
<i>All residents are urged
to seek immediate shelter.</i>
It's time, Shadow.
Professor, is this really
what Maria would have wanted?
The question isn't what
Maria would have wanted.
It's what do they deserve.
Remember what she meant to us.
Remember what they took from us.
Kids!
We have to go, now!
They want to take
Shadow away from us, Maria!
Hey! Hey! What are you
doing? Those are children.
- We've got our orders, Walters!
- Stand down!
Huh?
Maria!
Excuse me, Grand Paso Doble.
What is that thermonuclear
gerbil doing?
Infusing the core...
with chaos energy.
That's my little secret.
The Eclipse Cannon is
about to turn this planet
into a flaming pile of rubble,
wiping out everything
in a 25,000-mile radius.
Including us.
What?
We can't annihilate the Earth!
- Hmm?
- By combining our genius, we can rule humanity.
Together!
Humanity is a failed experiment.
If anyone should
know that, it's you.
All your life, you've been
rejected by this world.
You have nothing down there.
No one who cares about you.
But I have you now.
We're family.
We have each other.
Oh, Ivo...
you're no Maria.
The moment I lost her, my
family was gone forever!
The only way to give
Maria's life meaning
is to destroy the world
that took her from me.
So I'm burning it all down!
It's done.
Good work, Shadow.
I'm prepping the
firing sequence.
The weapon will be fully
charged in ten minutes.
It's almost finished, Maria.
You will have justice.
What is that?
Is GUN launching missiles at us?
Impossible. It's
moving too fast.
It's him.
You hurt my family.
This ends now!
Now you know my anger.
The pain I've felt for 50 years.
And you've made the
same choice I did.
I'm nothing like you!
We'll see.
Show yourself, coward!
You were right about one thing.
This ends now.
What's happening?
Where are they?
- Up there.
- Where?
- Higher.
- Hmm?
Left yourself open.
Ivo! What are you doing?
Thwarting your evil plan!
- Not the mustache!
- Agreed.
Let go on three.
One, two, three!
Oh... a nano-fist.
I haven't seen that since I
hate-watched <i>Green Lantern</i> in 2011.
I was saving it for Comic-Con.
But now there won't
be a Comic-Con!
Why are you alone?
Where are your friends?
They tried to stop
you, didn't they?
But you came anyway.
Your anger was too much.
What kind of hero
abandons his friends
to pursue revenge?
Abandons his family!
Don't you dare talk
about my family.
And here I thought
you cared for them.
Especially the one...
What's his name?
Tom?
Go ahead. Finish it!
What are you waiting for? Do it!
I'm right here!
You didn't let your pain
change who you are...
in here.
This is not who I am.
What are you doing?
You won. Take your revenge.
There are no winners
with revenge.
<i>Wow.</i>
Look
at all those stars.
<i>They're like diamonds.</i>
The last time I sat
beneath stars like this...
I was with her.
I've felt this pain for so long.
It's all I know.
When I lost Longclaw...
I felt the same way.
Did your pain
eventually go away?
No.
But in time, I learned
there's something
even more powerful than pain.
The love we felt for each other.
That's what you need
to hold on to, Shadow.
Maria might be gone,
but your love will
always remain.
"The light shines even
though the star is gone."
This whole mess is my fault.
I've been so blinded
by rage, I thought...
I had no choice.
You always have a choice.
But making the right
one is never easy.
One more thing I learned
is that when you really
screw something up,
you can't fix it on your own.
Gotta go fast.
Don't tell me you've
got a catchphrase.
That's right, new hedgehog.
And everyone loves it.
I... will... not...
try...
to stop... my...
elders... from...
destroying... the... world!
Playtime is over.
There's no going back now.
Set up defense.
Damn you, autocorrect!
Mantis!
Oh!
Whee!
I'm right here, arach-nerd.
That's what I call
mantis-scaping.
That's elder abuse!
<i>Alert! Alert! Alert!</i>
Shadow...
I see you've chosen betrayal.
And you were once
so useful to me.
Ready to recycle some tin cans?
Just try to keep up.
Please, Grampsy,
don't do this!
Sorry, kiddo.
Bring Your Grandkid
to Work Day is over.
Any last words?
Just one thing...
that I never thought I'd say.
What is it?
"I love you"?
No.
It was something even better.
But I'm not gonna say it if
that's the way you're gonna be.
Okay. Bye.
Grandchildren.
All the fun and none
of the responsibility.
- Huh?
- Oh, right. You did.
Victory!
Say what you want
about my granddad,
he made one hell
of a bug zapper.
We got to stop that laser!
I knew there was something
I was forgetting.
We're out of time. The
cannon is about to fire!
Where are you?
Oh, you know, just
making friends.
They're all yours.
Follow me!
Now, this might hurt a little!
So this was your plan?
Yeah...
Would someone mind shutting
down the giant death ray?
We can't stop the
cannon from firing...
But we can steer it
away from the Earth.
- Coming around to starboard.
- Aye-aye, Doc.
Here we go.
It's a little tight.
Definitely not power steering.
Keep... turning.
Jump in anytime here, guys!
Can't... hold... much... longer.
Yes!
I did it! I did it!
- Oh!
- Ooh!
Look what you did!
- Hey, look down there!
- Sonic!
Oh, Knuckles, please
tell me you have a...
Last one.
Let's make it count.
Ready for a little base of ball?
Deep breath.
One... two... three!
- Really!
- What's happening?
The reactor core is overloading.
It's only a matter of
time before it blows.
So what does that
mean for Earth?
A radioactive atmosphere.
Rain that kills the crops
and melts your flesh.
Other than that...
We're not done here!
You try to stabilize
the reactor.
Buy me some time.
I'll push the station
away from Earth
before it explodes.
This is our last chance
to do the right thing.
Go with God
stinking hedgehog.
<i>Core integrity failing.</i>
I've got you, Sonic!
<i>Initializing
reactor core stabilizers.</i>
This is Doctor Ivo Robotnik,
dedicating my final livestream
to one very special henchman:
<i>Agent Stone.</i>
No, no. Doctor, wait!
<i>If I can't rule the world...</i>
I might as well save it...
for the one and only person
who ever cared about me.
Don't do this, Doctor, please!
Stone, you were more
than a sycophant to me.
You were...
a syco-friend.
I'll miss your lattes with
steamed Austrian goat milk.
I love the way you make 'em!
So... I guess there's only
one thing left to say.
It's been a real drag.
Thanks for nothing.
Sonic, look.
Shadow and Robotnik.
They sacrificed themselves...
to save everyone.
You always have a choice.
Guys, I'm really sorry
for running off like that.
I shouldn't have
left you behind.
The truth is...
you're the best teammates a
hedgehog could ever ask for.
And the best friends.
Can you ever forgive me?
Team Sonic?
How about just "team"?
Goodbye, Doctor.
Big
finish. Mmm!
Now that's what I call teamwork.
Okay! It's ready!
Knuckles, how could you?
Gotta be faster than that!
Give me a break.
Still moving a little
slow over here.
- Donut Lord!
- Yay!
Okay, Knuckles, that's...
I am having the love.
I want the love!
Aww...
Get in here, Ozzy.
It's great to be back together.
We're stronger than ever.
And nothing is gonna
stand in our way.
Except that one piece
of unfinished business.
And way out in front, to the
surprise of absolutely no one,
it's the Blue Blur!
Often imitated,
never duplicated,
the one, the only...
Let's do this!
Yeah!
All right,
boys, try and keep up.
Sonic the Hedgehog is
Family Champion once again!
Tails?
Knuckles?
Okay. Yeah, I overshot
the finish line.
Okay, so
how do I get back?
If you're gonna take a shot
at the fastest creature
in the universe...
you'd better not miss.
Um... I'm flattered
by the cosplay,
but you got a few details wrong.
I can't blame you, though.
It's hard to copy perfection.
That's a neat trick.
What? Who are you?