Come on, one car?
Hey, buddy! Where's the fire?
Got kids living around here.
What?
Twenty minutes ago, an energy surge
knocked out power
across the entire Pacific Northwest.
What do we know?
Well, our first instinct
was it was an EMP.
But electromagnetic pulses
don't have that kind of power.
NASA has ruled out
meteor strikes or solar flares.
The Department of Energy says
it's not a power plant malfunction.
Well, sounds like we're really good
at figuring out what it wasn't.
This could be a prelude
to a larger attack.
I'm suggesting we scramble
the Fifth and Sixth Regiment.
No, no, no, no.
This needs a much more sophisticated mind.
Someone who understands technology.
- You want to send in a lab rat?
- Not just any lab rat.
A lab rat with teeth.
You're not suggesting
who I think you're suggesting.
- I know, he's a little weird.
- Weird?
- No. No way.
- He's a psychological tire fire!
But he's also brilliant.
Five PhDs, IQ off the charts.
And his drone tech is revolutionary!
You're sure he can handle this?
He has a perfect operations record.
- Remember the coup in Pakistan?
- No.
Or the uprising in Azerbaijanistan?
- That's not even a country.
- Exactly.
And you can thank Robotnik for that.
I can't believe you're
bringing that freak into this.
Neither can I, but...
we have no choice.
What the...
Are you in charge here?
You've never seen
anything like this before.
It says I'm the top banana
in a world full of hungry little monkeys.
Allow me to clarify.
In a sequentially ranked hierarchy
based on level of critical importance,
the disparity between us
is too vast to quantify.
- Agent Stone?
- The Doctor thinks you're basic.
I'm initiating a sweep sequence.
Ten miles in every direction
should suffice.
Ah... my babies.
Whoo! Look what came out of my egg sac.
You know what I love about machines?
They do what they're told.
They follow their programming.
They don't need time off to get drunk
and put the boat in the water.
Now you do what you're told.
Stand over there on the edge
of your personal abyss...
and watch my machines do your job.
- Can you feel it, Stone?
- I can feel it, Doctor.
It's evolution, Stone.
It's evolution!
- Agent Stone?
- Doctor.
Do you see anything useful in this image?
- Nothing at all, Doctor.
- Of course you don't.
Your eyes weren't
expertly trained to spot tracks
by the Native American Shadow Wolves.
That's extraordinary.
No. What's extraordinary is,
I've determined the exact height, weight
and spinal curvature of this creature,
and my computer
can't find a single match for it
anywhere in Earth's animal kingdom.
This blackout was not a terrorist attack,
and that's no baby bigfoot.
This guy is something else...
entirely.
Divert all search units
to the site of the footprint.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for me.
Here we go.
It didn't work out on Earth,
but that's okay.
You're going to a safe world.
A nice, safe world full of mushrooms.
Mushrooms that'll be your only friends.
That sounds awful. I can't do this.
You have to do it.
There's no other option.
All right.
SFPD, pending background check.
Paws in the air!
Uh, meow?
Ow!
"San... Francisco?"
No.
What?
The blue devil.
- Donut Lord?
- It can talk.
You're not...
You're not here to abduct me, are you?
You abducted me.
Okay, that's a fair point. What are you?
Why are you hiding out in my garage?
I needed somewhere safe.
And you're the only person
I could think of, Donut Lord.
Why do you keep calling me Donut Lord?
'Cause you talk to donuts.
And then eat them if they get out of line.
Again, fair.
Wait, wait, wait.
Where are all the mushrooms?
Why am I still on Earth? What is...
Oh, no! I lost my rings.
What?
What's happening?
Is this your mother ship?
I'm not in the mood to get probed.
You think you're worried?
I'm not even wearing pants.
What the...
- They're coming for me!
- Who's coming for you?
What's that got to do with me?
I don't have time to explain,
but you have to help me.
No, I don't. Why?
Well, my legs, which normally
would be classified as lethal weapons,
feel like spaghetti.
I need your help. Please.
It's life or death.
Fine. Come with me.
All right, stay here. And be quiet.
Hello there!
Can I help you?
Good morning, my rural chum.
I'm... from the power company,
investigating the blackout.
If you don't mind, I'd like to take
a few readings inside your house?
No kidding? You're from the power company?
- Mmm.
- Oh, you must know my buddy Spencer.
- We play softball together.
- Ah! Spence.
He's a good man.
- Yeah. Come on in!
- Great.
Take all the readings you need.
Except, uh...
doesn't the power company usually take
their readings from outside the house?
That way they can check them
even if you're not home.
Also, my buddy Spencer
works for the gas company,
and he's more of an Ultimate Frisbee guy.
So, you want to tell me
why you think I'm dumb enough
to just let you walk inside my house?
- I'm sorry, Mister...
- Wachowski.
But everyone calls me Tom.
Except my dentist, he calls me Tim.
But it's gone on for so long now
that it would be weird if I corrected him.
Well, Tom, whose dentist calls him Tim,
you may have noticed that this entire town
has been experiencing a power outage.
Yep, no lights. Picked up on that.
Twenty minutes ago, I tracked
an energy pulse with a similar signature
to the one that caused that disruption.
Listen, uh, Mister...
Doctor.
Dr. Robotnik. But my dentist calls me Rob.
Hmm.
Look, uh, Dr. Robotskeez.
Um, I'm sure what you're here for
is very serious,
but it's got nothing to do with me.
You can ask anyone in town.
- Everyone knows me.
- I bet they do.
I'm sure you're hella popular
with the Jebs and Merles and Billy Bobs,
in this glorified gas-station rest stop.
Betcha go way back
to the days of tippin' cows
and playin' in a jug band!
And maybe someday you'll achieve your goal
of getting a Costco card
or adopting a Labradoodle.
But the reality is, I surpassed
everything you're ever going to do...
before I was a toddler.
I was spitting out formulas
while you were still spitting up formula.
I was breastfed, actually.
Nice. Rub that in my orphan face.
Mr. Wachowski,
are you familiar with US Code 904,
Title 10, Article 104?
- Yeah, who isn't...
- "Anyone...
who attempts to aid an enemy
of the United States shall suffer death."
And if I'm the one that catches you,
it'll be even worse.
Worse than death?
Compared to what I...
- Old pipes.
- Yeah.
Probably just the house settling.
Nothing to see here!
Hey!
Here's the thing.
I'm never wrong.
Well, first time for everything, I guess.
Would you like some cake?
I hear raccoons have the cleanest mouths
of any animal that routinely eats garbage.
Look at that.
I was right.
Note the lack of surprise.
Shall we try this again?
I'm going to give you five seconds
to tell me where it is.
- Five...
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Four.
- Hey, tough guy. I'm a cop,
and you're threatening an officer.
How can you threaten somebody
who never existed?
Three...
Come on! Rack your brain.
You might be able to come up with some
lame excuse to go on living, in two...
one.
Wait! Don't hurt him!
Stay behind me.
Hiya!
Come on! We gotta get out of here.
Doctor! Are you okay?
I saw a guy race out of here and thought...
That you should stop them?
Whatever this creature is,
it's our job to secure it,
neutralize it,
uncover the source of its power.
And if it resists...
we take it apart... piece by piece.
See what makes it tick.
- Stone?
- Doctor?
Call Optical Illusions.
Tell them I need new frames.
They know what kind I like.
Oh, and bring that quill.
Yes, Doctor.
All right, there's
gonna be rules on this trip.
Number one,
do exactly as I say all the time.
- Got it?
- Got it, Donut Lord.
Would you stop with the "Donut Lord"?
I have a name. It's Tom.
I'm Sonic.
Sonic. Sonic.
I'm gonna go check in with Wade,
see if he knows what's going on.
Hello. Green Hills Police Department.
- Wade, it's me.
- Hi.
I'm so glad that you called.
Uh, so, some guys came in
asking some questions.
Uh, they're a little creepy.
Wait, what kind of questions?
Um, questions about terrorism?
I told them that
I've gone ice fishing with Tom.
He doesn't know how to make a bomb.
He can't even make bait in the cold.
All right, Wade, listen to me.
This is really important.
Don't tell them that we talked, okay?
You know, I think they already know.
Mr. Wachowski.
Tom.
I want you to know
that the only other person
who ever punched me in the face
was the school bully.
He hit me in the cafeteria,
causing a blunt-force contusion
to the soft tissue
surrounding my orbital bone.
Humiliated me in front of
the entire school!
And do you know what I did in response?
Uh, I'm assuming that you reported him
to the principal's office
'cause that kind of behavior
is really unacceptable.
No. I examined the inefficiency of a world
where brawn trumped brain,
and I used technology
to resolve that inefficiency.
The boy ate his meals
through a straw for a year.
And I have never lost a fight again.
Until today.
Hey, hooray for me then, huh?
No, because you're about to become
the bully with the straw!
I'm coming for you, Mr. Wachowski.
And when I catch you, I'll...
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, hello, hello?
I think he actually hung up,
because I notice that the light isn't on.
Thank you, Officer Brainfart.
If you give me a second,
I can get an outside line.
No. Don't be bothered.
You just sit there and be "u"... 'seless.
Thomas Wachowski, accused of committing
an act of domestic terrorism.
Wachowski is considered
armed and dangerous.
Any information regarding his whereabouts
should be reported to
local authorities immediately.
Did he say where he was going?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Like I'd ever tell you.
Stand down, Agent Stone.
This well-meaning citizen
obviously doesn't understand
the urgency of the matter.
Really?
Now that's
what I call good cop, bad cop.
Hoy!
Left yourself open.
Judging by the quickest route
to San Francisco,
the approximate speed of their vehicle,
and local weather conditions...
they should be...
right about...
here.
- That's brilliant, sir.
- Thanks...
for nothing.
Eeny, meeny, miny...
mayhem.
- Look, I get your poi...
- Whoa!
Yeah!
Sonic!
- Your body!
- Oh, no, not again!
Hey! Hold on!
- Why?
- Because I'm gonna do this.
Sonic!
Is that all you got?
No, but thank you for asking.
- Uh-oh.
- Sonic! Get back in the truck!
Ha!
Incoming!
Yes, we did it!
We did not do it. Who is this guy?
Ever wonder where
your tax dollars are going?
My turn.
Here, just keep us going straight.
I put it in cruise control.
Ha-ha! Whoo!
Oh!
Give me a big, fat break!
Aw, this one is cute. Let's keep him.
Aah!
Buzz off.
That doesn't sound good.
- No, beeping is bad. Get rid of it!
- I'm trying.
Throw it out the win... Throw it anywhere!
- I can't get it off.
- All right, I'm pulling over.
- Did I get it?
- Nope.
Here. Hold still.
It's going, it's going...
It's still here.
Get off me.
Sonic!
No, no, no, no, no.
Hey. Come on. You're all right.
Wake up. Wake up.
Did we get 'em?
Oh. No, there they are.
They are real survivors, those two.
Can we have a moment?
Pin yourself to the wall.
You know, I won't miss you
when you're gone.
Human beings are unreliable and stupid,
and I care very little about them.
But my machines are diligent, relentless.
They're everything to me!
Huh?
Mmm?
Come on, buddy.
You're gonna be all right.
You'll be all right.
I just thought you might like a latte
with steamed Austrian goat milk.
Who do I look like, an imbecile?
Of course I want a latte.
I love the way you make them!
Ready the prototype.
With this kind of power,
my machines can finally reach
their full potential.
He's gonna be okay, Jojo.
Oh, thank God. He's gonna be okay, right?
I'm a vet, Tom. I don't even know
what I'm looking at here.
He's a hedgehog. Or so he says.
- It talks?
- Almost constantly.
Okay.
- Holy...
- What?
His pulse is super-fast.
That actually might be normal for him.
I don't know. You gotta help him, Maddie.
I don't know his physiology.
He doesn't seem to have any broken bones.
He's just really banged up.
Oh, look at his poor little feet.
Hang in there, buddy.
You're gonna be all right.
- So, this is it?
- That's it. That's your pyramid.
Wow, look at that thing!
What happens now?
- Oh. He's... gone.
- Yep.
No good. You need a special key
to get to the roof.
What now?
Time for me to abuse
the power entrusted to me.
We got a jumper on the roof.
Gotta get up there fast or we're gonna
have a human pancake on our hands.
You came all the way from Montana.
Yeah. That's how serious it is.
Okay.
You just saved a life.
All right. What are we looking for?
This.
Okay. What happens now?
Now all I have to do
is think of where I want
the other end of the ring
to appear, and I throw it.
So that's it? We did it?
Yeah. We did it!
- All right.
- Um, you gotta go, right?
- Yeah, I gotta go.
I gotta go. We gotta go too.
See... All right, bye-bye.
Welcome to San Francisco, Mr. Wachowski.
Are you enjoying the clam chowder?
It's the government wack job
who keeps trying to kill us.
Unsuccessfully!
Nice of you to swing by
on your way to Comic-Con.
Yeah, what are you wearing?
It's a flight suit, designed to modulate
my body temperature and reduce drag.
Yeah, and yet you still are one.
Ooh-hoo! Good one.
You are catching fire, Thomas.
Oh, and speaking of heat,
I see you've taken a lover.
Does she have a name
or should we just call her
"collateral damage"?
Hey, watch your mouth.
Unless you want a little more
of what I gave you earlier?
I punched him in the face.
The time for talking is over!
It's time to push buttons.
I was not expecting that.
But I was expecting not to expect
something, so it doesn't count.
Pew, pew-pew-pew, pew-pew-pew-pew!
Oh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! No, no, no!
Aah.
Can I give you one genius piece of advice?
Don't run.
It'll only hurt more if you do.
And it's bad for your joints.
They've proved it.
All right, Eggman. You wanna get fast?
Let's get fast.
The hard way it is.
That was an illegal left, by the way.
How is this possible?
No one's ever caught up to me before.
Coming through!
Sacrebleu!
Excusez-moi, monsieur!
Here we go. Room to open it up.
I can't lose him!
Lost visual contact.
You're not allowed up there!
It's one of the Seven Wonders!
Get out of here!
You're an astonishing little creature.
It'll be fun to take you back to the lab
for a litany of invasive
exploratory procedures.
Any last words?
Guac. I like that word.
I don't have to tell you how
many scientific breakthroughs
have been made possible by animal testing.
You're being very selfish.
Going my way?
What the...
Who the hell do you think you are?
I'm the Donut Lord, you son of a...
Autopilot, adjust.
Why?
Why would you throw
your life away for this thing?
That's why I don't have friends.
Next thing you know,
you're somebody's best man.
They want to have the wedding out of town.
Like nobody has anything better to do!
Anyway, where were we?
Oh, yes. You were about to die.
That's our sheriff you're messing with.
I don't mean to be indelicate here,
but someone should get some ice,
keep the body fresh.
He's just a silly little alien.
He didn't belong here!
Everyone, get back!
I think you have something
that belongs to me.
Whoa.
Ooh! Now you've done it!
- I think these belong to you.
- You did pretty good, space hog.
- Thanks, Donut Lord.
All right, everybody. Nothing to see here.
Let's disperse.
Just another ordinary day in Green Hills.
My grasp on sanity remains... absolute.
Isn't that right, Agent Stone?
Why don't you get a head start?
Do some rock-connaissance.
Rock-connaissance!
Come on! That's hilarious!
What's the matter with you?
Here's the "sitch." Uninhabited planet.
No resources, no supplies,
no apparent way home.
A lesser man would die here.
I'll be home by Christmas.
Rock-connaissance!
Come on! Cheer up!
If these readings are accurate, he's here.
I found him.
I just hope I'm not too late.