[ Alien Screeches, Faint ]
[ Alien Roars, Faint ]
[ Typing ]
[ Hisses ]
[ Ripley Narrating ]
My mommy always said
there were no monsters.
No real ones.
But there are.
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ]
We've seen
no additional defects.
She's perfect.
Mm-hmm.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Electronic Whirring ]
[ Machine Beeping ]
Careful.
Two centimeters.
Okay.
Yeah.
Ready with that amnio.
[ Beeping Continues ]
Oh.
And...
there it is.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Exhales ]
No.
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Clicks ]
Be careful.
[ Alarm Stops ]
[ Screeches ]
Jesus.
Clamp.
What about her?
Can we keep her alive?
How's the host?
- [ Beeping ]
- Doing well.
Sew her back up.
[ Mouths Word ]
Excellent work, everybody.
[ Alien Screeching, Faint ]
[ Hatch Opens ]
And how is
our Number 8 today?
Appears to be
in good health.
Hmm?
How good?
Excellent,
as in completely off
our projected charts.
Look at the scar tissue.
See the recession?
This is from three days ago?
Exactly.
Oh, this is good.
This is very good.
You're gonna make us all
very proud.
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasps, Wheezing ]
[ Choking ]
[ Groans ]
No.
[ Panting ]
Don't. I'm all right.
Now try this.
[ Mouthing Word ]
- Hand.
- Close.
Glove.
[ Woman Over Monitor ]
Number 8?
Fruit.
[ Woman Continues ]
Good. Cherries.
It's unprecedented.
Totally.
She's operating...
at a completely adult capacity.
What about her memories?
There are gaps.
- And some degree
of synaptic dissonance.
- [ Woman ] You know this.
She's freaked.
[ Woman ] Come on.
It has connective difficulties,
caused by a biochemical imbalance,
causing emotional autism.
Certain reactions—
All right,
wait a second!
It has memories.
Why does it have memories?
Well, I'm guessing, but...
inherited memories,
passed down generationally
at a genetic level...
by the aliens, like its strength.
Plus a, uh,
highly evolved form of instinct.
An unexpected benefit
from the genetic crossing.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho.
I see.
Stupid me.
Of course.
An unexpected benefit
ofthe genetic process.
Oh! And I didn't
even think of that!
You're not thinking
termination?
Oh, boy,
am I thinking termination.
General,
we do not perceive this
to be a problem.
Ellen Ripley died trying to
wipe this species out.
For all intents and purposes,
she succeeded.
I'm not anxious to see her
taking up her old hobbies.
That won't happen.
We won't tell her.
Oh, I see.
And that's supposed
to comfort me?
[ Beeping ]
[ Male Electronic voice ]
Identification, please.
[ Exhaling ]
[ Whirring, Buzzes ]
Please try again.
[ Exhaling ]
Thank you, General Perez.
Bottom line is,
she looks at me funny
one time,
I'm putting her down.
Okay, as far as I'm concerned,
Number 8...
is a meat... by-product.
Her Majesty here
is the real payoff.
When does she start producing?
Days.
Less maybe.
We need the cargo.
I told you,
it's on its way.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Growling ]
Fork.
- Fuck.
- It's-It's "fork."
How did you—
How did... we get you?
Yes.
[ Fork Clinks ]
[ Sighs ]
Hard work.
We used blood samples...
from Fiori Sixteen on ice,
where you died.
We've remade you.
We cloned you.
- Does it grow?
- Yeah.
Very rapidly.
[ Chuckles ]
It's a queen.
How did you know that?
She'll breed.
You'll die.
Everyone in the company
will die.
In the— In the-
In the company?
Weyland-Yutani.
Ripley 8's
former employers.
Terran growth conglomerate.
They had...
defense contracts
under the military.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Fork Clinks ]
I think you will find
that, uh,
things have changed
a great deal since your time.
I doubt that.
We're not flying
blind here, you know.
It's United Systems Military,
not some greedy corporation.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, it won't
make any difference.
You're still gonna die.
How do you feel about that?
I wish you could understand
what we're trying to do here.
The potential for this species
goes way beyond
urban pacification.
New alloys, new vaccines.
Nothing like this we've ever seen
on any world before.
You should be very proud.
Oh.
I am.
And the animal itself-
wondrous.
The potential, unbelievable,
once we've tamed them.
[ Chuckles ]
Roll over. Play dead.
Heel?
Mm-hmm.
You can't teach it tricks.
Why not?
We're teaching you.
[ Man ]
Time to enjoy some of
the general's hospitality, Christie.
Great.
Army food.
Yeah. It'll do
till we get the family wagon
up to spec, I reckon.
Yeah.
That is if the natives
are friendly.
How's that?
Good.
We expecting any,
uh, trouble?
Nah. From Perez, I doubt it.
But you never know.
We've been there before.
Where are the others?
In the cargo bay.
[ Whirring ]
[ Whistling "Popeye The Sailor Man" ]
[ Whirring Stops ]
[ Thuds ]
[ Continues ]
[ Making Monkey Sounds ]
[ Screeches ]
[ Monkey Sounds Continue ]
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Grunts ]
What is wrong with you?
[ Man ]
Just a little target practice.
vriess isn't complaining.
Goddamn it!
Johner, you son of a bitch!
Come on, man.
You didn't feel a thing.
[ Making Monkey Sounds ]
[Johner]
Whoa.
The knife.
Son of a bitch!
[ Laughing ]
[Johner]
Don't push me, little Call.
You hang with us for a while,
you'll find out
I am not the man
with whom to fuck!
Hey, son, I'll give you
my authorization code.
It's E-A-T-M-E.
[ Beeps ]
[ Man Over Speaker ]
I'm sorry, sir.
Could you repeat that?
Little prick.
[ Male Electronic voice
Over Loudspeaker]
I am Father.
Welcome to the U.S.M. Auriga.
Step forward for
contraband and weapons search.
Please report
any infectious diseases...
to the medical officers.
Levels 7 through 12
are off-limits to civilians.
[ Device Whirring ]
Thank you foryour cooperation.
Go.
Get your hands up,
please, sir.
What?
Could you get
your hands up, please?
[ Device Whirring ]
[ Beeping ]
There are no weapons
allowed on board, sir.
My own recipe.
Way more dangerous.
Nice welcome, Perez.
What the hell is this?
What, are you afraid
the six of us are gonna hijack
your damn ship or what?
Just a minor concern
that one of your
asshole crew members...
is gonna get drunk
and put a bullet
through the hull.
We happen to be
in space, Elgyn.
No shit. How you been?
[ Device Beeping ]
Wanna check the chair?
[ Beeping Stops ]
Elgyn, these were
very, very hard to come by.
[ Woman Singing Aria, Indistinct ]
So was our cargo.
- You're, uh, not about to plead
poverty on me, are you, General?
- No.
Just saying very few people
deal in cash nowadays.
Just the ones don't like
to keep business records.
- Yourself, for example.
- Drink, Elgyn?
Constantly.
[ Continues ]
Now, I'm gonna take
a wild guess here, General,
but I'm thinking whatever
you got going on here,
it, uh, ain't exactly approved
by Congress.
Who's the...
new filly you got
on board, Elgyn?
Call. Little girl
playing pirates.
She makes an impression.
[ Chuckling ]
Mind you, uh, I think
she's just a tad curious...
about, uh,
this little transaction of ours.
I mean, I can't say as I blame her.
It's awfully cloak-and-dagger stuff.
It's a military operation.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but, uh,
I was under the impression
that, uh,
most army medical labs
don't have to operate
outside of regulated space.
- What do you want, Elgyn?
What can I do foryou?
- Me?
- Yeah.
- Oh, two days bed and board.
You know,
vriess might wanna snag a part
here or there, whatever.
I mean, uh, if it's not imposing.
Mi casa es su casa.
[ Beeping ]
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Father Over Loudspeaker]
Please direct cargo
to med lab center, area "G."
Follow the lit path.
Do not deviate.
Cargo status: stable.
Life-forms intact.
Stasis uninterrupted.
Med lab center
is off-limits to civilians.
Thank you.
[Johner Chuckles ]
Oh.
Hey. Chill.
[ Call ] Oh, please.
You know I can't
lay off the tall ones.
Howyou doin'?
How about a little
one-on-one?
What do you say?
You got some moves
on you, girl.
[ Christie ]
Oh, man.
Mm-hmm.
Well, now, if you don't
wanna play basketball,
I know some other indoor sports.
[ Sniffing ]
Come on, now.
Give me the ball.
[ Groaning ]
Okay, I got a new game.
Tag!
[ Shouts ]
Ripley? Ripley.
[ Whistles ]
You've had enough fun.
What the hell are you?
[ Chuckles ]
Something of a predator,
isn't she?
Yes, she continues
to make us all very proud.
[ Clicks ]
[ Wheelchair Motor Whirring ]
[ Woman ] We're coming up on just
one minute and 30 seconds left...
to order this one-of-a-kind
collector's item.
Jesus Christ,Johner,
what do you put in this shit,
battery acid?
Just for color.
[ Clang ]
[ Growling Softly ]
[ Hisses ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Screeches ]
[ Buzzes ]
[ Hissing ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Growls ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growling Stops ]
So, we're a fast learner.
[ Woman ] Now here's a fine item.
This is a really
good show, man.
[ Woman ]
It's from the Gut Cutter's
Celebration Collection,
makers of premier
knives and edge ware.
The knife features
a stainless steel blade,
perfect for any use
in hunting or in the home.
The pro handle
is made from authentic
antique plywood...
and stained in brilliant colors
for an uncanny charm.
Hey, man, that shit
is not easy to come by!
Why don't you take
a walk outside?
...to a cutting edge
that will rip through anything—
[ Liquid Splashes ]
Great!
I'm so sorry.
[ Christie ]
Now I smell like this shit!
[ Chuckling ]
[Johner ] If bitches
can't handle this shit,
bitches should stay away
from this shit!
[ Christie ]
Go to bed. Fucking bitch.
[ Beeping ]
[ Father Over Loudspeaker]
Identification, please.
[ Whirring, Buzzes ]
Please try again.
- [ Chimes ]
- Thank you, General Perez.
Well?
You gonna kill me,
orwhat?
There's no point,
is there?
They've taken it
out ofyou.
Where is it?
Is it on the ship?
You mean my baby.
I don't get it.
Ifthey took it out,
why are they
keeping you alive?
Well, they're curious.
I'm the latest thing.
Look.
I can make it all stop.
The pain, this nightmare.
That's all I can offeryou.
What makes you think...
I would let you do that?
Who are you?
Ripley, Ellen,
Lieutenant First Class,
number 36706.
Ellen Ripley died
200 years ago.
You're not her.
I'm not her.
[ Sighs ]
Who am I?
You're a thing, a construct.
They grew you in a fucking lab.
And now they brought it
out ofyou.
Not all the way out.
I can feel it...
behind my eyes.
I can hear it moving.
You gotta help me stop this thing
before it gets loose.
It's too late.
You can't stop it.
It's inevitable.
Not as long as I'm around.
You'll never get out of here alive.
I don't care.
Really?
[ Whispers ]
I can make it stop.
Go on. Get out of here.
They're looking for you.
[ Weapon Cocks,
Whirring ]
I think you're gonna find
that this was very ill-advised.
Where are her friends?
They're in
the mess hall, sir.
Well, you find them, now.
Quietly.
What the hell
is going on here?
Smells like
a double-cross, boss.
Where's the other one?
With the chair?
Don't ever touch me.
Ever.
You wanna tell us what this is?
You wanna tell me
who you're workin' for.
What?
- Wren, they got nothing
to do with this.
- To do with what?
Do you know what
the penalties for
terrorist activity are?
No goddamn terrorists
on my crew. Call, there
something you wanna tell me?
Look. I don't care whether
you knew or not. You brought
a terrorist on board a military vessel.
And as far as I am concerned,
you all die with her!
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I understand.
Christie.
[ Elgyn ]
Down!
Freeze!
[ Gunshot ]
Stop! Drop your weapons!
And you!
Drop that piece of shit,
or I blow his head off!
- Can't do that, man.
- Drop it now!
- Can't do that.
They're attached to me.
- I'm not fucking with you!
You're all under arrest
for a code eight,
which is concealed weapons,
and a code 12, which is murder!
Release Dr. Wren!
Kiss my ass.
Put down your weapons
and assume the fucking—
[ Groans, Coughs ]
Everybody okay?
[ Soldier Coughs Over Monitor]
[Johner Over Monitor ]
Real easy, soldier boy.
[ Man ]
Security.
Get up!
There is a serious problem
in the mess hall.
You lie to me now,
little girl,
I will cut your throat
and leave you here to die,
you understand me?
[ Man ] This is security, Section 2.
We do not read you.
Hello? Goddamn it! Hello?
We do not copy you.
Please repeat.
Hello?
[ Growling ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Both Hissing ]
[ Shrieking ]
Gediman!
He's conducting
illegal experiments.
He is breeding some sort of-
[Johner ] Ice the goddamn mole!
Listen to me!
He is breeding an alien species.
More than dangerous.
If those things get loose,
it's gonna make
the Lacerta plague look like
a fucking square dance!
Shut up!
[ Alarm Blaring, Faint ]
Listen.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Father Over Loudspeaker]
Your attention, please.
Security breach, med lab,
Level 1 5.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Machine Gun Fire ]
[ Men Shouting ]
Go. Let's get back to the Betty.
Doctor and soldier boy here
can see us to the door.
[ Woman ] What about vriess?
[Johner ]
Fuck vriess.
[ Father ]
Your attention, please.
Unauthorized opening
of cage three.
of cages five,
seven, eight, 10-
- Move it! Now!
- [ Father ]
Evacuation.
- Go! Go now!
- Evacuation.
[ Shrieking ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Father ]
This is not a drill.
- Evacuation.
- Move it! Go! Get on board!
Your attention, please.
Nonhuman presence detected,
Levels 21 , 23,
27, 14,
Level 38, Level 39.
- [ Hissing ]
- Evacuation.
Proceed to lifeboats.
This is not a drill.
Thank you for your cooperation.
[ Growls ]
[ Roars ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Roaring ]
- I'll give you holes,
you slimy bastard!
[ Shouting ]
Move it! Let's go!
- [ Father ]
Final lifeboat ready for launch.
- Get aboard!
[ Growling ]
[ All Shouting ]
Go!
[ Father]
Complete evacuation now.
Grenade.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Gasping ]
[ Growling ]
[ Father]
Alert. Alert.
Evacuation incomplete.
Civilian presence detected
in area "H." Warning.
Main vessel
declared uninhabitable.
[ Alarm Blaring, Faint ]
[ Christie ]
Elgyn, come on.
Let's move, man.
Yeah.
[ Clatter ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Woman ]
Elgyn!
God. Elgyn?
[ Christie ]
Elgyn?
[ Woman ]
Elgyn!
[Johner ]
Easy, Hillard!
Christie, give me a hand here!
Get him up!
Give me a hand here!
[ Hillard ]
Come on! Let's get him up!
Move out ofthe way!
[ Sobbing ]
No!
Ah, shit.
What the fuck did this?
What's in this place?
[ Roaring ]
- [Johner ]
Call, get down!
- [ Christie ] What the fuck is that?
Don't shoot!
It's in front of the hull!
[ Snarling ]
What is that?
Come on, man.
Time to go. Time to go!
[ Christie ] Get back!
- [ Roaring ]
- Damn!
Call, time to go!
Come on, Call!
Get the goddamn door open!
[ All Shouting ]
We can't open it!
We can't open the door!
[ Shouting Continues ]
- [ Soldier ] We gotta go back!
- [Johner] I'm not going back!
You go back!
[ Hisses ]
- What the fuck?
- [ Ripley Panting ]
Was it everything
you hoped for?
[ Hillard ]
Leave him alone!
What do we do now, man?
Same thing we're doin'.
Get the hell outta here!
What if there's more?
I say we stay here, man.
Let the army guys deal.
Where the fuck
are the army guys?
They're dead!
Well, then we don't need
this asshole anymore.
- Step back!
- No, you step back!
- Stop it!
- You got no authority here!
[ Alarm Blaring, Faint ]
Doctor, that thing
that killed my partner,
that's your pet
science project?
Yes.
- Let me do him right now, man!
- I should let him do you right now!
How many more are there?
Twelve.
- [Johner]
Twelve?
- Twelve.
Twelve.
There'll be more.
So,
who do I have to fuck
to get off this boat?
I can get you off.
Maybe not the boat, but-
Let's get out of here.
No, wait a second here.
She was the host
for these monsters.
Wren cloned her because
she had one inside her.
She's not human.
She was part of his experiment,
and she will turn on us
in a second.
[ Christie ]
I don't give a shit
what she is.
[ Call ]
She's too much of a risk.
We have to leave her.
- She comes.
- We can't trust her!
I don't trust anyone.
Ifwe're gonna survive this mess,
we all stick together.
Agreed?
Hillard, we gotta go.
It's not over.
We gotta get to the Betty.
It's like killing
your own kind.
It was in my way.
[ Beeps ]
I can't believe
you did that.
Did what?
Killed one of'em.
[ Christie Exhales ]
Oh, man!
Who were you expecting, Santa Claus?
- [ Sighs ]
- Thought you were toast
for certain, man.
Shit. Where's Elgyn?
Oh, shit.
Hey, man, what if
we get to the Betty
and they're all over it?
- All the activity's been in the aft sector
by the barracks. Why would they move?
- [ Ripley ] They won't.
If they send anyone out,
it'll be, uh, here,
where the meat is.
Yeah. Well, I say
if we wanna make any decent time,
I say we ditch the cripple.
- No offense, man.
- None taken.
Nobody is left behind.
Not even you, Johner.
- What's the quickest way out of here?
- After the cooling tower,
there's a freight elevator.
It runs from the top
of the ship down to
Engineering Level 1 deck.
- Take us straight to the dock.
- Sounds reasonable. Let's do it.
We're moving.
- What?
- [ Ripley ]
The ship is moving.
I can feel it.
The ship has stealth run.
There's no way you can tell.
She's right.
The ship's been go since the attack.
That's a standard
emergency procedure.
That's right.
Any serious problem,
and the ship autopilots
back to home base.
And you were planning
on letting us know this?
Nobody asked.
- [ Scoffs ]
- What's home base?
Earth.
Oh, great.
- Bastard.
- [Johner]
Earth?
I'd rather stay here
with the things, man.
How long until we get to Earth?
Three hours almost.
We gotta blow the ship.
Call, you're not blowing this ship.
Not while we're on it, okay?
We get out of this shit,
you do as you please,
all right?
Earth, man.
What a shit-hole.
[ Ripley ]
It's clear.
Hey, Ripley.
I heard you, like,
ran into these things before.
That's right.
Wow, man.
So, like, what did you do?
I died.
[ Wheelchair Whirring ]
[ Soldier ]
Not that way!
[ Christie ]
Ripley.
Ripley, come on.
Ripley, we got no time
for sightseeing here.
[ Wren ]
Ripley, don't.
[ Gasping ]
[ Sobs ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Machine Beeping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gasps ]
Hel—
Kill... me.
Kill me.
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Don't do it, Ripley.
Don't do what?
What's the big deal, man?
Fuckin' waste of ammo.
Let's go.
Must be a chick thing.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Faint Snarl ]
[ Hisses ]
Am I dreaming, or is this not
the shit we brought with us?
Yeah, it's the same shit.
Stinks in here, man.
Let's keep moving.
[ Screams ]
Get away from me!
Drop the rod, man.
- Do it!
- Get away from me.
[ Clangs ]
Get away from me.
Who are you people?
What's happening here?
[ Christie ]
Calm down.
What's happening here is
we're getting the fuck off
this ghost ship, okay?
Ship? What ship?
Where am I?
I was in cryo, right?
On my way to Xarem, right?
Work crew for the nickel
refinery, right?
I wake up.
I know I don't understand.
Oh, God. Uh, I s- I saw—
I saw horrible things.
Look, you're coming with us.
It's too dangerous for you here.
[ Breathing Erratically ]
[ Sniffing ]
Leave him.
Fuck you.
We're not leaving him here.
He's got one inside of him.
I can smell it.
[ Man ]
Inside me?
What's inside me?
[Johner] Hey, man.
I don't want one of those things
birthing anywhere near my ass.
It's a bad risk.
- What's inside me?
- Look, we can't just leave him here.
- I thought you came here
to stop 'em from spreadin'.
- What's inside me?
- There's gotta be a process.
Can't you stop it?
- [ Christie ] Got no time for that.
- I can't do it here.
The lab is out of order.
- What's inside me?
I could do him.
Back of the head.
Painless.
It might be the best way.
- What's inside me?
- No, there's got
to be another way.
[ Call ]
What ifwe freeze him?
What's in-fuckin'-side me?
There's a monster in your chest.
These guys
hijacked your ship,
and they sold
your cryo tube...
to this... human,
and he put an alien inside of you.
It's a really nasty one.
And in a few hours,
it's gonna burst its way
through your rib cage...
and you're gonna die.
Any questions?
[ Breathing Erratically ]
Who are you?
I'm the monster's mother.
[ Call ]
Look, he comes with us,
we freeze him on the Betty,
then the doctor
can remove it later.
[Johner ]
It's a mess down there!
Is this the only way?
vriess, we gotta lose
the chair.
I know.
Kawlang maneuver,
all right?
Yeah,just like old times.
Yeah.
Must be the cooling tanks.
Somebody must have
opened the valves.
The nasties couldn't have
done this, could they?
We're at the bottom
of the ship.
We have to go through
the kitchen, maybe 90 feet,
to the freight elevator
on the other side.
- I don't like it.
- What's to like?
This sucks!
- Wren, are you sure
about the distance?
- Yes.
- You ready to get wet, partner?
- Yeah.
[ Coughs ]
[ vriess ]
Hey, Christie,
do me a favor.
When we hit the surface
on the other side,
no backstroke, okay?
[ Shouts ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Growling ]
[ Screams ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
[ All Gasping ]
- [ Gasps ]
-Jesus Christ!
[ Gasps ]
They set a goddamn trap.
It's a goddamn ambush!
[ Screeches ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Roaring ]
Distephano!
[ Snarls ]
It won't break.
Give me your weapon.
You really are way too trusting.
No!
You killed her!
You bastard!
- I'll get you!
- [ Chamber Clicks ]
Father, lock the door.
- Christie! Climb! Climb!
- [ Snarls ]
I'm doin' it, man!
Come on!
[ Snarls ]
It's jammed!
Move it!
[ Grunts ]
[ Shots Firing ]
[ Vriess Muttering ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Screams ]
Get off my foot, bitch!
[ Groaning ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Christie ]
Get off me!
[ Grunts ]
Johner!
Get off me!
Aaah! Johner!
Die, motherfucker!
- Do it, man!
- [ Snarls ]
- Hey!
[ Screeches ]
[ Gasps ]
Real nice party, ain't it?
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Groaning, Sobbing ]
Christie! Christie!
Christie! No!
Christie!
What are you doing?
Don't do it!
Don't!
We can make it!
- No!
- [ Screams ]
- [ Groaning, Sobbing ]
- Damn!
[ Grunting ]
[ Breathing Erratically ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Grunts ]
This way.
Come on!
Baby, am I glad to see you.
I was sure that asshole got you.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
You got body armor on?
Yeah. Come on.
You took it in the chest.
I saw it.
[ Chuckles ]
You're a robot?
Son of a bitch!
Our little Call
is just full of surprises.
I should have known.
No human being is that humane.
I thought synthetics
were supposed to be
all logical and shit.
You're just
a big old psycho, girl.
- You're a robot?
- You're a second gen, aren't you?
You're an Auton.
Robots designed
by robots, right?
Hah!
Oh, yeah. That's right.
I remember.
Now, they were
supposed to revitalize
the synthetic industry.
Instead, they buried it.
[ Chuckles ]
They didn't like
being told what to do.
Government ordered
a recall.
Now, I heard—
I had— I had heard...
that only a few-
just a few-
had gotten out intact.
Man, I never, never thought
that I would see one!
Great. She's a toaster oven.
Can we leave now?
- [ Distephano Laughing ]
- [ Ripley ]
How long before we land?
[ Distephano ]
Just under two hours.
[Johner] Hey, vriess.
You got a socket wrench?
Maybe she just needs
an oil change.
[ Father ]
I'm sorry. Access denied.
I can't believe I almost fucked it.
Yeah, like you
never fucked a robot!
[ Ripley ]
You know, if Wren gets in the computer,
he could really screw us.
[Johner] We gotta find a terminal.
No, there's no console
on this level.
We'd have to go back.
Well, we can't go back.
- And I don't know
any of Wren's access codes.
- Help me.
Call.
No. I can't.
Right. You're the new model droid.
You can access
the mainframe by remote.
No, I can't.
I burned my modem.
We all did.
Call, you can still patch in manually.
You know that.
[ Distephano ]
There's ports
in the chapel, up there.
Call.
You're programmed
for that?
Don't make me do this.
Don't make me make you.
[ Sighs ]
I don't want to go in there.
It's like my insides are liquid.
It's not real.
Get over it.
You can blow the ship
before it reaches Earth...
and kill them all.
[ Sniffles ]
Just give us time
to get out first.
Damn it.
Anything?
Hold on.
[ Computer Voice ]
Breach in Sector 7,
Sector 3.
Sector 9 unstable.
Engines operating at 41 %.
Eighty-six minutes
until Earth dock.
[ Sighs ]
[ Normal voice ]
We burned too much energy.
I can't make critical mass.
I can't blow it.
Then crash it.
[ Grunting ]
Yeah.
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunting ]
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Really.
I feel good.
[ Call: Computer voice ]
Ground level recalibrated.
Time until impact now
43 minutes, 8 seconds.
Try to clear us a path
to the Betty...
and start her up.
[ Normal Voice ]
Okay.
[ Whirring, Beeping ]
[ Computer Voice ]
Please wait.
Emergency override
in console 45v, Level 1 .
[ Gasps ]
[ Normal voice ]
It's Wren.
He's almost at the Betty.
[ Beeping ]
- [ Buzzes ]
- [ Powering Down ]
Father, locate
the power drain. Report.
Father? Father!
[ Call Over Speaker ]
Father's dead, asshole.
Intruder on Level 1.
All aliens,
please proceed to Level 1.
You got a mean streak.
[ Groans ]
Damn it.
Let me see.
- Don't touch me.
- Come on.
You must think
this is pretty funny.
I'm finding a lot of things
funny lately,
but I don't think they are.
Why do you go on living?
How can you stand
being what you are?
Not much choice.
At least there's
a part of you that's human.
[ Sighs ]
I'm just— Look at me.
I'm disgusting.
Why did you come here?
To kill you,
remember?
Before the recall,
I accessed the mainframe.
Every dirty little covert op
the government ever
dreamed of is in there.
And this-you, the aliens,
even the crew from the Betty-
I knew if they succeeded,
it would be the end of them.
Why do you care
what happens to them?
Because I'm programmed to.
You're programmed
to be an asshole?
You're the new asshole model
they're putting out?
Come on.
I guess we're almost there.
- [ Distephano ]
It's not so far now!
- God, I'm so tired.
[Johner ]
Sleep when you die, man.
Oh, no. This is bad, right?
- I think we're near the nest.
- Well, then we'll go another way.
We don't have time.
We got nearly 90 minutes.
- Not anymore.
- What are you saying?
- What did you do, robot?
- Let's go. Come on.
Hey! You want to die here
with your little brothers
and sisters, that's cool!
But I plan to live past today!
If this little hunk of plastic
is pulling any shit,
I'm gonna kill her!
Kill you!
Does that compute?
Or do I have to
draw you a schematic?
[ Gagging ]
Hey!
- You want another souvenir?
- [ Gagging Continues ]
- How far are the docks?
- A h-hundred yards.
Ripley.
Come on.
Ripley, we have to go.
I hear them.
They're so close.
Ripley.
It's the queen.
She's in pain.
- [ Screams ]
- Ripley!
Ripley!
Wait!
Oh, my God.
[ Man ]
We gotta be moving.
The best thing you can do
is pray for a quick death.
Come on. Come on.
It's not right.
[ Man ]
I've been saying that all day.
[ vriess ]
It's up to you now, Call.
I need you to patch into
the ship again and open the hatch.
[ Computer Beeping ]
[ Beeps ]
Johner, we should put Purvis
in the freezer now.
[Johner ]
All right, little buddy.
Nap time.
[ Screams ]
- Oh!
- [ Call Whimpering ]
Nobody moves,
or I put a cap...
right where
this little droid's brain is.
Distephano, take the weapons.
Begging your pardon, sir,
but fuck you!
Oh, fine. Then I kill her,
and you kill me,
and we all die,
and nobody goes home!
Now drop the weapon.
Then this little
synthetic bitch...
is gonna plug into the Auriga,
and she is gonna take us
right back to home base,
according to the standard
emergency procedures.
- No, she's not.
- [ Distephano ]
Are you crazy?
You still want to bring
those things back to Earth?
- Haven't you been paying
any attention today?
- Ah, the intellectual speaks.
Stay there!
Listen, if you don't—
Don't you ever shut up?
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunting ]
- Why does nobody listen to me?
- [ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Screeching Continues ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Gediman ]
I told you.
At first, everything was normal.
The queen laid her eggs.
But then she started to change.
She added a second cycle cell.
So,
this time there is no host.
There are no eggs.
There is only her womb...
and the creature inside.
That is Ripley's gift to her:
a human reproductive system.
She is giving birth
for you, Ripley,
and now she is perfect!
[ Growling ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Father]
Civilian vessel on line.
Emergency departure
authorized.
[ Panting ]
All right. She's hot.
I'll open the Auriga's air locks,
pull the holding clamps on your mark.
Right. I-I just need
to find, uh, the, uh—
th-the vertical thrust lock.
Are you sure you guys
can fly this thing?
Yes!
- [ Father ]
Launch status is go.
- No!
Ripley.
[ Beeps ]
[ Shouting ]
- Hey.
- I thought you were dead.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
Why are we still here?
Uh, I'm just, uh, finding
the, uh, manual override.
- For Christ's sake.
- [Johner]
Hey, Ripley.
Good memory. Excuse me.
Ripley's back, man.
Is that it?
Nope.
You can't fly one of
these things too, can you?
Are you kidding?
This piece of shit
is even older than I am.
[ Father ]
U.S.M. Auriga
will impact in five seconds.
Four. Three.
Two. One.
Thank you.
[ Whooshing ]
- [Johner Screaming ]
- [ Computer Beeping ]
[ Whimpers ]
- What's burnin'?
- Us!
- Shit! You're right!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Both Sigh ]
Well, you did it.
You saved the Earth.
You sound disappointed.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
I didn't expect it to be.
What happens now?
I don't know.
I'm a stranger here myself.